本字幕由宇翔&玉梅编辑并校正
☆2011年09月16日于贵港☆
What do we care if we were expelled from college?
The war is gonna start any day. We would've left college anyhow.
War. Isn't it exciting, Scarlett?
Do you know those Yankees actually want a war?
We'll show 'em. Fiddle-dee-dee.
War, war, war.
This war talk's spoiling all the fun at every party this spring.
I get so bored I could scream.
Besides, there isn't going to be any war. Not gonna be any war?
Why, honey, of course there's going to be a war.
If either of you says war just once again, I'll go in the house and slam the door.
But, Scarlett, honey... Don't you want us to have a war?
Well
but remember
I warned you.
I've got an idea.
We'll talk about the Wilkes' barbecue at Twelve Oaks.
That's a good idea. Aren't you eating barbecue with us?
I hadn't thought about that yet. I'll think about that tomorrow.
We want all your waltzes.
First Brent, then me, then Brent, then me again and so on.
Promise? I'd just love to.
If only I didn't have every one of them taken already.
Why, honey, you can't do that to us.
How about if we tell you a secret? A secret? Who about?
Do you know Miss Melanie Hamilton from Atlanta?
Ashley Wilkes' cousin. She's visiting the Wilkes'
That goody-goody. Who wants to know a secret about her?
Anyway, we heard, that is, they say
Ashley Wilkes is gonna marry her. The Wilkeses always marry their cousins.
Now do we get those waltzes?
Of course.
I'll bet the other boys will be hopping mad. Let 'em be mad. We two can handle 'em.
It can't be true. Ashley loves me.
Scarlett.
What has gotten into her?
Do you suppose we made her mad?
Where're you goin' without your shawl, and the night air fixin' to set in?
How come you didn't ask them gentlemen to stay for supper?
You ain't got no more manners than a field hand
after me and Miss Ellen done labored with you.
Miss Scarlett, come on in the house.
Come on in before you catch your death of dampness.
No. I'll wait for Pa to come home from the Wilkes'.
Come on in here.
Come on.
Quittin' time.
Who says it's quittin' time?
I says it's quittin' time.
I's the foreman. I's the one that says when it's quittin' time at Tara.
Quittin' time.
There's none in the county can touch you, and none in the state.
Pa.
So it's proud of yourself, you are.
Well, Katie Scarlett O'Hara.
So, you've been spying on me, and like your sister, Suellen
you'll tell your mother I was jumping again.
Pa, you know I'm no tattletale like Suellen, but it does seem to me
after you broke your knee last year jumping that same fence
I'll not have me own daughter tellin' me what I shall jump and not jump.
It's my own neck, so it is.
All right, Pa, you jump what you please. How are they all over at Twelve Oaks?
The Wilkeses?
Just as you'd expect with the barbecue tomorrow and talking nothing but war.
Oh, bother the war. Was there anyone else there?
Their cousin, Melanie Hamilton, from Atlanta and her brother, Charles.
Melanie Hamilton.
She's a pale-faced, mealy-mouthed ninny. I hate her.
Ashley Wilkes doesn't think so.
Ashley Wilkes couldn't like anyone like her.
What's your interest in Ashley and Miss Melanie?
It's nothing. Let's go into the house, Pa.
Has he been trifling with you? Has he asked you to marry him?
No. No, nor will he.
I have it in strictest confidence from John Wilkes this afternoon
Ashley is going to marry Miss Melanie.
It will be announced tomorrow night at the ball.
I don't believe it.
Here. Here. Where are you off to?
Scarlett.
What are you about?
Have you made a spectacle of yourseIf running after a man
who's not in love with you when you might have any man in the county?
I haven't been running after him. It's just a surprise, that's all.
Now, don't be jerking your chin at me.
If Ashley wanted to marry you, it would be with misgivings I'd say yes.
I want my girl to be happy. You'd not be happy with him.
I would, I would.
What difference does it make who you marry
so long as he's a Southerner and thinks like you?
And when I'm gone, I'll leave Tara to you.
I don't want Tara. Plantations don't mean anything when
You mean to tell me, Katie Scarlett O'Hara, that land doesn't mean anything to you?
Why, land is the only thing in the world worth working for
worth fighting for, worth dying for, because it's the only thing that lasts.
Oh, Pa, you talk like an lrishman. It's proud I am that I'm lrish.
And don't you be forgetting, Missy, that you're haIf lrish too.
And to anyone with a drop of lrish blood in them
why, the land they live on is like their mother.
Oh, but you're just a child. It'll come to you, this love of the land.
There's no getting away from it if you're lrish.
Yonder she comes.
Miss Scarlett, Miss Suellen, Miss Carreen, your ma's home.
Actin' like a wet nurse to them low-down, poor white trash
instead of bein' here eatin' her supper. Cookie, stir up the fire.
Miss Ellen's got no business wearin' herseIf out.
Take the lamp out on the porch. Wearin' herseIf out.
Mist' Gerald, Miss Ellen's home.
Wearin' herseIf out waitin' on the poor white trash.
Shut up, dogs. Barkin' in the house like that.
Get up from there. Don't you hear that Miss Ellen's comin'?
Get out there and get her medicine chest.
We was gettin' worried about you, Miss Ellen.
Mist' Gerald... All right, Pork. I'm home.
Mrs. O'Hara, we finished plowing the creek bottom today.
What do you want me to start on tomorrow?
Mr. Wilkerson, I've just come from Emmy Slattery's bedside.
Your child has been born.
My child, ma'am? I'm sure I don't understand.
Has been born and, mercifully, has died.
Goodnight, Mr. Wilkerson.
I'll fix your supper for you myself, and you eats it.
After prayers, Mammy.
Yes, ma'am.
Mr. O'Hara.
You must dismiss Jonas Wilkerson.
Dismiss him, Mrs. O'Hara? He's the best overseer in the county.
He must go tomorrow morning, first thing.
But.
No. Yes.
The Yankee Wilkerson and the white-trash Slattery girl.
We'll discuss it later, Mr. O'Hara.
Yes, Mrs. O'Hara.
I want to wear Scarlett's green dress.
I don't like your tone, Suellen. Your pink gown is lovely.
Can't I stay up for the ball tomorrow? But you may wear my garnets with it.
Why can't I stay up for the ball tomorrow night?
Scarlett
you look tired, my dear. I'm worried about you.
I'm all right, Mother.
Why can't I stay up for the ball tomorrow night?
I'm 13 now.
You may go to the barbecue and stay up through supper.
I didn't want to wear your tacky green dress anyhow, stingy.
Oh, hush up.
Prayers, girls.
And to all the saints, that I have sinned exceedingly in thought, word and deed
through my fault.
Through my fault, through my most grievous fault.
Therefore, I beseech the Blessed Mary, ever Virgin
Blessed Michael, the Archangel
Blessed John the Baptist
the Holy Apostles, Peter and Paul
and all the saints to pray to the Lord, our God, for me.
But Ashley doesn't know I love him.
I'll tell him that I love him and then he can't marry her.
May the Almighty, and most merciful Lord
grant us pardon, absolution
and remission of our sins. Amen.
Just hold on and suck in.
Mammy, here's Miss Scarlett's vittles.
You can take that back. I won't eat a bite.
Oh, yes, ma'am, you is.
You's gonna eat every mouthful of this.
No, I'm not.
Put on the dress, because we're late already.
What's my lamb gonna wear? That.
No you ain't. You can't show your bosom before three o'clock.
I'm gonna speak to your ma about you.
If you say one word to Mother, I won't eat a bite.
Well.
Keep your shawl on. I ain't aimin' for you to get all freckled
after the buttermilk I done put on you all this winter, bleachin' them freckles.
Now, Miss Scarlett, you come on and be good, and eat just a little, honey.
No.
I'm going to have a good time today and do my eating at the barbecue.
If you don't care what folks says about this family, I does.
I has told you and told you that you can always tell a lady
by the way she eats with folks. Like a bird.
I ain't aimin' for you to go after Mr. Wilkes
and eat like a field hand and gobble like a hog.
Fiddle-dee-dee.
Ashley Wilkes told me he likes to see a girl with a healthy appetite.
What gentlemen says and what they thinks is two different things.
And I ain't noticed Mist' Ashley askin' to marry you.
Now don't eat too fast. Ain't no need of havin' it come right back up again.
Why does a girl have to be so silly to catch a husband?
Scarlett, ifyou're not here by the time I count ten, we'll be goin' without you.
I'm coming, Pa.
One
two, three
four, five, six
Oh, dear.
My stays are so tight I know I'll never get through the day without belching.
How are you.
Well, John Wilkes. It's a grand day you'll be having for the barbecue.
So it seems, Gerald. But why isn't Mrs. O'Hara with you?
She's after settling accounts with the overseer.
But she'll be along for the ball tonight.
Welcome to Twelve Oaks, Mr. O'Hara.
Thank you kindly, lndia.
Your daughter's getting prettier every day, John.
India, here are the O'Hara girls. We must greet them.
I can't stand Scarlett. If you saw the way she throws herseIf at Ashley.
Now, that's your brother's business.
You must remember your duties as hostess.
Good morning, girls.
Good morning, Scarlett.
Why, lndia Wilkes, what a lovely dress.
Perfectly lovely, darling. I just can't take my eyes off it.
Scarlett, honey.
You're looking mighty fine this morning.
Good morning, Miss Scarlett. Good morning.
It's a pleasure to see you. Good morning.
Howdy, Miss Scarlett.
Ashley.
Scarlett, my dear.
I've been looking for you everywhere.
I've got something I must tell you.
Can't we go some place where it's quiet? Yes, I'd like to, but l
I have something to tell you too.
Something I hope you'll be glad to hear.
But come say hello to my cousin, Melanie, first.
Oh, do we have to?
She's been looking forward to seeing you again.
Melanie.
Here's Scarlett.
Scarlett.
I'm so glad to see you again.
Melanie Hamilton. What a surprise to run into you here.
I hope you'll stay with us a few days at least.
I hope I shall stay long enough for us to become real friends, Scarlett.
I do so want us to be.
We'll keep her here, won't we, Scarlett?
We'll just have to make the biggest fuss over her, won't we?
If there's anybody knows how to give a girl a good time, it's Ashley.
Though I expect our good times will seem silly to you because you're so serious.
Oh, Scarlett, you have so much life.
I've always admired you so.
I wish I could be more like you.
You mustn't flatter me, Melanie, and say things you don't mean.
Nobody could accuse Melanie of being insincere. Could they, my dear?
Then she's not like you, is she, Ashley?
Ashley never means a word he says to any girl.
Oh, why, Charles Hamilton, you handsome old thing, you.
But, oh, Miss O'Hara, l.
Was it kind to bring your good-looking brother here
just to break my poor, simple, country-girl's heart?
She never even noticed Charles before.
Because he's your beau, she's after him like a hornet.
Charles Hamilton, I want to eat barbecue with you.
Mind you, don't go philandering with any other girl, 'cause I'm mighty jealous.
I won't, Miss O'Hara.
I couldn't.
I do declare, Frank Kennedy, if you don't look dashing
with that new set of whiskers.
Oh, thank you, Miss Scarlett.
Charles and Rafe asked me to eat barbecue with them
but I told them I couldn't because I promised you.
You needn't be so amused. Look at her. She's after your beau now.
Oh, that's mighty flattering of you, Miss Scarlett.
I'll see what I can do, Miss Scarlett.
What's your sister so mad about? You sparkin' her beau?
As if I couldn't get a better beau than that old maid in britches.
Brent and Stuart Tarleton, you handsome old things, you. No, you're not.
I won't say that. I'm mad at you.
What have we done?
You haven't been near me all day. I wore this old dress
'cause I thought you liked it.
I was counting on eating barbecue with you two.
Well, you are, Scarlett. Of course, you are.
Oh, I never can make up my mind which of you two is the handsomer.
I was awake all last night trying to figure it out.
I'm sorry
Cathleen, who's that?
Who?
That man looking at us and smiling.
The nasty, dark one.
My dear, don't you know? That's Rhett Butler. He's from Charleston.
He has the most terrible reputation.
He looks as if, as if he knows what I look like without my shimmy.
Scarlett.
Why, my dear, he isn't received.
He spends a lot of time up North
because his folks in Charleston won't even speak to him.
He was expelled from West Point, he's so fast.
And then there's that business about that girl he wouldn't marry.
Tell, tell.
Well, he took her out buggy riding in the late afternoon without a chaperon.
And then he refused to marry her.
No, but she was ruined just the same.
Ashley.
Happy?
So happy.
You seem to belong here
as if it had all been imagined for you.
I like to feel that I belong to the things you love.
You love Twelve Oaks as I do.
Yes, Ashley.
I love it as
as more than a house.
It's a whole world that wants only to be graceful and beautiful.
It's so unaware that it may not last
forever.
You're afraid of what may happen if the war comes, aren't you?
But we don't have to be afraid for us.
No war can come into our world, Ashley.
Whatever comes
I'll love you, just as I do now
until I die.
Isn't this better than sitting at a table?
A girl hasn't got but two sides to her at a table.
I'll go get her dessert.
Here, she said me. Allow me, Miss O'Hara.
I think.
I think Charles Hamilton may get it.
Oh, thank you, Miss O'Hara.
Thank you.
Go get it.
Isn't he the luckiest?
Miss O'Hara
I love you.
I don't guess I'm as hungry as I thought.
Why do I have to take a nap? I'm not tired.
Well-brought-up young ladies take naps at parties.
And it's high time you started behavin' and actin' like you was Miss Ellen's daughter.
When we were at Saratoga I didn't notice any Yankee girIs taking naps.
No, and you ain't gonna see no Yankee girIs at the ball tonight neither.
How was Ashley today, Scarlett?
He didn't seem to be paying much attention to you.
You mind your own business.
You'll be lucky not to lose ol' whisker-face Kennedy.
You've liked Ashley for months.
His engagement's gonna be announced tonight. Pa said so this morning.
That's all you know.
Miss Scarlett. Miss Suellen. You all behave yourselves.
Actin' like poor, white-trash children.
If you's old enough to go to parties, you's old enough to act like ladies.
Who cares.
We've borne enough insults from the meddling Yankees.
It's time we made them understand we'll keep our slaves
with or without their approval.
'Twas the sovereign right of the state of Georgia to secede from the Union.
That's right.
The South must assert herseIf by force of arms.
After we've fired on the Yankee rascaIs at Fort Sumter, we've got to fight.
There's no other way. Fight. That's right. Fight.
Let the Yankees ask for peace.
The situation is very simple. The Yankees can't fight and we can.
There won't even be a battle.
They'll just turn and run every time.
One Southerner can lick 20 Yankees.
We'll finish them in one battle.
Gentlemen can always fight better than rabble.
Yes, gentlemen always can fight better than rabble.
What does the captain of our troop say?
Well, gentlemen, if Georgia fights I go with her.
But, like my father, I hope that the Yankees will let us leave the Union in peace.
But, Ashley.... But, Ashley, they've insulted us.
You can't mean you don't want war.
Most of the miseries of the world were caused by wars.
And when the wars were over no one ever knew what they were about.
If it wasn't that I knew you
Now, gentlemen, Mr. Butler's been up North, I hear.
Don't you agree with us, Mr. Butler?
I think it's hard winning a war with words, gentlemen.
What do you mean, sir?
There's not a cannon factory in the whole South.
What difference does that make to a gentleman?
It'll make a great deal of difference to a great many gentlemen, sir.
Are you hinting, Mr. Butler, that the Yankees can lick us?
No, I'm not hinting.
I'm saying very plainly that the Yankees are better equipped than we.
They've got factories, shipyards, coal mines
and a fleet to bottle up our harbors and starve us to death.
All we've got is cotton and slaves and arrogance.
That's Yankee treachery. Sir, I refuse to listen to any renegade talk.
I'm sorry if the truth offends you.
Apologies aren't enough, sir.
I hear you were turned out of West Point, Mr. Rhett Butler
and you aren't received by any decent family in Charleston, not even your own.
I apologize again for all my shortcomings.
Perhaps you won't mind if I walk about and look over your place.
I seem to be spoiling everybody's brandy and cigars and
dreams of victory.
That's just about what you could expect from somebody like Rhett Butler.
You did everything but call him out.
He refused to fight.
Not quite that, Charles. He refused to take advantage of you.
Take advantage of me?
He's one of the best shots in the country
as he's proved a number of times
against steadier hands and cooler heads than yours.
I'll show him. Now, please.
Don't go tweaking his nose anymore.
You may be needed for more important fighting, Charles.
Now, if you'll excuse me, Mr. Butler is our guest.
I think I'll just show him around.
Ashley.
Scarlett.
Who're you hiding from in here?
What are you up to?
Well, why aren't you upstairs resting with the other girls?
What is this, Scarlett? A secret?
Oh, Ashley, Ashley
I love you.
Scarlett.
I love you, I do.
Well, isn't it enough that you've gathered every other man's heart today?
You've always had mine. You cut your teeth on it.
Oh, don't tease me now.
Have I your heart, my darling? I love you, I love you.
You mustn't say such things. You'll hate me for hearing them.
Oh, I could never hate you, and I know you must care about me.
Oh, you do care, don't you?
Yes
I care.
Oh, can't we go away and forget we ever said these things?
But how can we do that?
Don't you want to marry me?
I'm going to marry Melanie.
But you can't. Not if you care for me.
Oh, my dear, why must you make me say things that will hurt you?
How can I make you understand?
You're so young and unthinking.
You don't know what marriage means.
I know I love you, and I want to be your wife.
You don't love Melanie.
She's like me, Scarlett.
She's part of my blood and we understand each other.
But you love me.
How could I help loving you?
You have all the passion for life that I lack.
That kind of love isn't enough for a successful marriage
for two people as different as we are.
Well, why don't you say it, you coward? You're afraid to marry me.
You'd rather live with that fool who can't speak except
to say yes and no and raise a passel of mealy-mouthed brats just like her.
You mustn't say such things about Melanie.
Who are you to tell me I mustn't?
You led me on, you made me believe you wanted to marry me.
Now, Scarlett, be fair. I never, at any time
You did, it's true you did. I'll hate you till I die.
I can't think of anything bad enough to call you.
Has the war started?
Sir, you should have made your presence known.
In the middle of that beautiful love scene?
That wouldn't have been very tactful, would it?
But don't worry, your secret is safe with me.
Sir, you are no gentleman.
And you, Miss, are no lady.
Don't think I hold that against you.
Ladies have never held any charm for me.
First you take a low, common advantage of me, then you insuIt me.
I meant it as a compliment and I hope to see more of you
when you're free of the spell of the elegant Mr. Wilkes.
He doesn't strike me as haIf good enough for a girl of your, what was it?
Your passion for living.
How dare you. You aren't fit to wipe his boots.
And you were going to hate him for the rest of your life.
She certainly made a fool of herseIf running after all the men at the barbecue.
That's not fair, lndia.
She's so attractive, the menjust naturally flock to her.
Oh, Melanie, you're just too good to be true.
Didn't you see her going after your brother, Charles?
Yes, and she knows Charles belongs to me.
Oh, you're wrong, lndia.
Scarlett's just high-spirited and vivacious.
Men may flirt with girIs like that but they don't marry them.
I think you're being very mean to her.
War. War's declared. War.
Miss O'Hara.
Mr. LincoIn has called for soldiers, volunteers to fight against us.
Don't you men ever think of anything important?
But it's war and everybody's going off to enlist.
They're going right away. I'm going too.
Everybody?
Oh, Miss O'Hara, will you be sorry?
To see us go, I mean.
I'll cry into my pillow every night.
Miss O'Hara, I told you I loved you.
You're the most beautiful girl in the world, and the sweetest and the dearest.
I know I couldn't hope that you could love me.
I'm so clumsy and stupid and not nearly good enough for you.
But if you could think of marrying me I'd do anything in the world for you.
Just anything. I promise.
What did you say?
Miss O'Hara, I said, would you marry me?
Yes, Mr. Hamilton, I will.
You will? You'll marry me. You'll wait for me?
I don't think I'd want to wait.
You mean you'll marry me before I go?
Oh, Miss O'Hara.
Scarlett.
When may I speak to your father?
The sooner the better.
I'll go now. I can't wait.
Will you excuse me, dear?
Mr. O'Hara, Mr. O'Hara.
It'll be a week at least before they call on me.
Only a week, and then they'll take you away from me.
Melanie.
Scarlett, I thought of you at our wedding yesterday
and I hoped that yours would be as beautiful, and it was.
Was it?
Now we're really and truly sisters.
Charles. Melanie.
Don't cry, darling, the war will be over in a few weeks
and I'll be coming back to you.
Miss Scarlett.
Well, I don't care. I'm too young to be a widow.
Why, I just go around scaring people in that thing.
You ain't supposed to be around people. You's in mournin'.
For what? I don't feel anything.
Why should I have to pretend and pretend.
What is it?
Oh, baby.
My life is over.
Nothing will ever happen to me anymore.
Oh, Mother.
I know you'll think I'm horrible, but I just can't bear going around in black.
It's bad enough not being able to go to any parties
but looking this way too.
I don't think you're at all horrible.
It's only natural to want to look young and be young when you are young.
Oh, baby.
How would you like to go visiting somewhere?
Savannah perhaps?
What would I do in Savannah?
Well, Atlanta then.
There's lots going on there.
And you could stay with Melanie and her Aunt Pittypat.
Melanie.
Yes.
Yes, I could, couldn't l?
Oh, Mother, you're sweet to me, sweeter than anybody in the world.
You'd like it, really?
All right then. Now stop your crying and smile.
You can take Prissy with you.
Start packing Miss Scarlett's things, Mammy.
I'll go write the necessary letters.
Atlanta.
Savannah would be better for you. You'd just get in trouble in Atlanta.
What trouble are you talking about?
You know what trouble I's talkin' about. I's talkin' about Mist' Ashley Wilkes.
He'll be comin' to Atlanta when he gets his leave
and you're sittin' there waitin' for him just like a spider.
He belongs to Miss Melanie... You go pack my things like Mother said.
They're all whispering, and I just know it's about her.
What's it matter what they say, Aunt Pittypat?
But Scarlett is living under my roof so they all think I'm responsible for her
and for a widow to appear in public at a social gathering.
Every time I think of it I feel faint.
Aunt Pitty, you know Scarlett came here only to help raise money for the cause.
It was splendid of her to make the sacrifice.
Anyone would think, to hear you talk
that she came here to dance instead of to sell things.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I have important news. Glorious news.
Another triumph for our magnificent men in arms.
General Lee has completely whipped the enemy.
And swept the Yankee Army northward from Virginia.
And now, a happy surprise for all of us.
We have with us tonight that most daring of all blockade-runners
whose fleet schooners, slipping past the Yankee guns
have brought us here the very woolens and laces we wear tonight.
I refer, ladies and gentlemen, to that will-o' the-wisp of the bounding main.
None other than our friend from Charleston
Captain Rhett Butler.
Permit me.
Captain Butler, it's such a pleasure to see you again.
I met you last at my husband's home.
That's kind of you to remember, Mrs. Wilkes.
Did you meet Captain Butler at Twelve Oaks, Scarlett?
Yes. I, I think so.
Only for a moment, Mrs. Hamilton. It was in the library.
You had broken something.
Yes, Captain Butler, I remember you.
Ladies, the Confederacy asks for your jewelry on behaIf of our noble cause.
We aren't wearing any. We're in mourning.
Wait.
On behaIf of Mrs. Wilkes and Mrs. Hamilton.
Thank you, Captain Butler.
Just a moment, please.
But it's your wedding ring, ma'am.
It may help my husband more, off my finger.
Thank you.
That's a very beautiful thing to do, Mrs. Wilkes.
Here.
You can have mine, too, for the cause.
And you, Mrs. Hamilton. I know just how much that means to you.
Melanie. Yes, Dr. Meade.
I need your approval, as a member of the Committee
for something we want to do that's rather shocking.
Will you excuse us, please?
I'll say one thing, the war makes the most peculiar widows.
I wish you'd go away.
If you had any raising you'd know I never want to see you again.
Now, why be silly?
You've no reason for hating me. I'll carry your guilty secret to my grave.
I guess I'd be very unpatriotic to hate one of the great heroes of the war.
I do declare I was surprised to see you turn out to be such a noble character.
I can't bear to take advantage of your little girl ideas, Miss O'Hara.
I'm neither noble nor heroic.
But you are a blockade-runner.
For profit, and profit only.
Are you telling me you don't believe in the cause?
I believe in Rhett Butler. He's the only cause I know.
The rest doesn't mean much to me.
And now, ladies and gentlemen
I have a startling surprise for the benefit of the hospital.
Gentlemen, if you wish to lead the opening reel with the lady of your choice
you must bid for her.
Caroline Meade, how can you permit your husband to conduct this
this slave auction?
Dolly Merriwether, how dare you criticize me.
Melanie Wilkes told the doctor
that if it's for the benefit of the cause, it's quite all right.
She did.
Oh dear, oh dear. Where are my smelling salts?
I think I shall faint.
Don't you dare faint, Pittypat Hamilton.
If Melanie says it's all right, it is all right.
Come, gentlemen, do I hear your bids? Make your offers.
Don't be bashful, gentlemen.
Twenty dollars, $20 for Miss Maybelle Merriwether.
Twenty-five dollars for Miss Fanny Elsing.
Only $25 to give your
One hundred and fifty dollars in gold.
For what lady, sir?
For Mrs. Charles Hamilton.
For whom, sir?
Mrs. Charles Hamilton.
Mrs. Hamilton is in mourning, Captain Butler
but I'm sure any of our Atlanta belles would be proud to
Dr. Meade, I said Mrs. Charles Hamilton.
She will not consider it, sir.
Oh yes, I will.
Choose your partners for the Virginia reel.
We've sort of shocked the Confederacy.
It's a bit like blockade-running, isn't it?
It's worse.
But I expect a very fancy profit out of it.
I don't care what you expect or what they think.
I'm going to dance and dance.
Tonight I wouldn't mind dancing with Abe LincoIn himself.
Another dance and my reputation will be lost forever.
With enough courage, you can do without a reputation.
Oh, you do talk scandalous.
You do waltz divinely, Captain Butler.
Don't start flirting with me. I'm not one of your plantation beaux.
I want more than flirting from you.
What do you want?
I'll tell you, Scarlett O'Hara, if you'll take that Southern belle simper off your face.
Some day I want you to say to me
the words I heard you say to Ashley Wilkes
l love you.
That's something you'll never hear from me, Captain Butler, as long as you live.
How sweet, how kind.
He is a thoughtful gentleman.
Fiddle-dee-dee, why doesn't he say something about my sacrifice?
Oh, the darling thing.
Oh, Rhett, it's lovely, lovely.
You didn't really bring it all the way from Paris just for me.
Yes, I thought it was about time I got you out of that fake mourning.
Next trip I'll bring you some green silk for a frock to match it.
Oh, Rhett.
It's my duty to our brave boys at the front to keep our girIs at home looking pretty.
Oh, it's so long since I've had anything new.
How do I look?
Awful. Just awful.
Why, what's the matter?
This war has stopped being a joke
when a girl like you doesn't know how to wear the latest fashion.
Oh, Rhett, let me do it.
But, Rhett, I don't know how I dare wear it.
You will though.
And another thing, those pantalettes.
I don't know a woman in Paris that wears pantalettes anymore.
Oh, what do they?
You shouldn't talk about such things.
You little hypocrite.
You don't mind my knowing about them, just my talking.
But, I really can't go on accepting gifts from you, though you are awfully kind.
I'm not kind. I'm just tempting you.
I never give anything without expecting something in return. I always get paid.
If you think I'll marry you to pay for the bonnet, I won't.
Don't flatter yourself. I'm not a marrying man.
Well, I won't kiss you for it either.
Open your eyes and look at me.
No, I don't think I will kiss you
although you need kissing badly.
That's what's wrong with you.
You should be kissed and often. And by someone who knows how.
Oh, and I suppose you think you're the proper person.
I might be, if the right moment ever came.
You're a conceited, black-hearted varmint, Rhett Butler.
And I don't know why I let you come and see me.
I'll tell you why, Scarlett.
Because I'm the only man over 16 and under 60
who's around to show you a good time.
But cheer up, the war can't last much longer.
Oh really, Rhett? Why?
There's a battle going on right now that ought to pretty well fix things
one way or the other.
Oh, Rhett. Is Ashley in it?
You still haven't gotten the wooden-headed Mr. Wilkes out of your mind.
Yes, I suppose he's in it.
Oh, but tell me, Rhett, where is it?
Some little town in Pennsylvania called Gettysburg.
Here you is, Miss Melanie.
They was fightin' for them so it just got tore in half.
Scarlett, you look. The W's at the end.
Wellman, Wendell, White, Whitner, Wilkins
Williams, Woolsey, Workman.
Scarlett, you've passed him.
Oh, he isn't there.
He isn't there.
Ashley's safe. He isn't listed.
Oh, he's safe, he's safe.
Oh, Scarlett, you're so sweet to worry about Ashley like this for me.
I must go to her.
Don't, my dear, not here.
Let's go home.
Dr. Meade, not.
Yes, our boy, Darcy.
I was making these mittens for him.
He won't need them now.
Mother, I'm going to enlist. I'll show 'em. I'll kill all those Yankees.
Phil Meade, you hush your mouth.
Do you think it will help your mother to have you off getting shot too?
I never heard of anything so silly.
It's a black day, Scarlett. You haven't had bad news, have you?
Ashley's safe.
I'm glad, for Mrs. Wilkes' sake.
But, Rhett, there are so many others.
Many of your friends?
Just about every family in the county. The Tarleton boys, Rhett, both of them.
Yes, look at them. All these poor tragic people.
The South's sinking to its knees. It'll never rise again.
The cause.
The cause of living in the past is dying right in front of us.
I never heard you talk like that before.
I'm angry. Waste always makes me angry. And that's what all this is, sheer waste.
But don't you be downcast.
Ashley Wilkes is still alive to come home to the women who love him
both of them.
Oh, you're here.
Oh, you're here. You're really here at last.
Oh, my dear, I've waited so long.
Melanie, my dear, my darling wife.
Oh, but we're forgetting Scarlett.
Scarlett, dear.
Well, is this any way to greet a returning warrior?
Ashley, l.
Merry Christmas, Ashley.
Come on, old gentleman, come on. We've got all your wives.
We've got all your little chicks.
You got nobody to worry your head about leavin'.
Come on.
Now you just stand still so you can be a Christmas gift for the white folks.
Now hold on.
Hold on.
Don't go gettin' so uppity
even if you is the last chicken in Atlanta.
Let's not talk about the war. It's Christmas.
Let's talk about Twelve Oaks, and Tara and all the times before the war.
Can we have the wine, Aunt Pittypat?
Why did you say there wasn't enough, Uncle Peter?
There's plenty. It's the very last of my father's fine Madeira.
He got it from his uncle, Admiral Will Hamilton of Savannah
who married his cousin, Jessica Carroll of Carrollton
who was his second cousin once removed and a kin to the Wilkeses too.
I saved it to wish Ashley a Merry Christmas.
But you mustn't drink it all at once because it is the last.
I meant it, my dear. It was a lovely Christmas gift.
Only generaIs have tunics like this, nowadays.
I'm so happy you like it, dear.
Where did you get the cloth?
It was sent to me by a Charleston lady.
I nursed her son while he was in the hospital, Ashley, before he died and.
Oh, you will take good care of it, won't you?
You won't let it get torn.
Promise me.
You mustn't worry.
I'll bring it back to you without any holes in it, I promise.
Good night, my dear.
Good night, Scarlett, darling.
Is it time yet, Uncle Peter, for Mr. Ashley to leave?
Pretty quick now, Miss Scarlett.
She isn't going to the depot with him? She hasn't changed her mind?
No, ma'am. She's layin' down.
She's so upset Mist' Wilkes told her she can't even come downstairs.
Ashley.
Ashley, let me go to the depot with you.
Oh, Scarlett, I'd rather remember you as you are now
not shivering at the depot.
All right.
Oh, Ashley, I've got a present for you, too.
Why, Scarlett, it's beautiful.
Tie it on me, my dear.
While Melly was making your new tunic, I made this to go with it.
You made it yourself?
Well, then I shall value it all the more.
You know there's nothing I wouldn't do for you.
There's something you can do for me.
What is it?
Will you look after Melanie for me?
She's so frail and gentle and she loves you so much.
You see, if I were killed and she
Oh, you mustn't say that. It's bad luck. Say a prayer quickly.
You say one for me.
We shall need all our prayers now the end is coming.
The end?
The end of the war.
And the end of our world, Scarlett.
But, Ashley, you don't think the Yankees are beating us?
Oh, Scarlett, my men are barefooted now
and the snow in Virginia is deep.
When I see them
and I see the Yankees coming and coming, always more and more.
Well, when the end does come I shall be far away.
It'll be a comfort to me to know that she has you.
You will promise, won't you?
Yes.
Is that all, Ashley?
All except, goodbye.
Oh, Ashley, I can't let you go.
You must be brave... No....
You must.
How else can I bear going?
Oh, Scarlett, you are so fine and strong and beautiful.
Not just your sweet face, my dear
but you.
Oh, Ashley, kiss me.
Kiss me goodbye.
No, Scarlett.
Oh, Ashley, I love you.
I've always loved you. I never loved anyone else.
I only married Charles just to hurt you.
Oh, Ashley. Tell me you love me.
I'll live on it the rest of my life.
Goodbye.
When the war is over, Ashley.
When the war is over.
And there's a place back home
where a wild plum tree comes to flower in the springtime.
Down by the creek, you know.
Yes, I know, I know.
When we were little, my brother, Jeff, and I used to.
I told you about my brother, Jeff, didn't l, ma'am?
I know I did.
He.
We don't know where Jeff is now, ma'am.
Since Bull Run we haven't heard anything and.
Please, we must have your temperature now.
Just take this in your mouth and not talk anymore.
Not just now.
Melanie, I'm so tired I've gotta go home.
Aren't you tired, Melanie?
No, I'm not tired, Scarlett.
This might be
Ashley.
And only strangers here to comfort him.
No, I'm not tired, Scarlett.
They could all be
Ashley.
I've been sittin' by this curb one solid hour waitin' to speak to you, Miss Wilkes.
Go on, you trash, don't you be pesterin' these ladies.
Don't talk to her, Melly.
It's all right, Scarlett. Who are you?
My name's Belle Watlin'. But that don't matter.
I expect you think I've got no business here.
Hadn't you best tell me what you want to see me about?
First time I come here, I says, Belle, you're a nurse.
But the ladies didn't want my kind of nursin'.
Well, they was more than likely right.
Then I tried givin' 'em money.
My money wasn't good enough for 'em, either.
Old pea-hens.
I know a gentleman who says you're a human bein'.
If you are, which they ain't, you'll take my money for the hospital.
What are you doing here? Haven't you been told twice already?
This time I'm conversin' with Miss Wilkes.
You might as well take my money, Miss Wilkes.
It's good money, even if it is mine.
I'm sure you're very generous.
No, I'm not. I'm a Confederate like everybody else, that's all.
Of course you are.
There's some folks here wouldn't feel that way.
But maybe they ain't as good Christians as you.
Look, Mrs. Meade. It's a great deal of money.
$Ten, $20, $30, $50.
And it's not our paper money. It's gold.
Let me see that handkerchief.
R. B.
And she's driving away in Rhett Butler's carriage.
Oh, if I just wasn't a lady what wouldn't I tell that varmint.
The Lord is my Shepherd. I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures.
He leadeth.
He restoreth my soul.
He leadeth me in the paths of righteousness for His name's sake.
Yeah, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death
I will fear no evil.
For Thou art with me.
Thy rod and Thy staff, they comfort me.
Yankees.
The Yankees. Dr. Meade, they're getting closer.
They'll never get into Atlanta. They'll never get through old Peg-Leg Hood.
Give me something for the pain.
Sorry, son, we haven't got anything to give you.
These animaIs is driving me crazy.
What luck. You've got my jack.
Give me an ace and I'll start another war.
I'll bid the moon.
I'll never see you or Pa again.
This leg's got to come off, soldier.
No, no. Leave me alone.
I'm sorry, soldier.
We're all run out of chloroform, Dr. Meade.
Then we'll have to operate without it.
No, no. Leave me alone.
You can't do it. I won't let you do it to me.
Tell Dr. Wilson to take this leg off immediately. It's gangrene.
No, no. Don't.
I haven't seen my family in three days.
I'm going home for haIf an hour.
Orderly. Give me a lift.
Nurse, you can free this bed.
Miss Scarlett.
Why, Frank Kennedy.
Miss Suellen, is she well?
When did they bring you in? You all right? Are you badly hurt?
But Miss Suellen, is she... She's all right, but I
Dr. Wilson needs you in the operating room.
He's going to take off that leg. Better hurry.
I'll be back.
No, no, leave me alone.
No, no, I can't stand it.
Don't cut.
Don't, don't.
Please.
Where's the nurse?
Dr. Wilson's waiting.
Let him wait. I'm going home. I've done enough.
I don't want any more men dying. I don't want any more.
Big Sam.
Big Sam. Big Sam.
Almighty Moses, it's Miss Scarlett.
Big Sam.
Sam, I'm so glad to see you.
Tell me about Tara, about my mother. She didn't write me.
She's gone and got sick, Miss Scarlett. Sick?
Just a little bit sick, that's all.
Your pa was wild when they wouldn't let him fight 'cause of his broken knee.
He had fits when they took us field hands to dig ditches for white soldiers to hide in.
But your ma says the Confederacy needs us.
So we's gonna dig for the South.
Sam, was there a doctor?
Ma'am, we've got to march.
Goodbye, Miss Scarlett. Don't worry, we'll stop them Yankees.
Goodbye, Big Sam. Goodbye, boys. If any of you get sick or hurt, let me know.
Goodbye, Miss Scarlett. Goodbye.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
Scarlett.
Climb into this buggy. This is no day for walking.
You'll get run over.
Oh, Rhett.
Drive me to Aunt Pitty's, please.
Panic's a pretty sight, isn't it?
That's just another of Gen. Sherman's calling cards.
He'll be paying us a visit soon.
I've got to get out of here before the Yankees come.
And leave your work at the hospital?
Or have you had enough of death and lice and men chopped up?
I suppose you weren't meant for sick men, Scarlett.
Don't talk to me like that. I'm so scared.
I wish I could get out of here.
Let's get out of here together.
No use staying here and letting the South come down around your ears.
There are too many nice places to go and visit.
Mexico, London, Paris
With you? Yes, ma'am.
With a man who understands you and admires you for just what you are.
I figure we belong together, being the same sort.
I've been waiting for you to grow up and get that sad-eyed Ashley out of your heart.
Well, I hear Mrs. Wilkes is going to have a baby in another month or so.
It'll be hard loving a man with a wife and baby clinging to him.
Well, here we are. Are you going with me, or are you getting out?
I hate and despise you, Rhett Butler, and I'll hate and despise you till I die.
Oh, no, you won't, Scarlett. Not that long.
Miss Scarlett. Miss Scarlett.
Folks is all going to Macon and folks is running away and running away.
I can't bear it. Those cannon balls right in my ears.
I faint every time I hear one.
Uncle Peter, look out for that trunk.
But, Aunt Pitty, you aren't leaving?
I may be a coward, but oh, dear.
Yankees in Georgia.
How did they ever get in?
I'm going, too. Prissy, go pack my things. Get them, quick.
Wait, Aunt Pitty, I won't be a minute.
Scarlett, do you really think you ought to?
Scarlett.
What is this? You ain't planning on running away?
And don't you dare try to stop me. I'm never going back to that hospital.
I've had enough of smelling death and rot and death.
I'm going home. I want my mother. My mother needs me.
Now you've got to listen to me. You must stay here.
Without a chaperon, Dr. Meade? It simply isn't done.
Good heavens, woman, this is war, not a garden party.
You've got to stay. Melanie needs you.
She's ill already. She shouldn't even be having a baby.
Can't we take her along?
Do you want her to take that chance?
To be jounced over rough roads
and have her baby ahead of time, in a buggy?
It isn't my baby. You take care of her.
Scarlett. We haven't enough doctors
much less nurses to look after a sick woman.
You've got to stay for Melanie.
I don't know anything about babies being born.
I knows, I knows.
I knows how to do it. I's done it lots and lots.
Let me, Doctor, let me. I can do everything.
Good. Then I'll rely on you to help us. Yes, Doctor.
Ashley's fighting in the field, fighting for the cause.
He may never come back. He may die.
Scarlett, we owe him a well-born child.
Ashley.
If you're coming, Scarlett, hurry.
I promised Ashley
something.
Then you'll stay?
Good. Go along, Miss Pittypat. Scarlett's staying.
Go on, Uncle Peter. Oh, dear, I don't know what to do.
It's like the end of the world.
Uncle Peter, my smelling salts.
Melanie, it's all your fault.
I hate you, I hate you.
And I hate your baby.
If only I hadn't promised Ashley.
If only I hadn't promised him.
Stop. Stop, please stop.
Is it true? Are the Yankees coming?
I'm afraid so, ma'am. The Army's pulling out.
Pulling out of Atlanta? Leaving us to the Yankees?
Not leaving, ma'am, evacuating.
We've got to before Sherman cuts the McDonough Road and catches us.
It can't be true. It can't be true. What'll I do?
Better refugee south right quick, ma'am. If you'll excuse me, ma'am.
Prissy.
Prissy, come here.
Pack my things and Miss Melanie's, too. We're going to Tara right away.
The Yankees are coming.
Yes, ma'am.
Scarlett.
Melly, we're going to
Melly.
I'm sorry to be such a bother, Scarlett.
It began at daybreak.
But, but
But the Yankees are coming.
Poor Scarlett.
You'd be at Tara now with your mother, wouldn't you
if it weren't for me?
Oh, Scarlett, darling
you've been so good to me.
No sister could have been sweeter.
I've been lying here thinking
if I should die
will you take my baby?
Oh, fiddle-dee-dee, Melly.
Aren't things bad enough without you talking about dying?
I'll send for Dr. Meade right away. Not yet, Scarlett.
I couldn't let Dr. Meade sit here for hours, while
while all those poor, wounded boys... Prissy.
Prissy. Prissy. Come here, quick.
Yes, ma'am. The baby.
Well, don't stand there like a scared goat. Run.
Hurry. I'll sell you South, I will. I swear I will.
Where's that Prissy?
This room's like an oven already
and it isn't noon yet.
Oh, don't worry, Melly.
Mother says it always seems like the doctor will never come.
If I don't take a strap to that Prissy.
Oh, Melly.
You know what I heard about Maybelle Merriwether?
You remember that funny-looking beau of hers?
The one with a uniform like ladies' red flannel underdrawers.
You don't have to keep on talking for my sake, Scarlett.
I know how worried you are.
Oh, Melly, I'll just go and fetch you some cool water.
You're as slow as molasses in January.
And where's Dr. Meade?
I ain't never seen him, Miss Scarlett. What?
No, ma'am. He ain't at the hospital.
A man, he told me the doctor's down at the car shed with the wounded soldiers
Well, why didn't you go after him?
Miss Scarlett.
I's scared to go down there to the car shed.
There's folks dying down there and I's scared of dead folks.
Oh, you go sit by Miss Melly.
And don't you be upsetting her, or I'll whip the hide off you.
Have you seen Dr. Meade? Side, lady, please.
Dr. Meade.
Dr. Meade. At last.
Oh, thank heavens you're here. I need every pair of hands.
Come, child. Wake up. We've got work to do.
But Melly's having her baby. You've got to come with me.
Are you crazy? I can't leave these men for a baby.
They're dying, hundreds of them. Get some woman to help you.
But there isn't anybody. Dr. Meade, she might die.
Die.
Look at them. Bleeding to death in front of my eyes.
No chloroform. No bandages. Nothing. Nothing to even ease their pain.
Now run along and don't bother me.
Now don't worry, child. There's nothing to bringing a baby.
Now bring those stretchers in here.
Dr. Meade.
I'm coming.
Is the doctor come?
No, he can't come.
Oh, Miss Scarlett, Miss Melly bad off.
He can't come. There's nobody to come.
Prissy, you've got to manage without the doctor. I'll help you.
Oh, lordy, Miss Scarlett.
Well, what is it?
Lordy, we've got to have a doctor.
I don't know nothing about birthing babies.
What do you mean? I don't know
You told me you knew everything about it.
I don't know how come I told such a lie.
Ma ain't never let me around when folks was having them.
Scarlett.
Oh, Miss Scarlett
Stop it.
Go light a fire in the stove.
Keep boiling water in the kettle, get me the ball of twine and
and all the clean toweIs you can find, and the scissors.
Don't come telling me you can't find them.
Go get them, and get them quick.
Scarlett.
Coming, Melly.
Coming.
Go, Scarlett, before the Yankees get here.
I'm not afraid. You know I won't leave you.
It's no use. I'm going to die.
Don't be a goose, Melly. Hold on to me. Hold on to me.
Talk to me, Scarlett.
Please talk to me.
Don't try to be brave, Melly.
Yell all you want, there's nobody to hear.
Ma says that if you puts a knife under the bed, it cuts the pain in two.
Capt. Butler.
Who do you want?
He's upstairs. Belle Watling's giving a party.
Thank you.
Capt. Butler. Oh, Capt. Butler.
What's all the rumpus about?
I's got a message for Capt. Butler, Miss Watling.
Capt. Butler, you come out here in the streets to me.
What is it, Prissy?
Miss Scarlett, she done sent me for you.
Miss Melly, she done had her baby today.
A fine baby boy
and Miss Scarlett and me, we brung him.
Do you mean to tell me that Scarlett
Well, it was mostly me, Capt. Butler, only Miss Scarlett
she helped me a little, but I don't expect no doctor could have done no better.
Only Miss Melly, she feeling kind of poorly now it's all over.
Yes, I can believe that.
And the Yankees is coming, and Miss Scarlett, she said
Oh, Capt. Butler, the Yankees is here.
Please come and bring your carriage for us right away.
I'm sorry, Prissy, but the Army took my horse and carriage.
You'd better come upstairs. I'll see what I can do.
Oh, no, Capt. Butler.
Ma would wear me out with a cornstalk if I was to go into Miss Watling's.
Any of you beauties know where I can steal a horse for a good cause?
Whoa, Marse Robert. Is that you, Rhett?
We's here, Miss Scarlett. We's here. Rhett, I knew you'd come.
Good evening. Nice weather we're having.
Prissy tells me you're planning on taking a trip.
If you make any jokes now, I'll kill you.
Don't tell me you're frightened.
I'm scared to death. If you had the sense of a goat, you'd be scared too.
Oh, the Yankees. No, not yet.
That's what's left of our Army, blowing up the ammunition
so the Yankees won't get it.
We've got to get out of here.
At your service, madam.
Just where are you figuring on going?
Home, to Tara.
They've been fighting all day around Tara.
Do you think you can parade through the Yankee Army
with a sick woman, a baby, and a simple-minded darky
or do you intend leaving them behind?
They're going with me. I'm going home. You can't stop me.
Don't you know it's dangerous jouncing Mrs. Wilkes over miles of open country?
I want my mother.
I want to go home to Tara.
Tara's probably been burned to the ground.
The woods are full of stragglers from both armies.
The least they'll do is take the horse away from you.
It isn't much of an animal, but I had trouble stealing it.
I'm going home if I have to walk every step of the way.
I'll kill you if you try to stop me. I will, I will.
I will.
All right, darling, all right. Now you shall go home.
I guess anybody who did what you've done today can take care of Sherman.
Here, now. Stop crying.
Now blow your nose like a good little girl.
There.
Prissy. What are you doing?
I's packing, Miss Scarlett.
Stop it and come get the baby.
Melly.
Mrs. Wilkes, we're taking you to Tara.
Tara
It's the only way, Melly. No.
Sherman will burn the house over our heads if we stay.
It's all right, Melly.
My baby.
My poor baby.
Have you the strength to put your arms around my neck?
I think so.
Never mind.
Oh, Ashley, Charles
What is it? What does she want?
Ashley's picture, Charles' sword. She wants us to bring them.
Get them.
What's that?
Our gallant lads must have set fire to the warehouses near the depot.
There's enough ammunition in the boxcars to blow us to Tara.
We'll have to hurry to get across the tracks.
You're not going that way. We have to.
The McDonough Road's the only one the Yankees haven't cut yet.
Oh, wait. I forgot to lock the front door.
What are you laughing at?
At you, locking the Yankees out.
Oh, dear, I wish they'd hurry.
I wouldn't be in such a hurry to see them go if I were you.
With them goes the last semblance of law and order.
The scavengers aren't wasting any time.
We've got to get out of here fast.
There's a horse.
Stay the horse
Down the alley, cut them off.
Give me that horse.
Miss Scarlett.
They haven't left much for the Yankees to take, have they?
We'll have to make a dash for it before the fire reaches that ammunition.
Come on.
Throw me your shawl.
Sorry, but you'll like it better if you don't see anything.
Take a good look, my dear.
It's a historic moment.
You can tell your grandchildren
how you watched the old South disappear one night.
They were going to lick the Yankees in a month.
Poor gallant fools.
They make me sick, all of them.
Getting us all into this with their swaggering and boasting.
That's the way I feIt once about their swaggering and boasting.
Rhett, I'm so glad you aren't with the Army.
You can be proud now, proud that you've been smarter than all of them.
I'm not so proud.
Why did you stop?
This is the turn to Tara. Let the horse breathe a bit.
Mrs. Wilkes.
Miss Melly done fainted way back, Capt. Butler.
Well, she's probably better off.
She couldn't stand the pain if she were conscious.
Scarlett, are you still determined to do this crazy thing?
Yes. I know we can get through, Rhett. I'm sure we can.
Not we, my dear. You.
I'm leaving you here.
You're what? Rhett, where are you going?
I'm going, my dear, to join the Army.
You're joking. I could kill you for scaring me so.
I'm very serious, Scarlett.
I'm going to join up with our brave lads in gray.
But they're running away.
No. They'll turn and make a last stand, if I know anything about them.
When they do, I'll be with them. A little late, but Better late
Rhett, you must be joking.
Selfish to the end, aren't you?
Thinking only of your own precious hide, with never a thought for the noble cause.
Rhett, how could you do this to me
and why should you go now, after it's all over and I need you?
Why? Why?
Why?
Maybe it's because I've always had a weakness for lost causes
once they're really lost.
Or maybe
maybe I'm ashamed of myself.
Who knows?
You should die of shame to leave me here alone and helpless.
You helpless?
Heaven help the Yankees if they capture you.
Now climb down here. I want to say goodbye.
No.
Climb down.
Oh, Rhett, please don't go. You can't leave me, please.
I'll never forgive you.
I'm not asking you to forgive me. I'll never understand or forgive myself.
And if a bullet gets me, so help me, I'll laugh at myseIf for being an idiot.
But there's one thing I do know
and that is that I love you, Scarlett.
In spite of you, me and the whole silly world going to pieces around us
I love you
because we're alike. Bad lots, both of us.
Selfish and shrewd
but able to look things in the eyes and call them by their right names.
Don't hold me like that.
Scarlett, look at me.
I love you more than I've ever loved any woman.
And I've waited longer for you than I've ever waited for any woman.
Let me alone.
Here's a soldier of the South who loves you, Scarlett
wants to feel your arms around him
wants to carry the memory of your kisses into battle with him.
Never mind about loving me.
You're a woman sending a soldier to his death with a beautiful memory.
Scarlett, kiss me.
Kiss me, once.
You low-down, cowardly, nasty thing, you.
They were right. Everybody was right. You aren't a gentleman.
A minor point at such a moment.
Here.
If anyone lays a hand on that nag, shoot him.
But don't make a mistake and shoot the nag.
Oh, go on. I want you to go. I hope a cannonball lands slap on you.
I hope you're blown into a million pieces.
Never mind the rest. I follow your general idea.
And when I'm dead on the altar of my country
I hope your conscience hurts you.
Goodbye, Scarlett.
Come on, you. We're going home.
Oh, my poor baby.
Don't worry, Melly.
Mother will take care of him when we get home.
Miss Scarlett, I's powerful hungry.
We's got to have something to eat.
Oh, hush up.
We're nearly at Twelve Oaks. We'll stop there.
Go on.
Ashley, I'm glad you're not here to see this.
The Yankees.
The dirty Yankees.
Prissy, come tie up this cow.
We don't need no cow, Miss Scarlett.
We'll be home soon, and I's scared of cows.
Tear up your petticoat and tie her on to the back of the wagon.
We need milk for the baby, and we don't know what we'll find at home.
Melly. Melly, we're home.
We're at Tara.
Hurry. Move, you brute.
Miss Scarlett, he's dead.
I can't see the house. Is it there? I can't see the house. Have they burned it?
Oh, it's all right.
It's all right. They haven't burned it.
It's still there.
Mother. Mother. I'm home.
Mother, let me in. It's me, Scarlett.
Pa.
Oh, Pa.
I'm home.
Katie.
Katie Scarlett.
Oh, darling.
Mammy.
Mammy, I'm home. Honey, honey child.
Oh, Mammy, I'm so
Where's Mother?
Why
Miss Suellen and Miss Carreen, they was sick with the typhoid.
They had it bad, but they's doing all right now.
Just weak like little kittens.
But where's Mother?
Well
Miss Ellen, she went down to nurse that Emmie Slattery, that white trash
and she took down with it, too.
And last night, she... Mother.
Mother.
Where is she?
Miss Scarlett, honey.
If there's anything I can do, Miss Scarlett
What did you do with Miss Melly?
Don't you worry your pretty head about Miss Melly, child.
I done slapped her in bed already, along with the baby.
You better put that cow I brought into the barn, Pork.
There ain't no barn no more, Miss Scarlett.
The Yankees done burned it for firewood.
They used the house for their headquarters.
They camped all around the place.
Yankees in Tara.
Yes, ma'am, and they stole most everything they didn't burn.
All the clothes and all the rugs and even Miss Ellen's rosaries.
I'm starving, Pork. Get me something to eat.
There ain't nothing to eat, honey. They took it all.
All the chickens, everything?
They took them the first thing.
And what they didn't eat they carried off across their saddles.
Don't tell me any more about what they did.
What's this, Pa?
Whiskey?
Yes, daughter.
Katie Scarlett, that's enough.
You're not knowing spirits, you'll make yourseIf tipsy.
I hope it makes me drunk.
I'd like to be drunk.
Oh, Pa.
What are those papers?
Bonds.
They're all we've saved.
All we have left.
Bonds.
What kind of bonds, Pa?
Why, Confederate bonds, of course, daughter.
Confederate bonds.
What good are they to anybody?
I'll not have you talking like that, Katie Scarlett.
Oh, Pa, what are we going to do with no money and nothing to eat?
We must ask your mother.
That's it.
We must ask Mrs. O'Hara.
Ask Mother? Yes.
Mrs. O'Hara will know what's to be done.
Now don't be bothering me.
Go out for a ride.
I'm busy.
Oh, Pa
don't worry about anything.
Katie Scarlett's home.
You needn't worry.
Miss Scarlett.
What are we gonna to do with nothing to feed those sick folks and that child?
I don't know, Mammy.
I don't know.
We ain't got nothing but radishes in the garden.
Miss Scarlett, Miss Suellen and Miss Carreen
they's fussing to be sponged off.
Where are the other servants, Mammy?
Miss Scarlett, there's only just me and Pork left.
The others went off to the war or runned away.
I can't take care of that baby and sick folks, too.
I's only got two hands.
Who's going to milk that cow, Miss Scarlett? We's houseworkers.
As God is my witness
As God is my witness, they're not going to lick me.
I'm going to live through this, and when it's all over, I'll never be hungry again.
No, nor any of my folks.
If I have to lie, steal, cheat or kill.
As God is my witness, I'll never be hungry again.
My back's near broken.
Look at my hands.
Mother said you could always tell a lady by her hands.
I guess things like hands and ladies don't matter so much anymore.
You rest, Sue. You're not well yet, and I can pick cotton for both of us.
Scarlett's hateful, making us work in the fields like
Too bad about that.
Now get back to work. I can't do everything at Tara all by myself.
What do I care about Tara? I hate Tara.
Don't you ever dare say you hate Tara again.
It's the same as hating Pa and Ma.
Katie Scarlett, there's something I must speak to you about.
Yes, Pa, what is it?
I've been talking to Prissy and Mammy. I don't like the way you're treating them.
You must be firm with inferiors, but you must be gentle with them
especially darkies.
Yes, Pa, I know. But I'm not asking them to do anything I'm not doing myself.
Nevertheless, Katie Scarlett, I don't like it. I shall speak to Mrs. O'Hara about it.
What are you doing out of bed, Melly?
Scarlett, darling, I must talk to you. You are all working so hard.
I can't lie in bed doing nothing.
Go on back upstairs. You're as weak as a newborn colt.
Please, Scarlett, let me.
Stop being noble. I've got enough on my hands
without you making yourseIf sick so you'll never be any use.
Oh, I didn't think of it that way.
Who's there? HaIt or I'll shoot.
You're alone, little lady?
You ain't very friendly, are you?
You got anything else besides these earbobs?
You Yankees have been here before.
Regular little spitfire, ain't you?
What have you got hidden in your hand?
Scarlett, you killed him.
I'm glad you killed him.
Scarlett, what happened? What is it, Scarlett? What is it?
Don't be scared, chickens. Your big sister was cleaning a revolver
and it went off and nearly scared her to death.
Oh, thank goodness. Haven't we got enough to frighten us?
Tell Katie Scarlett she must be more careful.
What a cool liar you are, Melly.
We've got to get him out of here and bury him.
If the Yankees find him here, they'll
I didn't see anyone else. I think he must be a deserter.
But even so, we've got to hide him.
They might hear about it, and then they'd come and get you.
I could bury him in the arbor where the ground is soft
but how will I get him out of here?
We'll both take a leg and drag him.
You couldn't drag a cat.
Do you think it would be dishonest if we went through his haversack?
I'm ashamed I didn't think of that myself.
You take the haversack, I'll search his pockets.
You look.
I'm feeling a little weak.
Melly, I think it's full of money.
Oh, Melly, look.
Look.
$10, $20, $30, $40
Don't stop to count it now. We haven't got time.
Do you realize this means we'll have something to eat?
Look in his other pockets.
Hurry, hurry.
We've got to get him out of here. Here.
If he bleeds across the yard, we can't hide it.
Give me your nightgown, Melly. I'll wad it around his head.
Don't be silly. I won't look at you.
If I had my petticoat or pantalets, I'd use them.
Thank heavens I'm not that modest.
Now go back to bed. You'll be dead if you don't.
I'll clean up the mess when I've buried him.
No, I'll clean it up.
Well, I guess I've done murder.
I won't think about that now.
I'll think about that tomorrow.
Katie Scarlett.
It's over. It's over.
It's all over. The war.
Lee surrendered.
It's not possible. Why did we ever fight?
Ashley will be coming home.
Yes, Ashley will be coming home.
We'll plant more cotton.
Cotton ought to go sky-high next year.
While we were marching through Georgia
Hurrah, hurrah.
The flag that makes you free
So we sing the chorus from Atlanta to the sea
While we were marching through Georgia
Get out of the road, rebel. Get out of the way.
Have you room in your carriage for a dying man?
I got no room for any Southern scum, alive or dead.
Get out of the way.
I reckon he'd rather try and walk it at that.
Giddap. Jump, you gray-backed beggars.
Act like they won the war.
Now you come on and give me them pants, Mr. Kennedy.
Come on.
You scrub yourseIf with that strong lye soap before I scrubs you myself.
I'm gonna put these britches in the boiling pot.
The whole Confederate Army's got the same trouble
Crawling clothes and dysentery.
It's humiliating, how you treat Mr. Kennedy.
You'd be a sight more humiliated if Mr. Kennedy's lice gets on you.
Come on, Beau.
We must leave this gentleman alone because he's tired and he's hungry.
I don't mind, ma'am. Good to see a youngster again.
Nice little fellow.
Another two years of war and we could have had him with us in Cobb's Legion.
Were you in Cobb's Legion?
Yes, ma'am.
Why, then, you must know my husband, Maj. Wilkes.
Oh, yes, ma'am.
He was captured at Spotsylvania, I think.
Oh, thank heavens, then he isn't
Oh, my poor Ashley in a Yankee prison.
Melanie.
Yes, Scarlett, I'm coming. Come along, Beau.
I'll watch out for him, ma'am. We're good friends.
Oh, thank you.
I slave day and night so we can have food to keep body and soul together.
And you give it all away to these starving scarecrows.
I'd sooner have a plague of locusts here.
Don't scold me, Scarlett, please.
I've just heard that Ashley was taken prisoner.
Ashley, a prisoner? Yes.
And maybe if he's alive and well, he's on some Northern road right now.
And maybe some Northern woman is giving him a share of her dinner
and helping my beloved to come back home to me.
I hope so, Melly.
Miss Scarlett.
Miss Scarlett, I want to take up something with your pa, but
he doesn't seem to
Perhaps I can help you. I'm head of the house now.
Well, I
Miss Scarlett, I was aiming to ask for Suellen.
Do you mean to tell me you haven't asked for her
after all these years she's been counting on you?
Well, the truth is, I'm so much older than she is, and
Well, now I haven't a cent to my name.
Who has nowadays?
Miss Scarlett, if true love carries any weight with you
you can be sure your sister will be rich in that.
I'll go out somewhere and get myseIf a little business if we're engaged.
As soon as I get on my feet again
All right, Frank. I'm sure I can speak for Pa.
You go ask her now.
Oh, thank you, Miss Scarlett.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Scarlett, what seems to be the trouble with Mr. Kennedy?
More trouble than he guesses.
He's finally asked for Suellen's hand.
Oh, I'm so glad.
It's a pity he can't marry her now. At least there'd be one less mouth to feed.
Oh, another one.
I hope this one isn't hungry.
He'll be hungry.
I'll tell Prissy to get an extra plate
Ashley.
Darling.
Miss Scarlett. Don't spoil it, Miss Scarlett.
Turn me loose, you fool. Turn me loose, it's Ashley.
He's her husband, ain't he?
Miss Scarlett, ma'am. High time you got back.
Did you get the horse shod? Yes, he shod all right.
Fine thing when a horse can get shoes and humans can't. Here, stir this soap.
Yes, ma'am. Miss Scarlett, ma'am.
I gotta know how much money have you got left, in gold.
$10. Why?
That won't be enough.
What in heaven's name are you talking about?
Well, Miss Scarlett, I seed that old no-count white-trash Wilkerson
that used to be Mr. Gerald's overseer here.
He's a regular Yankee now, and he was making a brag
that his carpetbagger friends done run the taxes way up sky-high on Tara.
But how much more have we got to pay?
I hear the taxman say $300.
$300.00
Might just as well be $3 million.
But we gotta raise it, that's all.
Yes, ma'am.
How?
I'll go ask Mr. Ashley.
Oh, he ain't got no $300, Miss Scarlett.
Well, I can ask him if I want to, can't I?
Asking ain't getting.
Ashley.
They say Abe LincoIn got his start splitting rails.
Think what heights I may climb to once I get the knack.
The Yankees want $300 more in taxes.
What shall we do?
Ashley, what's to become of us?
What becomes of people when their civilization breaks up?
Those who have brains and courage come through all right.
Those that haven't are winnowed out.
For heaven's sake, don't stand there talking nonsense at me
when it's us who are being winnowed out.
You're right, Scarlett.
Here I am talking tommyrot about civilization
when your Tara's in danger.
You've come to me for help, and I've no help to give you.
Oh, Scarlett, I
I'm a coward.
You, Ashley, a coward?
What are you afraid of?
Oh, mostly of life becoming too real for me, I suppose.
Not that I mind splitting rails
but I do mind very much losing the beauty of that life I loved.
If the war hadn't come, I'd have spent my life happily buried at Twelve Oaks.
But the war did come.
I saw my boyhood friends blown to bits.
I saw men crumple up in agony when I shot them.
And now I find myseIf in a world which for me is worse than death.
A world in which there's no place for me.
I can never make you understand because you don't know the meaning of fear.
You never mind facing realities
and you never want to escape from them as I do.
Escape?
Oh, Ashley, you're wrong.
I do want to escape, too.
I'm so very tired of it all. I've struggled for food and for money.
I've weeded and hoed and picked cotton until I can't stand it another minute.
I tell you, Ashley, the South is dead. It's dead.
The Yankees and the carpetbaggers have got it and there's nothing left for us.
Oh, Ashley
let's run away.
We'd go to Mexico.
They want officers in the Mexican Army. We could be so happy there.
I'd work for you, I'd do anything for you. You know you don't love Melanie.
You told me you loved me that day at Twelve Oaks.
And anyway, Melanie can't
Dr. Meade told me she couldn't have any more children and I could give you
Can't we ever forget that day at Twelve Oaks?
Do you think I could ever forget it? Have you forgotten it?
Can you honestly say you don't love me?
No. I don't love you. It's a lie.
Even if it is, do you think I'd leave Melanie and the baby, break Melanie's heart?
You couldn't leave your father and the girls.
I could leave them. I'm sick of them. I'm tired of them.
Yes, you're sick and tired. That's why you're talking this way.
You've carried the load for all of us
but from now on I'm going to be more help to you, I promise.
There's only one way you can help me.
Take me away.
There's nothing to keep us here.
Nothing.
Nothing except honor.
Oh, please, Scarlett.
Please, dear, you mustn't cry.
You mustn't.
Please, my brave dear, you mustn't.
You do love me, you do love me.
Say it, say it. Don't, don't.
You love me, you love me.
We won't do this, I tell you. It won't happen again.
I'm going to take Melanie and the baby, and go.
All right, I'll say it. I love your courage and your stubbornness.
So much that I could have forgotten the best wife a man ever had.
But, Scarlett, I'm not going to forget her.
Then there's nothing left for me.
Nothing to fight for.
Nothing to live for.
Yes, there is something.
Something you love better than me
though you may not know it.
Tara.
Yes, I
I still have this.
You needn't go.
I won't have you all starve simply because I threw myseIf at your head.
It won't happen again.
Why, it's Emmy Slattery. Yes, ma'am, it's me.
Stop.
You haven't forgotten your old overseer, have you?
Well, Emmy's Mrs. Wilkerson now.
Get off those steps, you trashy wench. Get off this land.
You can't speak that way to my wife.
Wife. High time you made her your wife.
Who baptized your other brats after you killed my mother?
We came out here to pay a friendly call and talk a little business with old friends.
Friends. When were we ever friends with the likes of you?
Still high and mighty, ain't you? Well, I know all about you.
I know your father's turned idiot.
You can't pay your taxes.
And I come here to offer to buy the place from you
to make you a right good offer.
Emmy's had a hankering to live here.
Get off this place, you dirty Yankee.
You high-flying Irish will find out who's running things around here
when you get sold out for taxes.
I'll buy this place lock, stock and barrel and I'll live in it.
But I'll wait for the Sheriff's sale.
That's all of Tara you'll ever get.
You'll be sorry for that.
We'll be back.
I'll show you who the owner of Tara is.
Pa, come back.
Pa.
Yankee coward.
Lordsy, Miss Scarlett. That's Mr. Gerald's watch.
You take it. It's for you. Pa'd want you to have it.
You ain't got no business parting from this watch now, Miss Scarlett.
You needs all your valuables to sell for that tax money.
You think I'd sell Pa's watch?
And don't cry.
I can stand everybody's tears but yours.
Oh, Mammy, Mammy.
You been brave so long, Miss Scarlett, you just gotta go on being brave.
Think about your pa like he used to be.
I can't think about Pa.
I can't think of anything but that $300.
Ain't no good thinking about that, Miss Scarlett.
Ain't nobody got that much money.
Nobody but Yankees and scalawags got that much money now.
Rhett.
Who that? A Yankee?
Oh, Mammy, I'm so thin and pale and
I haven't any clothes.
Scoot up to the attic and get down Ma's old box of dress patterns.
What you up to with Miss Ellen's portiere?
You'll make me a new dress.
Not with Miss Ellen's portieres. Not while I got breath in me.
Great balls of fire. They're my portieres now.
I'm going to Atlanta for that $300 and I've got to go looking like a queen.
Who going to Atlanta with you? I'm going alone.
That's what you think. I's going to Atlanta with you.
With you and that new dress.
Now, Mammy, darling.
No use to try to sweet-talk me, Miss Scarlett.
I's knowed you since I put the first pair of diapers on you.
I said I's going to Atlanta with you, and going I is.
Kings and treys, huh? Too good for me, Major.
Pity we couldn't have fought the war out in a poker game.
You'd have done better than Gen. Grant with far less effort.
What is it, Corporal?
Sir, there's a lady to see Capt. Butler. Says she's his sister.
Another sister?
This is a jail, not a harem, Capt. Butler.
No, Major, she ain't one of those.
This one's got her mammy with her.
She has?
I'd like to see this one, Major, without her mammy.
Let's see, my losses for the afternoon come to what?
$340.00
My debts do mount up, don't they, Major?
All right, Corporal.
Show Capt. Butler's sister to his cell.
Thank you, Major. Excuse me, gentlemen.
It's hard to be strict with a man who loses money so pleasantly.
Rhett. Scarlett.
My dear little sister.
It's all right, Corporal. My sister has brought me no files or saws.
Can I really kiss you now?
On the forehead like a good brother.
No, thanks. I'll wait and hope for better things.
Oh, Rhett, I was so distressed when I heard you were in jail.
I simply couldn't sleep for thinking.
It's not true they're going to hang you?
Would you be sorry?
Oh, Rhett. Well, don't worry yet.
They have plotted some charge against me
but they're really after my money.
They think I made off with the Confederate Treasury.
Well, did you?
What a leading question.
But let's not talk about sordid things like money.
How good of you to come and see me. And how pretty you look.
Oh, Rhett, how you do run on, teasing a country girl like me.
Thank heavens you're not in rags. I'm tired of seeing women in rags.
Turn around.
You look good enough to eat. And prosperous, too.
Thank you, I've been doing very well.
Everybody's doing well at Tara, only
I got so bored I just thought I'd treat myseIf to a visit to town.
You're a heartless creature. But that's part of your charm.
You know you've got more charm than the law allows.
Now I didn't come here to talk silliness about me, Rhett.
I came because I was so miserable at the thought of you in trouble.
I was mad at you the night you left me on the road to Tara
and I still haven't forgiven you.
Oh, Scarlett, don't say that.
Well, I must admit I might not be alive now, only for you.
And when I think of myseIf with everything I could possibly hope for
and not a care in the world, and you here in this horrid jail
and not even a human jail, Rhett, a horse jail.
Oh, listen to me trying to make jokes when
when I really want to cry.
In a minute I shall cry.
Scarlett, can it be possible that
Can what be possible, Rhett?
That you've grown a woman's heart, a real woman's heart?
I have, Rhett. I know I have.
You know, it's worth being in jail just to hear you say that.
It's well worth it.
You can drop the moonlight and magnolias, Scarlett.
So things have been going well at Tara, have they?
What have you done with your hands?
I went riding last week without my gloves.
These don't belong to a lady. You've worked with them like a field hand.
Why did you lie? What are you up to?
In another minute, I'd almost believe you cared something.
But I do care.
Suppose we get down to the truth.
You want something from me badly enough
to put on quite a show in your velvets.
What is it? Money?
I want $300 to pay the taxes on Tara.
I did lie to you when I said everything was all right.
Things are just as bad as they possibly could be. And you've got millions, Rhett.
What collateral are you offering?
My earbobs. Not interested.
A mortgage on Tara. What would I do with a farm?
You wouldn't lose. I'd pay you back out of next year's cotton.
Not good enough. Have you nothing better?
You once said you loved me.
If you still love me, Rhett
You haven't forgotten that I'm not a marrying man?
No, I haven't forgotten.
You're not worth $300.
You'll never mean anything but misery to any man.
Go on, insuIt me.
I don't care what you say, only give me the money.
I won't let Tara go. I can't let it go while there's a breath left in my body.
Oh, Rhett.
Won't you please give me the money?
I couldn't give you the money if I wanted to.
My funds are in Liverpool, not in Atlanta.
If I tried drawing a draft, the Yankees'd be on me like a duck on a June bug.
So you see, my dear, you've abased yourseIf to no purpose.
Here, here, here, stop it.
Want the Yankees to see you like this?
Take your hands off me, you skunk.
You knew what I was going to say before I started.
You knew you wouldn't lend me the money and yet you let me go on.
I enjoyed hearing what you had to say.
Cheer up. You can come to my hanging and I'll remember you in my will.
I'll come to your hanging. The only thing I'm afraid of
is that they won't hang you in time to pay the taxes on Tara.
Tell him Belle Watling.
Where you been lately? Thought you'd deserted Capt. Butler.
Oh, I keep myseIf occupied. Help me out.
Who that? I ain't never seen hair that color before in my life.
Does you know a dyed-haired woman?
I wish I did know that one. She'd get my money for me.
No matter what they done to you in that jail
they didn't do no more than you deserve
for visiting white trash in a jail.
Fresh and green.
Hey, what are you doing tonight, Susy?
That's one of them Georgia peaches.
There's nothing like that in Ohio.
You know what we're going to do? What?
We're going to give every last one of you 40 acres and a mule.
And a mule? Forty acres and a mule.
Gee.
'Cause we're your friends
and you're gonna become voters
and you're gonna vote like your friends do.
What's your hurry, sister?
What's come over this here town?
Yankees have come over it. Same as they've come over all of us.
Out of our way, trash.
Get out of the way here.
Get away. Go on.
Surely it can't be Miss Scarlett.
Why Frank Kennedy. And Mammy.
It sure is good to see home folks.
I didn't know you were in Atlanta.
I didn't know you were.
Didn't Miss Suellen tell you about my store?
Did she? I don't remember. Have you a store?
This?
Won't you come in, and look around a bit?
I don't suppose it looks like much to a lady, but
I can't help being proud of it.
You're not making money?
Well, I can't complain. In fact, I'm mighty encouraged.
Folks tell me I'm just a born merchant.
It won't be long now before Miss Suellen and I can marry.
Are you doing as well as all that?
Yes, I am, Miss Scarlett.
I'm no millionaire yet
but I've cleared $1, 000 already.
And lumber too.
Well
that's only a sideline.
A sideline, Frank?
With all the good Georgia pine around Atlanta and all this building going on?
Well, all that takes money, Miss Scarlett
and I've got to be thinking about buying a home.
What do you want a home for?
For Miss Suellen and me to set up housekeeping.
Here in Atlanta. You'd want to bring her to Atlanta, wouldn't you?
There wouldn't be much help in that for Tara.
I don't rightly know what you mean, Miss Scarlett.
I don't mean a thing.
Frank, how'd you like to drive me out to my Aunt Pitty's?
Nothing would give me more pleasure, Miss Scarlett.
You'd better stay to supper, too.
I'm sure Aunt Pitty'd be agreeable and I'd like a good long visit with you.
Oh, you act on me just like a tonic, Miss Scarlett.
And will you tell me all the news
all the news of Miss Suellen?
What's the matter, Miss Scarlett?
Miss Suellen's not ill, is she?
Oh, no, no.
I thought surely she had written you.
I guess she was ashamed to write you.
She should be ashamed.
Oh, how awful to have such a mean sister.
You must tell me, Miss Scarlett. Don't leave me on tenterhooks.
Well, she's going to marry one of the county boys next month.
She just got tired of waiting and was afraid she'd be an old maid and.
Oh, I'm sorry to be the one to tell you.
Oh, it's colder. I left my muff at home.
Would you mind if I put my hand in your pocket?
But, Melanie, you don't realize what she's done.
She's gone and married my Mr. Kennedy.
She did it to save Tara, you must understand that.
I hate Tara.
And I hate Scarlett. She's the only thing I hate worse than Tara.
It's all my fault.
I should have committed highway robbery to get that tax money for you.
I couldn't let you do anything like that, and.
Well, anyway, it's done now.
Yes, it's done now.
You wouldn't let me do anything dishonorable
but you'd sell yourseIf in marriage to a man you didn't love.
Well, at least you won't have to worry about my helplessness anymore.
What do you mean?
I'm going to New York.
I've arranged to get a position in a bank there.
But you can't do that.
I counted on you to help me start a lumber business, Ashley
and, well, I counted on you.
I wouldn't be any good to you.
I don't know anything about the lumber business.
You know as much as you do about banking.
And I'd give you haIf the business, Ashley.
That's generous of you, Scarlett.
But it isn't that.
If I go to Atlanta and take help from you again
I'dbury forever any hope of standing alone.
Oh, is that all?
Well, you could gradually buy the business and then it would be your own, and.
No, Scarlett.
Ashley.
Scarlett.
Scarlett, what is it?
Ashley's so mean and hateful.
What have you done?
She wanted me to go to Atlanta.
To help me start my lumber business, and he won't lift a finger to help me, and he.
Why, how unchivalrous of you.
Why, think, Ashley, think.
If it hadn't been for Scarlett, I'd have died in Atlanta.
And maybe we wouldn't have had little Beau, and
and when I think of her picking cotton and plowing just to keep food
in our mouths, I could just.
Oh, my darling.
All right, Melanie.
I'll go to Atlanta.
I can't fight you both.
Quick then please
Well, here's your new mill hands, Mrs. Kennedy.
The pick of all the best jaiIs in Georgia.
They look pretty thin and weak to me, Gallegher.
Halt.
They're the best you can lease, ma'am.
And if you'll just give Johnny Gallegher a free hand
you'll get what you want out of them.
All right, you're the foreman.
All I ask is, you keep the mill running and deliver my lumber when I want it.
Johnny Gallegher's your man, Miss.
But remember
no questions and no interference.
That's a bargain. Start them in the morning, Gallegher.
Come on, get a move on. Come on, move on there.
But, Scarlett, this isn't right and you know it.
It's bad enough for a woman to be in business, but
What are you complaining about?
You wouldn't have owned a mill had I not taken over.
I didn't want the mill, and we couldn't have bought it
if you hadn't pressed all of our friends for the money they owed me.
Isn't that right, Ashley?
What are you running, a charitable institution?
Go back to the store, then go home and take your medicine.
You're not looking very well.
But, sugar, shouldn't you come home with me?
Great balls of fire. Don't bother me anymore, and don't call me sugar.
All right, all right.
Good night, Ashley.
She can get mad quicker than any woman I ever saw.
Scarlett, I don't like to interfere, but
I do wish you'd let me hire free darkies instead of using convicts.
I believe we could do better.
Darkies. Why, their pay would break us, and convicts are dirt cheap.
If we just give Gallegher a free hand
A free hand. You know what that means. He'll starve them and whip them.
Some of them are sick, underfed.
Oh, Ashley, how you do run on.
Left alone, you'd be giving them chicken three times a day and
tucking them to sleep with eiderdown quilts.
Scarlett, I will not make money out of the enforced labor and misery of others.
You weren't so particular about owning slaves.
That was different. We didn't treat them that way.
Besides, I'd have freed them all when father died
if the war hadn't already freed them.
Oh, I'm sorry, Ashley.
But have you forgotten what it's like without money?
I found out that money is the most important thing in the world
and I don't intend ever to be without it again.
I'll make enough so the Yankees can never take Tara away from me.
I'll make it the only way I know how.
But we're not the only Southerners who have suffered.
Look at all our friends. They're keeping their honor and their kindness, too.
And they're starving. I've got no use for fooIs who won't help themselves.
I know what they're saying about me, and I don't care.
I'll make friends with the Yankee carpetbaggers.
And I'll beat them at their own game, and you'll beat them with me.
That's it. Move it a little over to that side.
Afternoon, Mrs. Kennedy.
Good afternoon.
Business is certainly growing, ain't it?
It certainly is.
But you're doing business with the same people who robbed us
and tortured us and left us to starve.
All that's past, Melly.
And I intend to make the best of things, even if they are Yankee things.
And do you know, Dolly Merriwether, that Dr. Meade actually saw her
peddling lumber to those Yankees, herself.
And that isn't all.
I think it's shocking what she's doing to my brother, Ashley.
She's even taken to driving her own buggy.
My dear Mrs. Kennedy.
My very dear Mrs. Kennedy.
I don't see how you have the gall to face me.
When I think you could have had my millions
if you'd just waited a little while.
Oh, how fickle is woman.
What is it you want? I have important things to do.
Would you satisfy my curiosity on a point which has bothered me for some time?
Well, what is it? Be quick.
Tell me, Scarlett, do you never shrink from marrying men you don't love?
How did you ever get out of jail? Why didn't they hang you?
Oh, that. Not much trouble.
There's nothing much that money won't buy.
I observe it's even bought you the honorable Mr. Wilkes.
So you still hate Ashley Wilkes.
Do you know, I believe you're jealous of him.
You still think you're the belle of the county, don't you?
That you're the cutest little trick in shoe leather.
And that every man you meet is dying of love for you.
Let me by.
Don't be angry, Scarlett. Tell me, where are you going?
To the mill, if it's any of your business.
Through shantytown, alone?
Haven't you been told it's dangerous to drive alone through all that riffraff?
Don't worry about me.
I can shoot straight if I don't have to shoot too far.
What a woman.
Could ya gimme a quarter?
Let go of my horse.
Hold this horse.
She has a gun.
Help.
Miss Scarlett.
Miss Scarlett, wait. Miss Scarlett.
Miss Scarlett. It's Big Sam.
Big Sam.
Miss Scarlett. Wait.
Sam. Sam.
Is you hurt, Miss Scarlett? Did they hurt you?
Don't you cry, Miss Scarlett. Big Sam'll get you out of this in a jiffy.
Horse, make tracks.
You get to Tara just as quick as you can, and stay there.
I sure will. I's got enough of them carpetbaggers.
Thank you, Mr. Frank. Goodbye, Miss Scarlett.
Goodbye, Sam, and thank you.
Scarlett, change your dress and go over to Miss Melly's for the evening.
I've got to go to a political meeting.
A political meeting.
How can you go to a political meeting
after what I've been through this afternoon?
Oh, sugar. You're more scared than hurt.
Nobody cares about me. You all act as though it was nothing at all.
The men talk, talk, talk about protecting our women
and after what happened to me today Frank has to go to a political meeting.
And if it won't pain you too much, lndia Wilkes
I'dbe much obliged if you'll tell me why you're staring at me.
Has my face gone green or something?
It won't pain me.
What happened this afternoon was just what you deserved.
And if there was any justice, you'd have gotten worse.
India, hush up.
Let her talk, Melanie. She's always hated me.
Ever since I took your brother away from her
though she's too much of a hypocrite to admit it.
If she thought anyone'd go for her
she'd walk down the street naked.
I do hate you.
You've done all you could to lower the prestige of decent people.
Now you've endangered the lives of our men, because they
India.
I don't think we'd better say any more, or one of us will be saying too much.
What's going on around here that I don't know about?
Somebody's comin' up the walk.
Somebody that ain't Mr. Ashley.
Will you hand me the pistol, please, Mrs. Meade?
Whoever it is
we know nothing.
Where have they gone?
You've got to tell me, Mrs. Wilkes. It's life or death.
Don't tell him anything. He's a Yankee spy.
Quickly, please. There may still be time.
How did you know?
I've been playing poker with two Yankee captains.
They knew there'd be trouble tonight.
They've sent their cavalry out to be ready for it.
Your husband and his friends are walking into a trap.
Don't tell him. He's trying to trap you.
Out the Decatur Road. The old Sullivan plantation.
The house is burned. They're meeting in the cellar.
I'll do what I can.
What's all this about? If you don't tell me, I'll go crazy.
We thought it best not to tell you, Scarlett.
But Ashley and Frank and the others have gone to clean out those woods
where you were attacked.
It's what a great many of our Southern gentlemen have had
to do lately for our protection.
And if they're captured, they'll be hanged, Scarlett.
And it will be your fault.
Another word, and you go out of this house, lndia.
Scarlett did what she thought she had to do.
And our men are doing what they think they have to do.
Frank.
And Ashley.
Oh, it isn't possible.
There's horses, Miss Melly. Here they come.
You're sewing, you're sewing.
Open the door, Mammy.
Good evening, Mrs. Kennedy.
Which of you ladies is Mrs. Wilkes?
I am Mrs. Wilkes.
I should like to speak to Mr. Wilkes, if you please.
He's not here.
Are you sure?
Don't you doubt Miss Melly's word.
I meant no disrespect, Mrs. Wilkes.
If you'll give me your word, I won't search the house.
Search if you like, but Mr. Wilkes is at a political meeting at Mr. Kennedy's store.
He's not at the store, and there's no meeting tonight.
No political meeting.
We'll wait outside till he and his friends return.
Sergeant, surround the house. Put a man on each door and window.
Yes, sir.
Keep on with your sewing, ladies.
And I'll read aloud.
The Personal History and Experience of David Copperfield.
Chapter one.
I'm born.
To begin my life, with the beginning of my life, I record that I was born.
Chapter Nine. I have a memorable birthday.
l pass over all that happened at school
until the anniversary of my birthday came around in March.
Except that Steerforth was more to be admired than ever.
l remember nothing.
He was going away at the end of the haIf year, if not sooner
and was more spirited and independent than before in my eyes
and, therefore, more engaging than before, but
beyond this I remember nothing.
The great.
l remember nothing.
Melly. They're drunk.
Leave this to me, Scarlett.
And, please, say nothing.
You stupid fool.
Quiet.
Will you shut up for the love of?
Hello, Melly.
So, you've got my husband intoxicated again, Captain Butler.
Well, bring him in.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Wilkes. Your husband's under arrest.
If you arrest all the men who get intoxicated
you must have a good many Yankees in jail.
Bring him in, Captain Butler. If you can walk yourself.
Oh
I want to tell you a story.
Listen, Doctor, l.
Put him there in that chair.
And now, Captain Butler, will you please leave my house
and try to remember not to come here again?
Well, now that's fine thanks I get for bringing him home
and not leaving him on the streets in this shameful condition.
Now, boys, all together.
Dr. Meade
I'm astonished at you.
Oh, Ashley. How can you do this to me?
I ain't so very drunk, Melly.
Take him into the bedroom and lay him out on the bed as usual.
Don't touch him, he's under arrest.
Now, Tom.
What do you want to arrest him for?
I've seen him drunker.
I've seen you drunker. And you've seen me.
He can lie in the gutter for all I care. I'm not a policeman.
But he led a raid tonight on that shantytown
where Mrs. Kennedy got into trouble this afternoon.
A lot of those shanties were burned. A couple of men were killed.
It's about time you rebeIs learned you can't take the law into your own hands.
What are you laughing at?
This isn't your night to teach that lesson, Tom.
These two have been with me tonight. Yes, sir.
With you, Rhett?
Where?
I don't like to say in the presence of ladies.
You'd better say.
Come out on the porch and I'll tell you.
Speak out, Captain Butler.
I think I have a right to know where my husband's been.
Well, ma'am, we dropped in on a friend of mine
and the captain's.
A Mrs. Belle Watling.
We played cards, drank champagne and
well.
Now, you've done it. Did you have to show me up in front of my wife?
Now I hope you're satisfied, Tom.
These ladies won't be on speaking terms with their husbands tomorrow.
Rhett, I had no idea, l.
Look here, will you take an oath that they were with you tonight at
at Belle's?
Ask Belle, if you don't believe me. She'll tell you, Captain.
Will you give me your word as a gentleman?
As a gentleman?
Why certainly, Tom.
Well, if l
if I've made a mistake, I'm sorry.
I hope you'll forgive me, Mrs. Wilkes. I.
If you'll go and leave us in peace, please.
Well, I say I'm sorry, and
well, I am sorry.
Come on, Sergeant.
Lock that door. Pull down the shades.
Ashley.
It's all right. It's only in the shoulder.
Get him on the bed where I can dress the wound.
I think I can walk.
It's not worth the effort. Which way?
In here.
Mammy, I want some hot water. Yes, sir.
And lint for bandages. I'll find some.
Now what can I use for a probe? If I only had my bag.
Were you really there? What did it look like?
Does she have cut-glass chandeliers, plush curtains and dozens of mirrors?
Good heavens, Mrs. Meade, remember yourself.
And now, Captain Butler, tell me what happened, all that happened.
I was too late.
When I got to the old Sullivan place there'd already been a skirmish with the Yankees.
I found Mr. Wilkes wounded and Dr. Meade was with him.
I had to prove they had been somewhere, anyplace but where they were.
So I took them to Belle's.
And she took them in?
She's by way of being an old friend of mine.
Oh, I'm sorry. I
I'm sorry I couldn't think up a more dignified alibi.
This isn't the first time you've come between me and disaster, Captain Butler.
It isn't likely that I'd question any device of yours.
And now, I'll go and see what Dr. Meade needs.
Oh, Ashley.
Ashley.
Have you no interest in what's become of your own husband, Mrs. Kennedy?
Did Frank go with you to Belle Watling's?
No.
Well, where is he?
He's lying out on Decatur Road
shot through the head.
He's dead.
Who is it?
It's Miss Watlin'.
Oh, Mrs. Watling. Won't you come in the house?
Oh, no, I couldn't do that, Miss Wilkes.
You come in and sit a minute with me.
How can I thank you enough for what you did for us?
How can any of us thank you enough?
I got your note sayin' you was goin' to call on me and thank me.
Why, Miss Wilkes, you must have lost your mind.
I come up here as soon as it was dark to tell you
you mustn't even think of any such thing.
Well, it wouldn't be fittin' at all.
It wouldn't be fitting to thank a kind woman who saved my husband's life?
Miss Wilkes, there ain't never been a lady in this town nice to me like you was.
I mean, about the money for the hospital, you know.
And I don't forget a kindness.
And I got to thinking about you being left a widow with a little boy
if Mr. Wilkes got hung
and he's a nice little boy, your boy is, Miss Wilkes.
I got a boy myseIf and so l.
Oh, you have? Does he live?
Oh, no, ma'am, he ain't here in Atlanta.
He ain't never been here.
He's off at school.
I ain't seen him since he was little.
Well, anyway, if it had been that Miss Kennedy's husband by hisself
I wouldn't have lifted a finger to, no matter what Captain Butler said.
She's a mighty cold woman.
Prancin' about Atlanta by herself.
She killed her husband same as if she shot him.
You mustn't say unkind things about my sister-in-law.
Please don't freeze me, Miss Wilkes.
I forgot how you liked her.
But she just ain't in the same class with you and I can't help it if I think so.
Well, anyway, I gotta be goin'.
I'm scared somebody'll recognize this carriage if I stayed here any longer.
That wouldn't do you no good.
And Miss Wilkes
if you ever see me on the street, you don't have to speak to me.
I'll understand.
I should be proud to speak to you. Proud to be under obligation to you.
I hope we meet again.
Oh, no, ma'am, that wouldn't be fittin'.
Good night, Miss Wilkes. Good night, Mrs. Watling.
And you're wrong about Mrs. Kennedy.
She's brokenhearted about her husband.
Great balls of fire. It's Rhett.
Miss Scarlett, Captain Butler here to see you.
I told him you was prostrate with grief.
Tell him I'll be right down, Mammy.
She says she's comin'.
I don't know why she's comin'. But she's a-comin'.
You don't like me, Mammy.
Now don't you argue with me, you don't. You really don't.
It's no good, Scarlett.
What?
The cologne.
I'm sure I don't know what you mean.
I mean you've been drinking. Brandy. Quite a lot.
Well, what if I have? Is that any of your affair?
Don't drink alone, Scarlett.
People always find out and it ruins the reputation.
What is it?
This is more than losing old Frank.
Oh, Rhett
I'm so afraid.
I don't believe it. You've never been afraid in your life.
I'm afraid now.
I'm afraid of dying and going to hell.
You look pretty healthy, and maybe there isn't any hell.
Oh, there is. I know there is. I was raised on it.
Well, far be it from me to question the teachings of childhood.
Tell me what you've done that hell yawns before you.
I ought never to have married Frank to begin with.
He was Suellen's beau and he loved her, not me.
And I made him miserable. And I killed him.
Yes, I did. I killed him.
Oh, Rhett
For the first time I'm finding out what it is to be sorry for something I've done.
Here. Dry your eyes.
If you had it all to do over again, you'd do no differently.
You're like the thief who isn't the least bit sorry he stole
but he's terribly, terribly sorry he's going to jail.
I'm glad Mother's dead.
I'm glad she's dead so she can't see me.
I always wanted to be like her, calm and kind and.
And I certainly have turned out disappointing.
You know, Scarlett, I think you're on the verge of a crying jag.
So I'll change the subject and say what I came to say.
Say it, then, and get out.
What is it?
That I can't go on any longer without you.
You are the most ill-bred man to come here at a time like this with your filthy
I made up my mind that you were the only woman for me
the first day I saw you at Twelve Oaks.
Now that you've got the lumber mill and Frank's money
you won't come to me as you did to the jail.
So I see I shall have to marry you.
I never heard of such bad taste.
Would you be more convinced if I fell to my knees?
Turn me loose, you varmint, and get out of here.
Forgive me for startling you with the impetuosity of my sentiments
my dear Scarlett. I mean, my dear Mrs. Kennedy.
But it cannot have escaped your notice that for some time past
the friendship I have feIt for you has ripened into a deeper feeling.
A feeling more beautiful, more pure, more sacred.
Dare I name it? Can it be love?
Get up off your knees. I don't like your common jokes.
This is an honorable proposal of marriage
made at what I consider a most opportune moment.
I can't go all my life waiting to catch you between husbands.
You're coarse, and you're conceited.
And I think this conversation has gone far enough.
Besides, I shall never marry again.
Oh, yes, you will, and you'll marry me.
You? You.
I don't love you.
And I don't like being married.
Did you ever think of marrying just for fun?
Marriage, fun? Fiddle-dee-dee. Fun for men, you mean.
Hush up. Do you want them to hear you?
You've been married to a boy and an old man.
Why not try a husband of the right age, with a way with women?
You're a fool, Rhett Butler, when you know I shall always love another man.
Stop it. Do you hear me, Scarlett? Stop it. No more of that talk.
Rhett, don't, I shall faint.
I want you to faint. This is what you were meant for.
None of the fooIs you've known have kissed you like this, have they?
Your Charles, or your Frank, or your stupid Ashley.
Say you're going to marry me. Say yes. Say yes.
Yes.
Are you sure you meant it? You don't want to take it back?
No.
Look at me and try to tell me the truth.
Did you say yes because of my money?
Well.
Yes. Partly.
Partly?
Well, you know, Rhett, money does help, and, of course I am fond of you.
Fond of me.
Well, if I said I was madly in love with you, you'd know I was lying
but you always said we had a lot in common.
Yes, you're right, my dear.
I'm not in love with you any more than you are with me.
Heaven help the man who ever really loves you.
What kind of a ring would you like, my darling?
Oh, a diamond ring. And do buy a great big one, Rhett.
You shall have the biggest and the most vulgar ring in Atlanta.
I'll take you to New Orleans for the most expensive honeymoon
my ill-gotten gains can buy.
Oh, that would be just heavenly.
And I think I'll buy your trousseau for you, too.
Rhett, how wonderful, but
you won't tell anybody, will you, Rhett?
Still the little hypocrite.
Rhett, aren't you going to kiss me goodbye?
Don't you think you've had enough kissing for one afternoon?
You're impossible.
You can go and I don't care if you never come back.
But I will come back.
What are you thinking about, Scarlett?
I'm thinking about how rich we are.
Rhett, I can keep the lumber business too, can't l?
Yes, of course, you can, if it amuses you.
Now that you're rich you can tell everyone to go to the devil
as you've always said you wanted to.
But you were the main one I wanted to go to the devil.
Don't scrape the plate, Scarlett. I'm sure there's more in the kitchen.
Oh, Rhett, can I have one of those chocolate ones stuffed with meringue?
If you don't stop being such a glutton, you'll get as fat as Mammy
then I'll divorce you.
Wouldn't it be nice if you bought something for Mammy, too?
Why should I buy her a present when she called us both mules?
Mules? Why mules?
Yes, she said we could give ourselves airs, and get ourselves all slicked up
like racehorses but we were just mules in horse harness
and we didn't fool anybody.
I never heard anything more true.
Mammy's a smart old soul
and one of the few people I know whose respect I'd like to have.
I won't give her a thing. She doesn't deserve it.
Then I'll take her a petticoat.
My Mammy always said when she went to heaven
she wanted a red taffeta petticoat, so stiff that it would stand by itself
and so rustly, the Lord would think it was made of angels' wings.
Why, she won't take it from you. She'd rather die than wear it.
That may be, but I'm making the gesture just the same.
Wake up. Wake up.
You were having another nightmare.
Oh, Rhett.
When I was so cold and hungry and
and so tired l
I couldn't find it. I ran through the mist and I couldn't find it.
Find what, honey? Oh, I don't know.
I always dream the same dream and I never know.
It seems to be hidden in the mist.
Darling.
Rhett, do you think I'll ever dream that I've found it and that I'm safe?
Dreams don't work that way, but when you get used to being safe and warm
you'll stop dreaming that dream.
And, Scarlett, I'm going to see that you are safe.
Would you do something for me if I asked you?
You know I would.
Will you take me away from here?
Don't you like New Orleans?
Oh, I love New Orleans, but I want to go home and visit Tara.
Will you take me to Tara?
Yes, Scarlett, of course I will. We'll go tomorrow.
You get your strength from this red earth of Tara, Scarlett.
You're part of it, and it's part of you.
Rhett, I'd give anything to have Tara the way it was before the war.
Would you? Then go ahead and make it that way.
Spend whatever you want, make it as fine a plantation as it ever was.
Oh, Rhett.
Rhett, you are good to me.
And can we still have our big new house in Atlanta?
Yes, and it can be as ornate as you want
marbled terraces, stained-glass windows and all.
Rhett, won't everyone be jealous?
I want everybody who's been mean to me to be pea-green with envy.
I don't care. Scarlett's hateful, building that new house just to show off
and even taking our servants.
Oh, darling, you mustn't think unkindly of her.
She's made it possible for us to keep Tara always.
Yes, and what good is Tara?
She's had three husbands and I'll be an old maid.
Great Jehosophat.
Lordsy, we sure is rich now.
It ain't quality.
But that's ridiculous. Why can't I go in?
I'm entitled to at least see what my own child looks like.
You control yourself, Mr. Rhett. You'll be seein' it for a long time.
I'd like to apologize, Mr. Rhett, about it's not being a boy.
Oh, hush your mouth, Mammy. Who wants a boy?
Boys aren't any use to anybody. Don't you think I'm proof of that?
Have a drink of sherry, Mammy.
Mammy, she is beautiful, isn't she?
She sure is.
Did you ever see a prettier one?
Well, sir, Miss Scarlett was mighty nigh that pretty when she come, but not quite.
Have another glass, Mammy.
What's that rustling noise I hear?
Lordsy, Mr. Rhett. That ain't nothin' but my red silk petticoat you done give me.
Nothing but your petticoat. I don't believe it. Let me see.
Pull up your skirt.
Mr. Rhett. You is bad.
Yeah, oh, Lord.
You sure took a long enough time about wearing it.
Yes, sir, too long.
No more mule in horse's harness?
Mr. Rhett, Miss Scarlett was bad tellin' you about that.
You ain't holdin' that against old Mammy, is you?
No, I ain't holding it against you. I just wanted to know.
Have another glass, Mammy. Here, take the whole bottle.
Dr. Meade says you may go in now, Captain Butler.
This sure is a happy day to me.
I done diapered three generations of this family's girls
and it sure is a happy day.
Oh, yes, Mammy. The happiest days are when babies come.
I wish.
Oh, Mammy, she's beautiful. What do you suppose they'll name her?
Miss Scarlett done told me if it was a girl
she's goin' to name it Eugenia Victoria.
Yes
she's a beautiful baby
the most beautiful baby ever.
Yes.
Do you know that this is your birthday?
That you're a week old today?
Yes, I'm going to buy her a pony the likes of which this town has never seen.
Yes, I'm gonna send her to the best schooIs in Charleston.
Yes. And her'll be received by the best families in the South.
And when it comes time for her to marry
well, she'll be a little princess.
You certainly are making a fool of yourself.
And why shouldn't l?
She's the first person who's ever completely belonged to me.
Great balls of fire.
I had the baby, didn't l?
It's Melanie. May I come in?
Come in, Melly.
Yes, come in and look at my daughter's beautiful blue eyes.
But, Captain Butler, most babies have blue eyes when they're born.
Don't try to tell him anything. He knows everything about babies.
Nevertheless, her eyes are blue and they're going to stay blue.
As blue as the bonnie blue flag.
That's it. That's what we'll call her.
Bonnie Blue Butler.
Try again, Mammy.
Twenty inches.
Twenty inches. I've grown as big as Aunt Pitty.
You've simply got to make it 18 and a haIf again, Mammy.
You done had a baby, Miss Scarlett
and you ain't never goin' to be no 18 and a haIf inches again.
Never. And there ain't nothin' to do about it.
There is something to do about it.
I'm just not going to get old and fat before my time.
I just won't have any more babies.
I heard Mr. Rhett say that he'll be wantin' a son next year.
Go tell Captain Butler I've decided not to go out after all.
I'll have supper in my room.
I got your message. I'll have them bring my supper up here too.
No objections to that, I hope?
No.
Yes.
I mean, I don't care where you have your supper.
Rhett?
Yes?
You see
well, I've decided
well, I hope I don't have any more children.
My pet, as I told you before Bonnie was born
it's immaterial to me whether you have one child or 20.
No, but you know what l.
Do you know what I mean?
I do. And do you know I can divorce you for this?
You're just low enough to think of something like that.
If you had any chivalry in you or would be nice like, well, look at Ashley Wilkes.
Melanie can't have any more children and he.
You've been to the lumber office this afternoon, haven't you?
What has that got to do with it?
Quite the little gentleman, Ashley. Pray go on, Mrs. Butler.
It's no use. You wouldn't understand.
You know, I'm sorry for you, Scarlett.
Sorry for me?
Yes, sorry for you because you're throwing away happiness with both hands
and reaching out for something that will never make you happy.
I don't know what you're talking about.
If you were free and Miss Melly were dead and you had your precious
honorable Ashley, do you think you'd be happy with him?
You'd never know him, never even understand his mind
any more than you understand anything except money.
Never mind about that. What I want to know is
You may keep your sanctity, Scarlett. It'll work no hardship on me.
Do you mean to say you don't care?
The world is full of many things and many people, and I shan't be lonely.
I'll find comfort elsewhere.
Well, that's fine. But I warn you.
Just in case you change your mind, I intend to lock my door.
Why bother? If I wanted to come in, no lock could keep me out.
I always knew that most women were cheats, hypocritical and hard.
But this one.... Rhett, it ain't no use.
What do you mean? I mean you're poisoned with her.
I don't care what she's done to you, you're still in love with her.
And don't think it pleasures me none to say it.
Maybe so. But I'm through with her, I tell you. I'm through.
You gotta think of the child. The child's worth ten of the mother.
You're a shrewd woman, Belle, and a very nice one.
Yes, Rhett?
I was just thinking of the difference between you, and
you're both hard-headed business women and you're both successful.
But you've got a heart, Belle
and you're honest.
Goodbye, Rhett.
Goodbye, Belle.
She'll be a wonderful horsewoman.
Look at those hands, and that seat.
Oh, fiddle-dee-dee.
Just why we have to wheel the baby when we have a house full of servants.
Good morning, Mrs. Merriwether.
Good morning, Captain Butler.
Good morning, Scarlett.
Making fooIs of ourselves in front of these old buffaloes.
If you'd thought of your position years ago, you wouldn't have to do this.
But as it is, we'll cultivate every female dragon of the old guard in this town.
Good morning, Mrs. Whiting.
Good morning, Captain Butler. Good morning, Scarlett.
So the millionaire speculator's turning respectable.
All of our money can't buy what I want for Bonnie.
Oh, I'll admit I've been at fault, too.
But Bonnie's going to have a place among decent people.
Yes, even if we both have to crawl on our bellies to every fat old cat.
Good morning, Mrs. Meade.
Good morning, Captain Butler. Good morning, Scarlett.
Mrs. Merriwether, I've always had a great regard for your knowledge.
I wonder if you could give me some advice.
Why, certainly, Captain Butler.
My Bonnie sucks her thumb. I can't make her stop it.
You should make her stop it. It'll ruin the shape of her mouth.
I know, I know.
She has such a beautiful mouth, too. I tried putting soap under her nails.
Soap. Bah.
Put quinine on her thumb and she'll stop sucking it quick enough.
Quinine. I never would have thought of it.
I can't thank you enough, Mrs. Merriwether.
You've taken a great load off my mind. Good morning.
Good morning, Dolly.
Wasn't that Captain Butler?
Good morning, Caroline. I was just thinking.
There must be a great deal of good in a man who could love a child so much.
But of course there is.
Oh, did I tell you that Fanny Elsing told Dr. Meade that Captain Butler
finally admitted he was honored by the Confederate Congress
for his services at the Battle of Franklin?
No. And did I tell you, Caroline, that Captain Butler
made a stupendous contribution to the Association for the Beautification
of the Graves of the Glorious Dead?
No.
My little grandbaby, Napoleon Picard, is giving a party for Bonnie next week.
Why, Dolly Merriwether, you know right well it was my idea
to give a party for Bonnie Butler.
Why Caroline Meade.
Now watch Daddy put your pony over, Bonnie. Now watch.
Daddy, let me. Let me.
All right, darling. Put her on, Pork.
Up we go.
Oh, there.
Lordsy mercy. There he goes again.
Grip tightly with your legs and sit close. Lean forward and be sure you go with him.
Hold your reins properly in a firm hand. Up.
That was fine. I knew you'd do it.
When you get a little older, I'll take you to Kentucky and Virginia.
You'll be the greatest horsewoman in the South. Give your daddy a kiss.
Mr. Rhett. Mr. Rhett.
Mr. Rhett.
Did you see her, Mammy? Wasn't she wonderful?
Mr. Rhett, I done told you and told you it just ain't fittin'
for a girl child to ride astraddle with her dress flyin' up.
All right, Mammy. I'll teach her to ride sidesaddle.
And I'll buy her a blue velvet riding habit. She'll love that.
A nice black broadcloth is what little girIs wear.
Now, Mammy, be reasonable.
Well, I don't think it's fittin', but.
It ain't fittin', it just ain't fittin'.
It ain't fittin'.
Why, Scarlett.
What are you doing downtown at this time of day?
Ashley, I just
Why aren't you helping Melly get ready for my surprise birthday party?
Why, Ashley Wilkes, you aren't supposed to know anything about that.
Melly'd be so disappointed if you weren't surprised.
I won't let on. I'll be the most surprised man in Atlanta.
As long as you're here, let me show you the books
so you can see just how bad a businessman I really am.
Oh, don't let's fool with any books today.
When I'm wearing a new bonnet, all the figures I ever knew
go right slap out of my head.
The figures are well lost when the bonnet's as pretty as that one.
Scarlett, you know, you get prettier all the time.
You haven't changed a bit since the day of our last barbecue at Twelve Oaks
where you sat under a tree surrounded by dozens of beaux.
That girl doesn't exist anymore.
Nothing's turned out as I expected, Ashley.
Nothing.
Yes, we've travelled a long road since the old days, haven't we, Scarlett?
Oh, the lazy days
the warm, still country twilights
the high, soft negro laughter from the quarters
the golden warmth and security of those days.
Don't look back, Ashley.
Don't look back.
It drags at your heart till you can't do anything, but look back.
I didn't mean to make you sad, my dear.
I'd never want you to be anything but completely happy.
Oh, Ashley.
Who is it?
Only your husband.
Come in.
Am I actually being invited into the sanctuary?
You're not ready for Melanie's party.
I've got a headache, Rhett.
You go without me, and make my excuses to Melanie.
What a white-livered little coward you are. Get up.
You're going to that party and you'll have to hurry.
Has lndia dared to... Yes. India has.
Every woman and man in town knows the story.
You should kill them, spreading lies.
I have a strange way of not killing people who tell the truth.
There's no time to argue now. Get up.
I won't go. I can't go until this misunderstanding is cleared up.
You won't cheat Miss Melly out of the satisfaction of publicly
ordering you out of her house.
There was nothing wrong. India hates me so.
I can't go, Rhett. I couldn't face it.
If you don't show it tonight, you'll never be able to as long as you live.
While that wouldn't bother me, you're ruining Bonnie's chances.
You're going to that party, if only for her sake. Now, get dressed.
Wear that. Nothing modest or matronly will do for this occasion.
And put on plenty of rouge. I want you to look your part tonight.
For he's a jolly good fellow For he's a jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow Which nobody can deny
For he's a jolly good fellow.
Good night, Scarlett. But Rhett, you can't
You go into the arena alone. The lions are hungry for you.
Oh, Rhett, don't leave me. Don't.
You're not afraid?
Which nobody can deny Which nobody can deny
For he's a jolly good fellow For he's a jolly good fellow
For he's a jolly good fellow Which nobody can deny.
What a lovely dress, Scarlett, darling.
India wasn't able to come tonight.
Will you be an angel?
I do need you to help me receive my guests.
Mrs. Meade
here's our darling Scarlett.
Good evening.
Why Scarlett.
Good evening, Miss Scarlett. Good evening, Mrs. Butler.
Ashley, aren't you going to get our Scarlett a glass of punch?
Did you have a good time tonight at Miss Melly's party, child?
Yes, yes.
Now, Mammy, be sure and leave word
if Captain Butler asks for me when he comes back, I'm asleep.
Yes, ma'am.
Come in, Mrs. Butler.
Come here.
Sit down.
There's no reason why you shouldn't have your nightcap even if I am here.
I didn't want a drink. I heard a noise and
You heard nothing of the kind.
You wouldn't have come down if you'd thought I was here.
You must need a drink badly. I do not.
Take it. Don't give yourseIf airs.
I know you drink on the quiet, and I know how much you drink.
Do you think I care if you like your brandy?
You're drunk, and I'm going to bed.
I'm very drunk
and I intend getting still drunker before the evening's over
but you're not going to bed, not yet.
Sit down.
So she stood by you, did she?
How does it feel to have the woman you've wronged cloak your sins for you?
You're wondering if she knows all about you and Ashley.
You're wondering if she did it just to save her face.
You're thinking that she's a fool for doing it even if it did save your hide.
I will not listen. Yes, you'll listen.
Miss Melly's a fool, but not the kind you think.
It's just that there's too much honor in her to ever conceive of dishonor
in anyone she loves.
And she loves you.
Though just why she does, I'm sure I don't know.
If you weren't so drunk and insulting, I could explain everything.
As it is though... If you get out of that chair once more.
Of course, the comic figure in all this is the long suffering Mr. Wilkes.
Mr. Wilkes, who can't be mentally faithful to his wife
and won't be unfaithful to her technically.
Why doesn't he make up his mind?
Rhett, you.
Observe my hands, my dear.
I could tear you to pieces with them.
And I'd do it, if it'd take Ashley out of your mind forever.
But it wouldn't.
So I'll remove him from your mind forever this way.
I'll put my hands so
one on each side of your head
and I'll smash your skull between them like a walnut.
And that'll block him out.
Take your hands off me, you drunken fool.
You know I've always admired your spirit, my dear.
Never more than now, when you're cornered.
I'm not cornered.
And you'll never corner me, Rhett Butler, or frighten me.
You've lived in dirt so long, you can't understand anything else.
And you're jealous of something you can't understand. Good night.
Jealous, am l?
Yes, I suppose I am.
Even though I know you've been faithful to me all along.
How do I know?
Because I know Ashley Wilkes, and his honorable breed.
They're gentlemen.
And that's more than I can say for you or for me.
We're not gentlemen, and we have no honor, have we?
It's not that easy, Scarlett.
You turned me out while you chased Ashley Wilkes.
While you dreamed of Ashley Wilkes.
This is one night you're not turning me out.
How are you feeling this morning, Mammy?
Well, this misery in my back ain't so good.
You actin' mighty happy this mornin', Miss Scarlett.
I am, Mammy. I am.
Oh, she wept with delight when he gave her a smile
And trembled with fear at his frown.
Hello.
I'd like to extend my apologies for my conduct of last night.
Oh, but Rhett.
I was very drunk
and quite swept off my feet by your charms.
Well, you needn't bother to apologize. Nothing you ever do surprises me.
I've been thinking things over, and I really believe that
it would be better for both of us
if we admitted we'd made a mistake and got a divorce.
A divorce? Yes.
There's no point in our holding on to each other, is there?
I'll provide for you amply. You've plenty of grounds.
Just give me Bonnie. You can say what you please, I won't contest it.
Thank you very much.
But I wouldn't dream of disgracing the family with a divorce.
You'd disgrace it quick enough if Ashley were free.
It makes my head spin to think how quickly you'd divorce me.
Wouldn't you, Scarlett?
Well, answer me.
Wouldn't you?
Will you please go now, and leave me alone?
Yes, I'm going. That's what I came to tell you.
I'm going on a very extended trip to London, and I'm leaving today.
And I'm taking Bonnie with me.
So you'll please get her little duds packed right away.
You'll never take my child out of this house.
She's my child, too, Scarlett.
You're making a mistake, if you think I'm leaving her here
with a mother who hasn't the decency to consider her own reputation.
You're a fine one to talk.
You think I'll let that child out of this house
when you'll probably have her around with people like that Belle?
If you were a man I'd break your neck for that.
As it is, I'll thank you to shut your stupid mouth.
As for you, giving yourseIf pious airs about your motherhood.
Why, a cat's a better mother than you are.
Have her things packed and ready for me in an hour, or I warn you.
I've always thought a good lashing with a buggy whip would benefit you immensely.
Excuse me, Mr. Rhett.
Hello, Uncle Rhett.
Hello, hello, Beau.
Daddy, Daddy.
Where have you been? I've been waiting for you all morning.
Well, I've been hunting for a rabbit skin to wrap my little Bonnie in.
Give your best sweetheart a kiss.
I'm going to take you on a long trip to fairyland.
Where? Where?
I'm going to show you the Tower of London, where the little princes were
and London Bridge.
London Bridge.
Will it be falling down?
Well, it will if you want it to, darling.
Daddy, dark.
Dark.
Daddy. Dark.
It's all right. Who put out that light? Nurse.
Daddy, dark.
There. Yes, yes.
What's the matter with my Bonnie?
A bear.
Oh, a bear? A big bear?
Dreadful big. And he sat on my chest.
Well, I'll stay here and shoot him if he comes back.
Good evening, Mr. Butler.
Haven't I told you never to leave her alone in the dark?
If you'll pardon me, sir, children are often afraid of the dark, but they get over it.
If you just let her scream for a night or two.
Let her scream. Either you're a fool or the most inhuman woman I've ever seen.
Of course, sir, if you want her to grow up nervous and cowardly.
Cowardly.
There isn't a cowardly bone in her body. You're discharged.
As you say, sir.
Where is Mother?
Aren't you happy here in London with me?
I want to go home.
Miss Bonnie.
And Captain Butler.
Miss Scarlett. Hello, Mammy.
Honey, child.
Miss Scarlett. They's back. They's back, Miss Scarlett.
Bonnie.
Bonnie. Bonnie, baby.
Darling, baby.
Are you glad to be home?
Daddy gave me a kitten.
What a little, lovely kitten. London's a horrid place.
Oh, my darling. Where's my pony?
I want to go out and see my pony. You go out and see your pony.
Where's my pony?
I wanna go out and see my pony.
You run along with Mammy.
Come on, honey child. Go with Mammy.
Mammy sure has missed you, honey.
Mrs. Butler, I believe.
Mammy said you'd come back.
But only to bring Bonnie.
Apparently any mother, even a bad one, is better for a child than none.
You mean you're going away again?
What perception, Mrs. Butler.
Right away.
In fact, I left my bags at the station.
You're looking pale. Is there a shortage of rouge?
Or can this wanness mean you've been missing me?
If I'm pale, it's your fault.
Not because I've been missing you, but because.
Pray continue, Mrs. Butler.
It's because I'm going to have a baby.
Indeed?
And who's the happy father?
You know it's yours.
I don't want it any more than you do.
No woman would want the child of a cad like you.
I wish it were anybody's child but yours.
Well, cheer up. Maybe you'll have an accident.
Is she better?
Has she asked for me?
Don't you understand? She's delirious.
Rhett.
I want Rhett.
What's the matter, honey? Did you call somebody, child?
It's no use.
Dr. Meade's left.
Scarlett's dead.
Oh, no, she's much better.
Really she is.
There, there, Captain Butler. You're beside yourself.
She'll very soon be well again, I promise you.
No, you don't understand. She never wanted this baby.
Not want a baby? Why, every woman wants a baby.
Yes, you want children, but she doesn't. Not my children.
She told me she didn't want any more children
and I wanted to hurt her because she'd hurt me.
I wanted to and I did.
Hush. You mustn't tell me these things. It's not fit.
I didn't know about this baby until the other day when she fell.
If I'd known, I'd have come straight home whether she wanted me or not.
Well, of course you would.
And then when she told me, there on the steps, what did I do?
What did I say? I laughed and I said
But you didn't mean it. I know you didn't mean it.
Oh, but I did mean it. I was crazy with jealousy.
She's never cared for me. I thought I could make her care, but I couldn't.
You're so wrong.
Scarlett loves you a great deal, much more than she knows.
If that were only true I could wait forever.
If she'd only forgive me, forget this ever happened.
She will.
You must be patient.
Oh, no, it's not possible.
You don't understand. If you only knew who she really loved
you wouldn't believe it.
Surely you haven't listened to idle gossip.
No, Captain Butler, I wouldn't believe it.
There, there. Scarlett's going to get well and there can be other babies.
Oh no, no, she couldn't even if she wanted to, after what she's been through.
But of course she could.
I'm going to.
No, Miss Melly, you mustn't risk it. It's too dangerous.
Children are life renewing itself, Captain Butler
and when life does that danger seems very unimportant.
I've never before known anyone who was really brave.
I pray God things go well with you, Miss Melly.
And I want to thank you for all you've done for me and for Scarlett.
From my heart, I thank you.
Miss Scarlett's feelin' a heap better today, Mr. Rhett.
Thank you, Mammy.
I've come to ask your forgiveness
in the hope that we can give our life together another chance.
Our life together?
When did we ever have a life together?
Yes, you're right.
But I'm sure if we could only try again, we could be happy.
Well, what is there to make us happy now?
Well, there's Bonnie and
and I love you, Scarlett.
When did you discover that?
I've always loved you, but you've never given me a chance to show it.
Well, and just what do you want me to do?
To begin with, give up the mill, Scarlett.
We'll go away.
We'll take Bonnie and we'll have another honeymoon.
Give up the mill? But why? It's making more money than ever.
Yes, I know, but we don't need it.
Sell it, or better still, give it to Ashley.
Melanie's been such a friend to both of us.
Always Melanie. If you'd only think a little more about me.
I am thinking of you
and I'm thinking that
well, maybe it's the mill that's taken you away from me
and from Bonnie.
I know what you're thinking. Don't try to bring Bonnie into this.
You're the one taking her away from me.
But she loves you.
You've done everything possible to make her love you and not me.
Why, she's so spoiled now that
Mommy. Daddy.
Watch me.
We're watching, darling.
You're mighty pretty, precious.
So are you.
I'm going to jump. Watch me, Daddy.
I don't think you ought to do much jumping yet, Bonnie.
Remember, you've just learned to ride sidesaddle.
I will so jump.
I can jump better than ever 'cause I've grown
and I've moved the bar higher.
Don't let her do it, Rhett.
No, Bonnie, you can't. Well, if you fall off, don't cry and blame me.
Rhett, stop her.
Bonnie.
Just like Pa.
Lordsy, Miss Melly. I sure is glad you has come.
This house won't seem the same without Bonnie.
How's Miss Scarlett bearing up?
Miss Melly, this here done broke her heart
but I didn't fetch you here on Miss Scarlett's account.
What that child got to stand, the good Lord give her strength to stand.
It's Mr. Rhett I's worried about.
He done lost his mind these last couple of days.
No, Mammy, no.
I ain't never see'd no man, black or white, set such store on any child.
When Dr. Meade says her neck broke
Mr. Rhett grab his gun and run out there and shoot that poor pony
and for a minute I think he going to shoot hisself.
Oh, poor Captain Butler.
Yes, ma'am. Miss Scarlett, she call him a murderer for teachin' that child to jump.
She say, You give me my baby what you kill.
And then he say Miss Scarlett ain't never cared nothin' about Miss Bonnie.
It like to turn my blood cold, the things they say to one another.
Stop, Mammy, don't tell me any more.
And then that night
Mr. Rhett, he locked hisseIf in the nursery with Miss Bonnie
and he wouldn't even open the door
when Miss Scarlett beat on it and hollered to him.
And that's the way it's been for two whole days.
Oh, Mammy.
And then this evenin', Miss Scarlett, she shout through the door
and she say the funeral set for tomorrow mornin'
and he says You try that and I kills you tomorrow.
Do you think I's goin' to put my child away in the
in the dark when she's so scared of it?
Oh, Mammy, he has lost his mind.
Yes, ma'am, that's the God's truth. He ain't goin' to let us bury that child.
You gotta help us, Miss Melly.
Oh, but I can't intrude.
If you can't help us, who can?
Mr. Rhett always set great store by your opinion.
Please, Miss Melly.
I'll do what I can, Mammy.
Get away from that door, and leave us alone.
It's Mrs. Wilkes, Captain Butler.
Please let me in.
I've come to see Bonnie.
Oh, Lord
please help Mr. Rhett in this hour of his grief.
I want you to go and make a good deal of strong coffee
and bring it up to Captain Butler. I'll go and see Miss Scarlett.
But.
Captain Butler is quite willing for the funeral to take place
tomorrow morning.
Hallelujah. I suspects the angeIs fights on your side, Miss Melly. Hallelujah.
Miss Melly. Miss Melly.
Miss Melly.
Send for Dr. Meade, Mammy
and try
try to get me home.
Miss Melly. Miss Melly.
Where is my mother goin' away to?
And why can't I go along, please?
We can't always go along, Beau, much as we may want to.
You're going back to bed now.
Oh, Rhett, she can't be dying, she can't be.
She hasn't your strength.
She's never had any strength. She's never had anything but heart.
You knew that, too.
Why do I have to go back to bed? It's morning.
It isn't really morning yet.
You may come in now, Scarlett.
Dr. Meade, please let me see her.
I've been waiting here two whole days and I've got to tell her
that I was wrong about something.
She knows you were wrong. She wants to see Scarlett.
Miss Melly's going to die in peace.
I won't have you easing your conscience telling her things
that make no difference now. You understand?
It's me, Melly.
Promise me?
Anything.
Look after my little son.
I gave him to you once before.
Remember?
The day he was born.
Please, Melly, don't talk this way. I know you'll get well.
Promise me
college.
Yes, yes, and Europe, and a pony, whatever he wants. But
Melly, do try.
Ashley.
Ashley and you.
What about Ashley, Melly?
Look after him for me.
Just as you
looked after me for him.
I will, Melly.
Look after him
but never let him know.
Good night.
Promise?
What else, Melly?
Captain Butler
be kind to him.
Rhett?
He loves you so.
Yes, Melly.
Goodbye.
You ladies may come in now.
Ashley.
I don't know where the mate to this is.
She must have put it away.
Oh, stop it.
Hold me.
I'm so frightened.
Oh, Scarlett, what can I do? I can't live without her, I can't.
Everything I ever had is
is going with her.
Oh, Ashley.
You really love her, don't you?
She's the only dream I ever had that didn't die in the face of reality.
Dreams. Always dreams with you, never common sense.
Oh, Scarlett. If you knew what I've gone through.
Ashley, you should have told me years ago that you loved her and not me
and not left me dangling with your talk of honor.
But you had to wait till now, now when Melly's dying
to show me that I could never mean any more to you than
than this Watling woman does to Rhett.
And I've loved something that
that doesn't really exist.
Somehow
I don't care.
Somehow it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter one bit.
Ashley, forgive me.
Don't cry. She mustn't see you've been crying.
Ashley.
Melly.
Rhett, Rhett.
Rhett, where are you?
Rhett, wait for me.
Rhett.
Come in.
Melanie, she's.
Well, God rest her.
She was the only completely kind person I ever knew.
A great lady.
A very great lady.
So she's dead. That makes it nice for you, doesn't it?
Oh, how can you say such a thing? You know how I loved her, really.
No, I don't know that I do.
But at least it's to your credit that you could appreciate her at the end.
Of course I appreciated her. She thought of everybody except herself.
Why her last words were about you.
What did she say?
She said
Be kind to Captain Butler. He loves you so.
Did she say anything else?
She said
she asked me to look after Ashley, too.
It's convenient to have the first wife's permission, isn't it?
What do you mean?
What are you doing?
I'm leaving you, my dear.
All you need now is a divorce, and your dreams of Ashley can come true.
Oh, no.
No, you're wrong. Terribly wrong.
I don't want a divorce. Oh, Rhett, when I knew tonight
when I knew I loved you, I ran home to tell you.
Oh, darling, darling.
Please don't go on with this.
Leave us some dignity to remember out of our marriage. Spare us this last.
This last?
Oh, Rhett, do listen to me.
I must have loved you for years, only I was such a stupid fool I didn't know it.
Please believe me. You must care.
Melly said you did.
I believe you. What about Ashley Wilkes?
I never really loved Ashley.
You certainly gave a good imitation of it, up till this morning.
No, Scarlett. I tried everything.
If you'd only met me haIf way, even when I came back from London.
I was so glad to see you. I was, Rhett, but you were so nasty.
And then, when you were sick and it was all my fault
I hoped against hope that you'd call for me, but you didn't.
I wanted you. I wanted you desperately, but I didn't think you wanted me.
It seems we've been at cross purposes, doesn't it? But it's no use now.
As long as there was Bonnie, there was a chance we might be happy.
I liked to think that Bonnie was you.
A little girl again, before the war, and poverty had done things to you.
She was so like you, and I could pet her, and spoil her, as I wanted to spoil you.
But when she went, she took everything.
Oh, Rhett.
Rhett, please don't say that.
I'm so sorry, I'm so sorry for everything.
My darling, you're such a child.
You think that by saying, I'm sorry,  all the past can be corrected.
Here, take my handkerchief.
Never, at any crisis of your life, have I known you to have a handkerchief.
Rhett, where are you going?
I'm going to Charleston. Back where I belong.
Please. Please take me with you.
No. I'm through with everything here.
I want peace.
I want to see if somewhere there isn't something left in life of charm and grace.
Do you know what I'm talking about? No. I only know that I love you.
That's your misfortune.
Oh, Rhett.
Rhett.
If you go, where shall I go? What shall I do?
Frankly, my dear, I don't give a damn.
Oh, I can't let him go. I can't.
There must be some way to bring him back.
I can't think about it now. I'll go crazy if I do.
I'll think about it tomorrow.
But I must think about it.
I must think about it.
What is there to do?
What is there that matters?
Do you mean to tell me, Katie Scarlett O'Hara
that Tara doesn't mean anything to you? Why, land's the only thing that matters.
It's the only thing that lasts.
Something you love better than me, though you may not know it. Tara.
It's this from which you get your strength. The red earth of Tara.
Why, land's the only thing that matters. It's the only thing that lasts.
Something you love better than me, though you may not know it. Tara.
This from which you get your strength. The red earth of Tara.
Why, land's the only thing that matters.
Something you love better than me.
The red earth of Tara.
Tara. Tara.
Tara.
Home.
I'll go home.
And I'll think of some way to get him back.
After all, tomorrow is another day.
这里曾是骑士和棉花的土地称为老南方
在这个美丽的世界里骑士之风 以成为过去
骑士和他们的淑女
庄园主和奴隶
在这里最后一次出现
只有在书中才能见到
如今只是梦的追忆
一代文明 随风飘逝
我们才不在乎被学校开除呢
就要打仗了反正我们得离开学校
哦战争  多让人激动啊
那些穷北佬真要打仗啊?
让他们看看讨厌
战争  战争  战争
这个春天里每次聚会都要谈论战争
我烦得都要喊出来了
再说 不会有战争的你说不会有战争?
不会? 亲爱的真的要打仗了
你们谁要是再说一句战争我就进屋去把门关上
可是斯卡莉特 亲爱的 你不要我们打仗吗?
好吧
别忘了
我警告过你们
那谈谈我们明天到
十二棵橡树卫尔科斯家的野餐会吧
好主意和我们一起去野餐好吗?
哦 我还没想过呢  我明天再说吧
和我们跳华尔滋
先跟他 再跟我再跟他 再跟我
就这样答应了好倒是好 哦 太好了  不过
那得要我没答应跟别人跳舞
怎么 亲爱的 你不能这样对我们
我想告诉你一个秘密? 秘密? 谁的?
亚特兰大的梅兰妮・韩密尔敦小姐?
艾希礼的表妹 她要到十二棵橡树卫尔科斯家
梅兰妮・韩密尔敦那个假正经 谁要听她的秘密
可是我们听说 他们
艾希礼要和她结婚了你知道他们家的人 通常是表亲之间通婚的
我们可以跳华尔滋了吧?
当然了
我敢说别的小伙子都要气疯了让他们气去吧  我们俩可以应付
这不可能  艾希礼爱我
斯卡莉
我们怎么惹着她了?
我们说错了什么让她生气了?
斯卡莉小姐你出去也不围上披肩晚上天凉了
你为什么不留先生们吃晚饭?
你这样就象一个乡下姑娘
爱伦小姐没功夫像我这么管你
快进屋来
再不进来就要着凉了
不  我要去等爸爸从威尔克斯家回来
快回来
回来
收工了
谁说收工了?
我说收工了
我是头 在泰拉庄园什么时候收工 得我说
收工了
哦 在这个郡整个州里没有能比得过你的
爸爸
现在你又感到骄傲了
啊 郝斯卡莉
你在监视我像你妹妹修伦那样
去告诉你妈妈说我又跳栏杆了
爸爸 我可不像修伦那样爱告状 可我觉得
自从去年你跳这个栏杆摔伤膝盖以后
我可不需要自己的女儿告诉我该不该跳
那是我自己的脖子
爸爸 你喜欢跳就跳吧十二橡树那儿怎么样了?
威尔克斯家?
他们正准备明天的野餐会无非是谈论战争
讨厌的战争 那儿还有什么人吗?
哦 梅兰妮和她弟弟卡尔斯从亚特兰大来了
梅兰妮
脸色苍白 说话好 转弯抹角 我讨厌她
艾希礼可不这么认为
艾希礼不会喜欢象她那样的人
你怎么对他们那么感兴趣?
没什么 我们回家吧 爸爸
他跟你胡说过什么吗? 还是向你求过婚?
没有 没有啊他不会的
今天下午我听约翰・卫克斯说
艾希礼要和梅兰妮小姐结婚
在明天的舞会上宣布
我不相信
回来  你要到哪儿去?
斯卡莉
你怎么了?
你要为追一个并不爱你的男人
而丢脸吗?
我并没有追他 只是 我只是觉得很奇怪
你别吞吞吐吐的
如果艾希礼想要娶你 我即使答应了也担心
我愿意我孩子幸福 你跟着他不会幸福的
我会的 我会的
你嫁给谁都可以
只要他是个南方人和你情投意和
等我死了以后把泰拉庄园留给你
我不要泰拉庄园 种植园对我毫无意义
你是说 斯卡莉土地对你毫无意义?
世界上只有土地才值得为它耕耘
为它战斗 为它去死因为只有它 才是永恒的
爸 你说话真像个爱尔兰人我为我是爱尔兰人而感到自豪
你别忘了 小姐你也是半个爱尔兰人
任何人身上那怕只有一滴爱尔兰人的血
就会把他们生存的土地当作母亲
可是你还是个孩子你将来会爱土地的
只要你是爱尔兰人就会的
她回来了
你们的妈妈回来了
她去照看那个下流的白种人
连晚饭都顾不得吃拿点心来 把火挑起来
爱伦小姐干什么这么累波 克是 墨利
把蜡烛拿到走廊上她累坏了
先生 爱伦小姐回来了
她把自己累坏了
狗别叫了
起来 孩子 你没听见爱伦小姐回来了吗?
去给她拿药箱
我们正着急呢 爱伦小姐
杰纳尔先生 没事 波克 我不是回来了吗
欧郝纳太太 今天已经耕完了那块洼地了
明天你要我干什么?
威克尔森先生我刚从挨米施爱特那儿来
你的孩子以经出生了
我的孩子? 哦 我真的不明白
以经出生了 还好 以经死了
晚安 威克尔森先生
我去为你准备晚饭
先等我祈祷 妈蜜
哦 是的
欧郝呐先生
你必须辞掉乔拉・斯威克森
嗯 辞退他? 他是这个郡里最好的监工
明天早上就让他走
哦 可是
是吗? 是的
这个北方佬和那个下流女孩斯奈特利
过一会再谈吧
好吧 欧郝纳太太
妈妈 我要穿斯卡莉的绿衣服
休伦 你的那件粉红色长裙可漂亮了
我为什么不能参加明天晚上的舞会呢? 不过你可以戴我的石榴石项链
我为什么不能参加明天晚上的舞会?
斯卡莉
你显得很累 亲爱的我有点担心
我很好 妈妈
为什么我不能参加明天晚上的舞会?
我已经13岁了
你可以去野餐一直到吃晚饭
我不穿你的破绿裙子了小气鬼
少废话
祈祷了  孩子们
对所有圣人而言 我在思想言语及行为上犯罪太多
为了我的过错
为了我的过错为了我最严重的过错
在此我向永远的处子圣母码利亚祈求
神圣的麦克天使长
神圣的施洗者约翰
圣徒彼得与保罗
以及所有圣人们祈求上帝保佑我
艾希礼不知道我爱他
我告诉他 我爱他那他就不会娶她了
愿万能仁慈的上帝
原谅我们 赦免
并宽恕我们的罪行 阿们
啊哦 别动 吸气
奶妈 斯卡莉小姐的点心
都拿回橱房去  我一点儿也不想吃
哦 你得吃
你要大口大口的吃
不  我不吃
快给我穿衣服我们已经晚了
你要穿哪一件? 那件
不行 3点钟以前是不能穿露胸的衣服的
我要去告诉你妈妈
你要是敢告诉妈妈一个字我一口也不吃
好吧
你 要把披肩披上 我可不想让你再长一身小疙瘩
去年一个冬天都用牛奶给你擦才擦好的
斯卡莉小姐 乖乖地听话吃一点吧 宝贝
不
我今天要好好的玩一天在野餐会上吃
你难道不怕别人笑话你们家
我告诉你多少次了
小姐在人面前吃东西要像小鸟似的
你这次去艾希礼先生家
不能象庄稼人那样吃象只大老鹰
胡说什么
艾希礼・卫尔克斯跟我说过他喜欢女孩的胃口好
男人们嘴里这么说心理可不这么想
我看得出来艾希礼先生没想娶你
喔 别吃得太快不然你又会吐出来了
女孩子为什么那么傻非得找个丈夫
斯卡莉・欧郝钠 如果我数到10 你还没下来 我们就不等你了
我来了 爸爸
一
二  三
四  五  六
哦 天呐
我的衣服这么紧这一天我都得打嗝了
十二橡树园 卫约翰警告
任何擅闯本农P者都将遭到起诉
哦 您好
卫约翰 今天的野餐会一定很热闹
是的 杰拉尔德欧郝纳太太没有一起来?
她和监工结算帐目呢
晚上要来参加舞会
欢迎到十二橡树来欧郝纳先生
谢谢你 英蒂雅
你的女儿越长越漂亮了 约翰
英蒂雅 你去招呼一下欧郝纳家的姑娘
我受不了斯卡莉看她讨好艾希礼的那副样子
好了 那是你哥哥的事
记住你的责任是当好女主人
早上好 姑娘们
早上好 您好 斯卡莉
英蒂雅 你的衣服真漂亮
太美了 亲爱的我的眼睛都离不开它了
喔  斯卡莉小姐 早上好
你看起来真漂亮 斯卡莉小姐早上好  嗨
早上好  你好
见到你真荣幸
看到你真是太高兴了
艾希礼
斯卡莉 亲爱的
我各处找你
我有点事想跟你说
你能找个辟静的地方吗? 好的 我愿意陪你
不过我也有件事想告诉你
我希望 我希望你听了会高兴
先跟我表妹打个招呼好吗
哦 有这个必要吗?
她正在等着 见见你呢
梅兰妮
斯卡莉在这儿
斯卡莉
又见到你 我真高兴
梅兰妮・韩蜜尔敦没想到在这儿见到你
希望你在这儿能跟我们多呆几天
我希望我们常在一起成为好朋友
我真希望这样
我们把她留下来好吗? 斯卡莉
喔  那我们得让她玩得高兴是不是 艾希礼?
艾希礼最会哄女孩子高兴了
所以我认为我们开玩笑你会看不惯因为你很严肃
斯卡莉 你是这么活泼
我非常羡慕你
我真希望能像你一点儿
你可别恭维我 梅兰妮没这么想就别这么说
没有人能说梅兰妮是不真诚的是吧? 亲爱的
喔  那她可不像你了是吗?
艾希礼从来没有对女孩子说过实话
哦 卡尔斯・韩蜜尔敦漂亮的老家伙
喔 欧郝纳小姐
你把你的漂亮兄弟带到这儿来
是为了伤我这可怜的 单纯的乡村姑娘的心吗?
看 斯卡莉 以前她从没理过卡尔斯
现在因为他是你的男朋友 她就盯上他了
卡尔斯・韩蜜尔敦 我要跟你一起吃野餐
你可不要跟别的女孩子调情 我要忌妒的
我不会的 欧郝纳小姐
我不会的
弗兰克・肯尼迪 你留着胡子
看起来更漂亮了
谢谢 谢谢你斯卡莉小姐
恰尔斯跟卡尔斯特邀请我一起吃野餐
我告诉他们 我答应你了
别觉得可笑了 你看她又盯上你的男朋友了
真让我受宠若惊了 斯卡莉小姐
我愿意为你效劳 斯卡莉小姐
你妹妹为什么生气啊? 你勾引她的男朋友了?
好像我找不到比他更好的了
伯伦特 史托尔特 亲爱的俩个漂亮小伙子
我不是说你们 我在生你们的气呢
为什么? 斯卡莉 我们怎么了?
你们一整天都没有接近我 我穿这件旧衣服
就因为你们喜欢
我准备和你们一起吃野餐呢
太好了 斯卡莉 当然了 亲爱的
我还没有想好你们俩个谁更漂亮
我昨天晚上整整想了一夜
喔 对不起
凯沙林 那个人是谁?
谁?
盯着我们看还笑的那个人
长得挺黑的讨厌的人
啊  你不认识他? 他是瑞德・巴得勒 是查尔斯人
他的名声很坏
他的目光好象要透过我的内衣
斯卡莉
他是不受欢迎的
他大部分时间要到北方度过
因为查斯特人都不愿意理他
他被西点军校给开除了 他的生活放荡
他和一个女孩子有事又没有娶她
说  快说啊
天都黑了 他把她一个人带上了一辆马车
没带监护人然后 他又不肯娶她
没有  可她的名声破坏了
艾希礼
高兴吗?
非常高兴
你似乎就应该属于这里
好像一切都是为你而设计好的
我愿意让我属于你所爱的一切
你跟我一样爱十二橡树
是的 艾希礼
我爱它
不仅是这所房子
这里有人世间最美好最优雅的一切
不知道它会不会永远是这样
梅兰妮
你担心战争暴发了怎么办 是吗?
我们不用害怕 不用
任何战争都不会进入我们俩的世界
无论发生什么事
我都像现在 一样爱你
只到死
那好 在餐桌上只能
一边有一个男伴
我去给她拿甜食
她说让我去的  欧郝纳小姐
我想想
让卡尔斯・韩密尔敦去拿吧
谢谢你 欧郝纳小姐
谢谢
快去吧  快啊
他真是太幸运了  真高兴啊
欧郝纳小姐
我 我爱你
我 我觉得一点儿也不饿呢
为什么非要睡午觉? 我并不累
有教养的姑娘都要睡午觉的
在这时候你的行为和举止都要像爱伦小姐的女儿
我们在萨拉托卡的时候我没看见过北方女孩子睡午觉
今天晚上的舞会可没有北方姑娘
艾希礼今天是怎么那? 斯卡莉
他好像没注意你
你少管闲事
但愿你能保住那个肯尼迪就不错了
你一直对艾希礼有意
今天晚上他就要宣讯┗榱
全都知道
斯卡莉小姐 休伦小姐注意点举止
别像没教养的女孩子
要象上等人那样去参加宴会
我不在乎
不要浪费光阴生命即是由时间所构成
我们受够了北方佬的侮辱
现在该让他们明白我们要保留奴隶
用不着他们批准
退出联邦是乔治亚州的权力
闭嘴
南方要用武力来维护自己
我们在沙摩特要塞向北方流氓开火以后我们就必需打了
没有别的选择战斗  对  战斗
让北方佬向我们求和对
情况非常简单 北方佬不会打仗而我们会
甚至不用交火
他们只会转身逃跑
1个南方人可以消灭20个北方佬
一次战斗就就可以把他们消灭光
绅士总比暴徒能战斗
对  绅士总比暴徒能战斗
让我们这里的队长说说吧?
如果左治亚州要打 我也会参加 不过象我的父亲那样
我希望北方能够让我们和平地脱离联邦
可是艾希礼 他们侮辱了我们
你是不愿意打仗吗?
世界上许多不辛的事都是由于战争
可是等战争结束以后没有人知道为什么要打
艾希礼 艾希礼 要不是我了解你
好了  好了 先生们听说巴特勒先生到过北方
你同意我们说的吗?
我想只可以说是打不胜的 先生们
你这是什么意思? 先生
我是说整个南方没有一座制造大炮的工厂
这对于一个绅士来说又有什么关系?
恐怕这对于很多绅士都有很大的关系 先生
你在暗示他们会打垮我们? 是吗?
不 我没有
我是明确地说北方佬的装备比我们好
他们有工厂 造船厂和煤矿
有舰队封锁我们的港口会把我们困死
而我们有的只是棉花 奴隶和狂望
替北方佬说话我拒绝听背叛的话
很抱歉 我的实话冒犯了您
道歉是不够的
听说你是被西点军校开除的 先生
查尔斯屯的任何正派的家庭都不欢迎你 甚至自己家
我再次为我所有的缺点道歉
卫尔科斯先生你不介意我各处走走
看看你的庄园吧我好像破坏了各位的美酒 雪茄
和胜利的美梦
象巴特勒这样的人 还能指望他做出什么来吗
就差把你叫出去了
他不敢决斗
不是那样的 卡尔斯他只是不想捉弄你
捉弄我 ?
是的 他是这里最好的射手了
战胜过不少
手比你稳头脑比你冷静的人
我要让他看看
好了  好了  别去找他的麻烦了
有更重要的战斗需要你 卡尔斯
巴特勒先生是我们的客人
我去陪他走走
艾希礼
斯卡莉
你在这儿躲谁呢?
你要干什么?
为什么不跟女孩子在楼上休息呢?
怎么那? 斯卡莉? 有什么秘密?
艾希礼 艾希礼
我爱你
斯卡莉
我爱你 真的
你今天把所有男人的心都收走了 还不够吗?
我心里一直有你这你是知道的
喔 别开玩笑了
你的心给我了吗? 亲爱的我爱你 我爱你
你别再说这些了 你听了我的话会恨我的
永远不会恨你我知道你喜欢我
你是喜欢我 对吗?
是的
我喜欢
让我们离开吧忘掉所说的这些
我们怎么能这样?
你 你不想跟我结婚吗?
我要跟梅兰妮结婚了
你不能 如果你喜欢我
为什么一定要我说出让你难过的话呢?
我怎么才能让你明白呢?
你太年青 缺乏思想
你不知道结婚意着什么
我就知道我爱你 我要做你的妻子
你并不爱梅兰妮
她和我一样 斯卡莉
我们有血缘关系而且彼此彼此了解
可你爱我呀
我怎么能不爱呢?
你对生活充满热情我却缺少这些
可是象我们这样性格不同的人
是不会有美满的婚姻的
你为什么不说? 胆小鬼你不敢娶我
你宁愿和那个小傻瓜一起生活
她只会说是或不是再给你生出那些象她那样笨的小崽子来
你不应该这样说梅兰妮
你是谁? 敢教训我该不该说?
是你让我相信你会和我结婚的
好了斯卡莉 要公平一点  我从来没有
就是 就是我要恨你一辈子
我想不出用什么话来骂你 才出气
战争暴发了?
先生 你应该让人知道你在这儿
打断美妙的爱情场景?
那太不明智了吧?
别担心 我会保守秘密的
先生 你不太象是个绅士
小姐 你也不象是个淑女
别认为我会要胁你
淑女对我没有一点吸引力
先偷听了我说的话然后再来羞辱我
我对你充满敬意
我希望等到你不再迷恋那位温雅的卫尔克斯先生时再见到你
我看他配不上你这样的 怎么说的呢
充满热情的姑娘
你敢这么说你给他擦靴子都不配
可是你还要恨他一辈子呢
她可真行啊把野餐会上的每个男人都追到了
别这么说 英蒂雅
她太迷人男人们自然都围着她转
梅兰妮 你真是太好了
你没看见她追你弟弟 卡尔斯吗?
而且她知卡尔斯跟我好
你想错了 英蒂雅
斯卡莉只不过是很活跃罢了
男人只能拿这样的女人开开心 而不会娶她的
你这话说得太刻薄点了
打仗了  打仗了  要打仗了
欧郝纳小姐
真让人激动 林肯先生召募自愿军
和我们作战胡说什么 你们男人就没有别的重要的事吗?
可这是战争每个人都要入伍了
立刻就走 我也去
每个人?
欧郝纳小姐 看到我们走
你会难过吧
我每天都会把枕头哭湿的
欧郝纳小姐 我说过我爱你
你是世上最美 最甜的 最可爱的姑娘
我知道我不指望你爱我
我这么笨这么傻根本配不上你
可如果你考虑嫁给我 我愿意为你做
世界上任何事 我保证
你 你在说什么?
欧郝纳小姐 你愿意嫁我吗?
好吧 韩密尔敦先生我愿意
你愿意? 愿意嫁我你愿意等我?
我 我不想再等了
在我走以前 和我结婚?
欧郝纳小姐
太好了
我什么时候和你父亲说?
越快越好
好吧 我这就去我不能等了
请原谅 亲爱的
欧郝纳先生
我们至少还有1星期的时间
只有1星期 他们就要把你招走了
梅兰妮
斯卡莉 在我们昨天的婚礼上
我就希望你的婚礼也一样隆重
是吗?
现在我们真正成了姐妹了
卡尔斯 梅兰妮
亲爱的 别哭战争几个星期就会结束
我又会回到你的身边
虽然韩密尔敦上尉不是壮烈的战死在沙场
但仍无愧为一位英雄
他死于麻疹并发肺炎
夫人 我是非常尊敬您的
您忠实的仆人威德・韩密尔敦上尉
斯卡莉小姐
我不在乎我这么年轻就成为寡妇
我 我这个样子怎么见人那?
你不能到外面去 你穿着丧服呢
为什么? 我并不难过
为什么要我装呢?
怎么了?
喔 宝贝
怎么那?
我的一切都完了
我没什么指望了
妈妈
我一定认为我太不象话了可我不能穿着黑衣服各处走
不但不能参加任何舞会
还要这副样子
我并没有觉得你不象话
这很自然 你还年轻当然喜欢漂亮了
好了 宝贝
你到外面去走走? 怎么样
去沙凡摩 好吗?
我去沙凡摩干什么?
那就 去亚特兰大
那儿有很多事情可以做
可以和梅兰妮和她的碧蒂姑妈在一起
梅兰妮
对
对 可以吗
喔 妈妈 你对我太好了比任何人都好
你愿意了 真的
那好吧  那就别哭了  笑一笑
你可以带碧西一起去
给斯卡莉小姐收拾行李 奶妈
我去写封信
亚特兰大
你还是去沙凡摩好你在亚特兰大会有麻烦的
你说有什么麻烦?
你知道是什么麻烦我说的是卫尔克斯先生
他一休假就要回到亚特兰大
你就会像蜘蛛一样在那里等着他
他是属于梅兰妮小姐的 照妈妈说的给我收拾行理
人们都在议论我知道准是说她
爱说就让他们说去吧碧蒂姑妈
可斯卡莉住在我家人们知道我该为她负责
一个寡妇在公共场合出头露面
我一想起这些 就要晕了
碧蒂姑妈 斯卡莉来这儿是为了义卖筹款帮忙的
对于她来说 已经作出牺牲了
别人要是听见你这么说
还以为她来这儿是为了跳舞呢
女士们 先生们
有重要的消息  特大的喜讯
我们的勇士们又取得了重大地胜利
李将军彻底打败了敌人
把北方的军队从佛尔吉尼亚赶回北方去了
现在报告大家一个令人惊喜的消息
今晚上 我们中间有一位最勇敢的 穿越封锁线的人
他的船只 冒着北方佬的枪林弹雨
给我们运来了今天晚上大家穿的丝毛衣料
女士们 先生们 我说的这位
不是别人 他就是我们的朋友
查尔斯敦的瑞德・巴特勒船长
啊 请允许我
巴特勒船长 能见到你非常荣幸
上次在我丈夫家里见过面
很荣幸你还记得我卫尔克斯太太
在十二颗橡树见过巴特勒船长吗? 斯卡莉
是的 我 我见过
只见了一会儿 韩密尔敦太太是在书房里
你是打碎了什么东西
是的 巴特勒船长 我记得你
女士们 请求你们捐献珠宝支援我们崇高的事业
我们没戴首饰 我在戴孝
等一下
替卫尔克斯太太和韩密尔敦太太捐的
谢谢你 巴特勒船长
请等一下
这是您的结婚戒指 太太
这可能 对我丈夫会有所帮助
谢谢
这真是一个崇高的举动卫尔克斯太太
给
我的也给你  为了事业
可是你 韩密尔敦太太我知道它对你有多大的意义
梅兰妮什么? 米特大夫
我要做一件惊人的事情
你作为委员会的成员我需要你的同意
请原谅  我们去一下
我说一件事 战争造成了最奇特的寡妇
我希望你走开
你应该知道我不想再见到你
别这么傻了?
你没有理由恨我我会把你的秘密带到坟墓里去的
我怎么能恨你这样一位战争中的大英雄呢?
我很奇怪 你怎么会成为一个品德高尚的人呢?
我不能欺骗你这样一个小女孩 欧郝纳小姐
我既不高尚 也不是英雄
可你穿过封锁线那?
为了利益 只是为了利益
你是说 你不相信什么理想?
我只相信瑞德・巴特勒他是我唯一的理想
别的对我毫无意义
女士们先生们
我有一个惊人的提议为了给医院募捐
先生们 如果你们想选哪位女士做你的舞伴
就请出个价钱
卡沃尔米达 你怎么允许你丈夫这么做呢?
就象拍卖奴隶
多莉・梅丽瑞你怎么能批评我呢?
梅兰妮告诉过大夫
只要是为了崇高的理想这没有什么不对的
她这么说?
天啊  天啊  我的嗅盐在哪儿?
我要晕倒了
你别晕 碧蒂・韩密尔敦
梅兰妮说没什么 就没什么
来吧 先生们 你们出什么价? 说吧?
别不好意思 先生们
我出20元请美贝尔・梅丽贝丝小姐
我出25元请芬妮小姐
只出到25元就
我出150元金币
请哪位小姐? 先生
请卡尔斯・韩密尔敦太太
请谁? 先生
卡尔斯・韩密尔敦太太
韩密尔敦太太在戴孝期间
不过我们亚特兰大每位美女们都会感到骄傲的
米格大夫 我是说恰尔斯・韩密尔敦太太
她不会考虑的 先生
喔 我愿意
舞会开始了 请选好舞伴
我们震惊了南方邦联 太太
这有点像穿过封锁线是不是?
比这更糟
不过我期望从中得到更多
我不管你期望什么他们怎么想
我就是要跳舞
今天晚上就是跟林肯跳舞我也不在乎
再跳一支舞我就名誉扫地了
如果你有足够的勇气就不用管什么名誉
我不爱听你这么说
你的华尔兹跳得真神了巴特勒船长
别给我卖弄风情我可不象葛米雅那些追求你的人
我只想得到更多
你想要什么?
告诉你 斯卡莉・欧郝纳你脸上不要装成南方美人的那种假笑
有一天我要你对我说
你跟艾希礼说过的话
我爱你
你一辈子也不会听到这话巴特勒船长 永远听不到
亲爱的卫尔科斯太太
南方联邦可能需要男人们的鲜血
但不需要妇女心中的血
我已赎回了您的戒指现在把它退还给您
等我从巴黎回来将要登门拜访
亲自向您这位伟大女性的勇气
和奉献精神表示敬意瑞德・巴特勒
我也把韩密尔敦太太的戒指附上
他心肠多好啊真是一位有心人别胡说了 他为什么一句也不提我的奉献精神?
喔 喔  太可爱了
瑞德 真是太漂亮了
你不会真的是从巴黎专门给我买的吧?
是的 我是想让你别在穿这虚伪的丧服了
下一次我给你带一块绿丝绸做衣服配这顶帽子
喔 瑞德
让在家的女孩子们打扮得漂漂亮亮是对我们前方勇士应尽的责任
我好长时间没有新东西了
你看怎么样?
难看  太难看了
喔 怎么了?
战争弄得你这样的女孩子
都不知道时装该怎么穿戴了
瑞德 我自己来吧
可是瑞德 我还不知道自己敢不敢戴出去
你会的
奥 还有 你这条长裤
现在巴黎还有那个女人穿长裤
那穿什么?
你不该跟我说这种事
哼  小伪君子你不在乎 我知道
只是不要说出来
瑞德 我不能再接受你的礼物了 虽然你是一片好心
不是好心 是诱惑你
我送东西从来是指望回报的 我总是得到了
我不会因为你送我一顶帽子就嫁给
你别抬高自己了 我是不结婚的人
我也不会为它和你接吻那
睁开眼睛看着我
不 我不想吻你
尽管你非常需要人吻你
毛病就在这儿
你需要经常被人家吻 被会亲吻的人去吻
我看 你以为你就是那个人
可能吗? 如果那个时刻到来的话
你是一个自负的 黑心肠的家伙 瑞德
我为什么会让你来看我
我来告诉你为什么
因为我是这儿唯一能让你高兴
的16岁到60岁的男人了
高兴点吧 仗不会打多久了
真的? 瑞德 为什么?
现在正在进行着一场小的战斗
无疑是 决定性的
瑞德 艾希礼参加了吗?
你还在想着那个木头脑袋的卫尔克斯先生?
是的 我想他也参加了
告诉我 瑞德 他在哪儿?
在宾西法尼亚洲的一个小镇 叫葛里茨堡
沉静而严峻
亚特兰大将痛苦的目光
投向远方的小镇
葛里茨堡
历史上新的一页
正等待三天来
在宾西法尼亚洲的田野上
所进行的一场
殊死决战
阵亡名单
给你 梅兰妮小姐
他们都在抢所以把它撕成两半了
斯卡莉你看 W字头的在末尾
威尔曼 温岱尔怀特 辉特 威尔金
威廉士伍喜 俄克纳
斯卡莉 俄克纳已经过了他了
没在里面
他没在里面
艾希礼还平安
他还平安  他还平安
喔 斯卡莉 你真好替我为艾希礼担心
我要去看看她
别在这儿哭了 亲爱的
我们回家吧
米格大夫 你们
是的 我们的儿子达尔西
我正在给他织手套呢
现在用不上了
妈妈  我要去参军我要把所有的北方佬都杀死
德米特 别说了
你去了再被打死你妈妈可怎么办?
别说傻话了
真是凄惨的一天 你没听到什么坏消息吧?
艾希礼还平安
我为卫尔克斯太太高兴
可是很多人阵亡了
你的朋友呢?
几乎每个家庭都有 玖泰克兄弟两个
是这样  看看他们看看这些可怜的人们
南方算是垮了 再也站不起来了
过去的
生活的理想正在我们面前破裂
我以前没听你这样说过
我很气愤  浪费使我气愤 所有这一切纯粹是浪费
不过你不用伤心
艾希礼・威尔克斯还活着会回到爱他的女人家里
两个女人
为了奖励斯克拂军团
的艾希礼・威尔克斯上校
在宾西法尼亚战役中所做的贡献
特准许圣诞节休假三天
你回来了
你回来了 你真的回来了
我等了那么久
梅兰妮  我亲爱的妻子
喔 我们 我们把斯卡莉给忘了
斯卡莉 亲爱的
你就这样来迎接一个回来的战士吗?
艾希礼 我
耶诞快乐 艾希礼
来吧 老先生你别跑啊
我们已经把你的老伴给吃了
把你的小鸡也给吃了
已经没什么牵挂了
来呀 还留着你就是为了作耶诞晚餐的
别跑
听说你是亚特兰大
最后一只鸡
喔  别再说战争了现在是耶诞节
让我们谈点十二橡树呀 泰拉庄园呀 和战前的事吧
我们喝点酒好吗? 碧蒂姑妈
你怎么说酒不够了呢? 彼得大叔
还有不少呢  这是以前我父亲存的酒
还是他的叔叔 威尔・韩密尔敦海军上将
他也是和表妹结婚的 和威尔卡斯家也是表亲
我一直留着它等艾希礼回来过圣诞节的
你们可以喝不过可别喝光了
因为这是最后一瓶啦很珍贵的
太好啦 亲爱的 这真是一件可爱的耶诞礼物
现在 只有将军才能有这样的上衣
你喜欢我真高兴
你哪儿来的布料?
查尔斯屯一位太太送给我的
我们在医院里看护过她儿子 后来他死啦
你要爱惜它
别把它弄破啦
答应我
放心吧
我一定把它完整的穿回来 我保证
晚安 亲爱的
晚安 斯卡莉
时间到啦 彼得大叔艾希礼先生该走啦?
马上要走啦斯卡莉小姐
梅兰妮不送他到车站吗? 她没改变主意吗?
没有小姐 她躺着呢
她整个心烦意乱卫尔克斯先生不让她下楼啦
艾希礼
艾希礼让我送你去车站
我宁愿记着 你现在这样
也不愿看见 在车站发抖
好吧
喔 艾希礼 我也有一件东西送你
斯卡莉 真漂亮
快给我系上 亲爱的
梅兰妮给你做新衣服的时候
你亲手做的?
这我太有价值啦
你知道 我为你做什么都可以
有件事你能替我做吗?
什么事?
你愿意替我照顾梅兰妮吗?
她是那么地脆弱 那么地文静
如果我死啦以后
奥 别说啦 不吉利赶快祈祷吧
你替我祈祷吧
所有的人都应该祈祷末日快要到啦
末日?
战争的末日
我们的世界末日
你不会认为北方佬会打败我们吧?
斯卡莉 我们的人现在光着脚
而拂吉尼亚的雪很厚
看看他们把
再看看北方佬 一批一批越来越多
等结束啦 我会在遥远的地方
而由你照顾她对我是一个安慰
告诉我 斯卡莉 能答应吗?
我能
艾希礼 就这些?
就这些啦 再见
艾希礼 我不能让你走
你要坚强些不
一定要不
我又何尝忍心走呢?
斯卡莉 你是那么的善良 那么的坚强那么的美丽
不仅是甜美的脸
还有
艾希礼 艾希礼 亲亲我
跟我吻别
不 斯卡莉
艾希礼 我爱你
我一直爱着你从没爱过别人
我跟卡里斯结婚只是为了气你
艾希礼 跟我说你爱我
我就靠它来渡过我的余生啦
再见
等战争结束啦 艾希礼
等战争结束
亚特兰大在祈祷与此同时
北方军正乘胜前进
人们仰着头
但是心情沉重
一批批伤员和难民
涌入不幸的左治亚州
我家的后面
有一棵野李子树 春天开满了花
下面有一条小溪你知道吗?
是的 我知道
我们小时候我和我的哥哥杰夫
我跟你说过杰夫的事是吧? 夫人
我是说过的
现在
也不知道他在什么地方
自从波尔园战役之后 就得不到他的消息啦
现在我们要给你量体温啦
把这个放在嘴里 别再说话啦
现在别说
梅兰妮 我太累啦我得回家
你不累吗? 梅兰妮
不 我不累 斯卡莉
被送来的 也可能是
艾希礼
只有陌生人来安慰他
我不累 斯卡莉
他们可能
都是艾希礼
我已经在马车上等了整整1小时想跟你说句话 卫尔克斯太太
走开 你这垃圾别打扰这俩位太太
别理她 梅妮
这没什么 斯卡莉 你是谁?
我是贝儿・沃特琳 不过这没关系
也许你认为这儿没我的事
告诉我你找我有什么事?
我第一次到这儿来我说我要当护士
可是这儿的太太们不要我
也许她们是对的
后来我要捐钱
她们认为我的钱也不够好
这些老孔雀
我认识一位先生说你心肠好
如果你是这样 请替医院收下我的钱
你在这儿干什么? 不是已经跟你说过两次了吗?
我是在跟卫尔克斯太太谈话
请你收下我的钱 卫尔克斯太太
既使是我的 也是好的钱
你确实很慷慨
不  我不是 我不过跟大家一样 是南方人
你当然是
这里很人可不这么想
他们不像你 是这么好的基督徒
看 米格太太 这有好多钱
十  二十  三十  五十
还不是我们的纸币 是金币
让我看看这个手绢
RB
她坐的是瑞德・巴特勒的马车
我要是不怕失身份看我怎么教训这个狐狸精
谢尔曼将军的第一发炮弹给这个城市造成了恐慌
没有援军 没有武器
人们纷纷逃避即将来临的灾难
勇敢的残存部队开赴前方
姑铸一掷的迎击敌人
主是我的牧者 我必不至缺乏
他使我躺卧在青草地上
领略着安歇的时间
他使我的灵魂苏醒
以自己的名誉引导我走正义路
我虽然走过死阴的幽谷
也不怕遭害
因为你与我同在
你的脏 你的肝都安慰吧
北方佬
米格大夫 他们离我们近啦
他们永远进不了亚特兰大永远越不过我们的防线
给我点止痛药吧
大夫 给我点止痛药吧
很抱歉 孩子 我们没有
这些虱子快让我发疯啦
什么运气你抓到啦我的J
给我力量我要去打仗
我会祝愿你
我再也见不到你和爸爸啦
这条腿得锯掉 孩子
不  不  别管我
对不起 没别的办法啦
我们没有麻醉药了 大夫
只好不用麻药做手术啦
不  不  我不锯
你们不能这样  我不要你们锯
告诉威尔克森大夫立刻把它锯掉已经坏死啦
不  不  不要锯
我已经3天3夜没回家啦
我得回去半小时看一下
护理员 帮我一把
护士把这张床腾出来吧
斯卡莉小姐
弗兰克・肯尼迪
休伦小姐 她好吗?
你什么时候进来的 弗兰克? 你伤势重吗?
休伦小姐她好吗? 她很好 弗兰克
大夫让你到手术室去
他要锯那条腿 快来
我就回来
喔 不  不  别管我
不  不  我受不了啦
别切
别
求你了
护士护士在哪儿?
韩密尔敦太太 大夫在等你呢
让他等吧  我回家啦够啦
我再不想看人们死啦 再也不看啦
大山姆
大山姆  山姆
天啊  是斯卡莉小姐
大山姆
山姆 你们全在看见你们真高兴
泰拉庄园怎么样? 妈妈怎么没给我写信呢?
她病啦 斯卡莉小姐病啦?
只是一点小病小姐
你爸爸因为膝盖受伤 没让他去打仗
军队让我们这些人为
白人士兵挖掩体
你妈妈说挖这个是为了南方
那有大夫吗?
对不起 太太 我们得前进啦
再见啦 小姐我们会挡住北方佬的
再见啦 大山姆 你们谁要是生病或受伤啦 就来找我
好 再见 再见
再见 再见
斯卡莉
快上车 这可不是散步的时候
你会被挤倒的
欧  瑞德
请你快送我到碧蒂姑妈家
逃难挺好看的是不是?
这是雪尔曼将军又送来的一张名片
他要来拜访我们啦
我得离开这儿 趁北方佬还没来赶快离开这儿
你不打算在医院工作啦?
你对死亡 蚤子 做手续切肉赶到厌倦啦?
我看你不适和照顾伤病员
别跟我说这些啦 我快吓死啦
我希望离开这儿
那我们就一块走
没有必要呆在这儿看到南方遭秧
有很多好地方可以去
墨西哥 伦敦 巴黎
跟你? 是的 太太
跟一个了解和钦佩你为人的男人
我认为我们俩人是同一类人
我等着你心里不再想着那位愁眉苦脸的艾希礼・卫尔克斯
听说卫尔克斯太太还有一个月就要生产啦
爱上一个有妻儿的人一定会非常的痛苦
我们到啦 你是跟我走? 还是下车?
我讨厌你 看不上你 至死都讨厌你 看不上你
不 不会的 斯卡莉 不会那么久的
斯卡莉小姐 斯卡莉小姐
人们都到梅肯去啦跑啦 都跑啦
我受不了啦 耳朵里全是炮声
我一听到炮声 就要晕倒
彼得大叔 小心箱子
碧蒂姑妈 你要走吗?
也许我是个胆小鬼 可是亲爱的
北方佬进了左治亚
他们是怎么进来的?
我也要走 普里西替我收拾东西 快点
碧蒂姑妈 我也得走
斯卡莉 你真的要走吗?
斯卡莉
怎么会事? 你不是想逃跑吧?
请你不要拦阻我 我再也不想回医院去啦
我闻够啦死人和腐烂的味
我要回家 找我妈妈去 她需要我
你要听我的话一定得留下
没有监护人? 米格大夫这绝对不行
天啊  夫人  这是战争不是花圆舞会
你必需留下 梅兰妮需要你
她已经病啦 她不应该有孩子
我们可以把她带走啊?
你要让她冒这个危险吗?
让她在坑坑洼洼的路上
把孩子早产在马车里吗?
又不是我的孩子 你照看她吧
斯卡莉 沃特大夫不够
又没有护士去照顾一个产妇
你得留下来照顾她
我一点也不懂接生的事
我懂  我懂
我知道怎么做 我帮人接过好多次啦
让我来干吧 大夫我什么都会
好 那我就指望你帮忙啦 好吧 大夫
艾希礼在战场上打仗 为理想在战斗
他可能回不来啦 可能战死啦
我们应该为他留下一个孩子
艾希礼
斯卡莉 你要走就赶快来吧
我答应过
艾希礼
你不走啦?
好 你走吧 碧蒂小姐斯卡莉不走啦
走吧 彼德大叔天啊  我不知道该怎么办啦
就像世界末日就要到啦
彼德大叔 我的嗅盐
梅兰妮 梅兰妮 全都为了你
我恨你  我恨你
恨你的孩子
如果我没答应过艾希礼就好啦
如果我没答应他
围城
死亡从天而降
被炮火轰击了三十五天的亚特兰大
顽强地抵御着 盼望出现奇迹
随后这里是一片沉寂
这比隆隆的炮声更加令人恐惧
停一下  请停一下
北方佬真的要打进来啦吗?
是的 太太 部队在撤退
撤出亚特兰大? 把我们丢给北方佬?
不是丢下 是撤退
我们必须在雪尔曼切断通往南方的路以前撤出去
这不是真的  不是真的我怎么办?
最好赶快往南逃太太 我得走啦
普里西
普里西 快点 普里西
快给我和梅兰妮小姐收拾东西 我们必须去泰拉庄园
北方佬现在来啦
是 小姐
斯卡莉
梅妮 我们得走
梅妮
真抱歉 成了你的累赘
天刚亮我就开始痛起来啦
可是 可是
北方佬要来啦
可怜的斯卡莉
要不是为了我 现在你以经在泰拉庄园
和你妈妈在一起啦
喔  亲爱的
你对我太好啦
亲姐妹也没这么好
我躺在这儿想
要是我死啦
你能收养我的孩子吗?
别胡说啦 梅兰妮
事情够糟的啦 别在说到死啦
我去请米格大夫来 等一等 斯卡莉
我不能让米格大夫坐等几个小时
而那些可怜的伤兵 梅妮 普里西
普里西  普里西  快一点儿
小姐 孩子
别在那儿傻站着快跑
快点  快点  看我不把你卖到南方去的 我会的
普里西还没回来?
这屋子热得像个火炉啦
还没到中午呢
别怕 梅妮
妈妈说 就好像大夫走不回来似的
该把这个普里西抽一顿
梅妮
你知道我听说过梅贝尔的事吗?
还记得她那个怪模怪样的男朋友吗?
穿的红色制服像女们内衣的料子
你别为啦我不停的说话啦
我知道你现在有多烦
梅妮 我去给你拿点凉水来
你怎么去了这么半天?
米格大夫在那?
我跟本就没有看见 什么?
他没有在医院里
有 有一个人告诉我大夫在车棚和伤兵在一起
为什么不到那里找他?
斯卡莉小姐
我不敢到那个车棚去
那里有很多死人我最害怕见到死人啦
你去照看梅妮小姐
你让她着急不然我剥了你的皮
看见米格大夫啦吗? 在那边
米格大夫
可找到你啦 大夫
谢天谢地 你来啦我这里正缺人呢
来吧  别楞着快干吧
梅妮要生孩啦 你得跟我一起回去
你糊涂啦? 我不能因为一个孩子离开这些人
他们要死啦  这么多人找个女人帮你
可我上哪儿去找人啦? 米格大夫 她会死的
死
瞧瞧他们吧 眼看着他们将会失血而死
没有麻醉药 没有绷带 连止痛药都没有
走吧 别来打扰我啦
别担心 孩子 接生并不是什么大事
把那只担架抬过来
米格大夫
好 我来啦
大夫来了吗?
没有  他来不了啦
喔  小姐梅妮小姐要生啦
他不能来 没有有人能来
普里西 没有大夫 你来接生 我来帮你
哦  不行  斯卡莉小姐不行
怎么哪?
不行  我们得找一个大夫
我对生孩子的事一点也不懂
你说什么? 我不会
你说过接生的事你全会
我也不知道为什么撒那个谎
妈妈从来不让我看生孩子 啊
斯卡莉
斯卡莉小姐
别说啦
去把炉子点着
烧一壶开水找一团线来
把干净毛巾都拿来还有剪刀
别跟我说你找不着
快去  快去
斯卡莉
来啦 梅妮
来啦
趁北方佬还没来你快走吧
我不怕 我不会离开你的
我不行啦 我要死啦
别说傻话啦 梅妮你拉着我  拉着我
跟我说话
你跟我 说说话
别硬挺着啦
要喊就喊吧这没人听见
妈妈说 床底下放一把刀能去掉一半的疼
巴特勒船长
你要找谁啊?
他在楼上 贝尔・沃特琳在请客呢
谢谢你
巴特勒船长
什么事? 这么吵啊?
嗯 我来给巴特勒船长送个口信 沃特琳小姐
巴特勒船长 请你到这边来一下
什么事? 普里西
斯卡莉小姐让我来找你
梅妮小姐今天生孩子啦
一个可爱的小男孩
是斯卡莉小姐和我给她接的生
你是来告诉我 斯卡莉
主要是我 巴特勒船长
斯卡莉小姐她只是帮了一点忙没有一个大夫能接得这么好
只是 梅妮小姐觉得有点难受现在都好啦
好 我相信你
北方佬要来啦斯卡莉小姐说 她说 啊
啊 巴特勒船长北方佬要来啦
请你马上赶着马车到我们家
对不起 军队把我的马车拉走了
你上来看我能想点什么办法
哦 不
我要是进了沃特琳小姐的家门 我妈妈会用玉米杆打死我的
你们谁能告诉我到哪儿能偷一匹马去?
到啦瑞德 瑞德 是你吗?
我们到啦 斯卡莉小姐瑞德 我就知道你会来的
晚安 真是个美好的天气
普里西说你要出去旅行
你要再开玩笑 我就杀了你
你不是说你害怕了吧?
即使你是一头山羊的话你也会害怕的
哦 北方佬 不  不
还没有来这是我们的军队在销毁军火
免得留给北方佬
我们一定得离开这儿
愿为您效劳
可是你有去哪儿呢?
回家 去泰拉庄园
泰拉庄园? 泰拉庄园附近已经打了一整天啦
你能带着一个产妇 一个婴儿
和一个头脑简单的黑丫头穿过北方的军队吗?
还是要把他们扔下?
我们一起走我要回家 别拦着我
你知道卫尔克斯太太在野外长途颠簸有多危险?
我想我妈妈
我要回泰拉庄园去
泰拉庄园也可能都被烧光啦
现在树林里到处都是散兵游勇
他们会把你的马抢走的
我是费了很大力气才把它们偷来的
我就是一步一步的走也要走回家
如果你要阻拦我 我就杀了你 我会的
我会 会的
好啦 亲爱的 好啦回家就是啦
我想任何人能有你今天的本事也对付得了雪尔曼啦
好啦 好啦 别哭啦
擦擦鼻子 像个乖孩子
啊
普里西 你在干什么吗?
正在收拾东西 斯卡莉小姐
别收拾啦 把孩子抱来
梅妮 梅妮
卫尔克斯太太 我们送你去泰拉庄园
泰拉庄园
只能这样 梅妮不
再等着雪尔曼来啦会把房子烧掉
没什么 梅妮这没什么
我的孩子
我的贝迪
你还有力气搂住我的脖子吗?
我想能行
别担心
艾希礼 卡里斯
怎么? 她要什么?
艾希礼的照片 卡里斯的军带她要带走
带上吧
那是什么?
大概是我们的勇士在放火烧仓库
那里整车厢的军火足能把我们崩到泰拉庄园
我们要穿过去就赶快走
别走那条路只能这样
这使唯一没有被切断的路
等等  我忘了锁大门啦
你在笑什么?
笑你想锁住北方佬
希望他们走快点
我要是你就不会急着要他们走
他们这一走这最后的法律和秩序就象征着消失啦
那些暴徒可不会浪费时问
我们得赶快走
那儿有匹马
把它留下 留下
到那边去 把他们截住
把马给我
斯卡莉小姐 斯卡莉小姐
军队不给北方佬而留下任何东西
趁大火还没有烧到军火库以前 我们得冲过去
快点
把披肩给我
对不起 你什么看不见会好一些的
好好看看吧 亲爱的
这是一个历史性的时刻
你可以告诉你的子孙
老南方是怎样在一夜之间覆灭的
还说1个月消灭北方佬
可怜的傻瓜
都是由于他们的
狂妄自负才把我们弄到这个地步
我那时候就认为他们太狂妄自负啦
瑞德 我正高兴你没去参军
现在你可以得意啦因为你比他们聪明
我并不得意
为什么停车?
这是去泰拉庄园的路 让马喘口气
卫尔克斯太太
梅妮小姐昏过去啦巴特勒船长
啊  或许这样样会更好
不然受不了这份罪的
斯卡莉 你一定要干这愚蠢的事吗?
奥 是 我知道我们能过去
我们一定能不是我们 亲爱的
我离开你们啦
你说什么? 你要去哪儿?
亲爱的 我要参军去
你在开玩笑? 又在吓唬我
我是认真的
到我们灰色勇士的行列里去
可他们在逃跑啊
不 我想他们会做最后的抵抗的
那个时候 我要跟他们在一起 虽然晚了一点
但是晚总比 瑞德 你准是在开玩笑
你太自私了吧?
只想着自己 却从来不想着那些崇高的目标
你怎么能这样对我
而且为什么现在要走现在我正需要你
为什么? 为什么?
为什么?
因为我一向留恋破灭的理想
一旦真正破灭的话
或许是
我自己感到羞愧
谁知道呢?
你应该羞死 把我们仍在这儿 无依无靠
你无依无靠?
北方佬要是抓到你他们就得 求上帝保佑啦
来 说再见吧
不
下来
瑞德 请你别走你不能走
我永远不会原谅你
我不求你原谅我我永远也不理解或原谅我自己
如果子弹打中我那倒好啦 我是个白痴
我只知道
我爱你 斯卡莉
即使这倒霉的世界和我们俩都变成碎片
我也爱你
因为我们很相像 我们都够坏啦
自私而且精明
但我们能够一眼把事物看清楚
别这么搂着我
斯卡莉 看着我
我爱你胜过爱任何女人
我等待你的时间比等待任何女人都长
放开我
在你面前是一个爱你的南方战士
期待着你的拥抱
期待着把和你亲吻的记忆带到战场
你是在为一个 准备带着美好记忆
去赴死的战士送行
斯卡莉 吻我
就这一次
你下流 胆小卑鄙的东西
他们说对啦  人人都说对啦你不是个绅士
现在这些都无所谓了
给你
如果有人要抢这匹马就打他
可是别弄错了把马给打死
走吧  走吧  我要你走我希望一颗炮弹把你打中
把你炸成一百万片
别再说啦我知道你是怎么想的
我希望等我为国捐躯的时候
你的良心能够感到不安
再见啦 斯卡莉
来 走吧  我们回家啦
我可怜的孩子
别担心 梅妮
回到家里妈妈会照顾他的
斯卡莉小姐 我饿极啦
我们弄点吃的吧
别说啦
快到十二橡树啦我们在那儿休息
快走
卫约翰 1864年
艾希礼 艾希礼辛亏你没看到这些
北方佬
可恶的北方佬
普里西 普里西去把牛栓住
我们不需要牛 斯卡莉小姐
我们就要到家啦我 我害怕牛
撕一条你的衬裙把它绑在车后面
贝比需要牛奶还不知道家里能有什么
梅妮  我们到家啦
到泰拉庄园啦
你快点走  这畜牲
斯卡莉小姐 它死啦
我没看见房子  它还在吗? 我看不见房子  他们把它烧啦吗?
哦 它还在
没有被烧掉
它还在呢
妈妈  爸爸
妈妈  爸爸  我回来啦
妈妈  让我进去
爸爸
我回来啦
凯丽
凯丽・斯卡莉
哦 宝贝
妈眯
妈眯 我回来啦宝贝孩子
妈眯 我没事
妈妈在那儿?
她啊
休伦小姐和凯琳小姐得了伤寒病
她病啦 现在好多啦
弱得象小猫似的
可 妈妈在哪儿?
你妈妈
爱伦小姐去照顾艾利・施莱特那个坏女人
她也被传染上啦
昨天夜里她 妈妈
妈妈
她在哪?
斯卡莉小姐
你有什么吩咐吗? 斯卡莉小姐
把梅妮小姐安置好了吗?
你别担心梅妮小姐啦
我已经把她和婴儿都安置到床上啦
波克 把我牵来的牛牵进牛栏里吧
没有牛栏啦斯卡莉小姐
北方佬把它拆啦当柴烧啦
他们用这所房子当指挥部
周围都搭上了帐篷
北方佬到泰拉庄园来啦
是的 他们把所有的东西都偷走啦
所有的布 所有的毯子连你母亲的念珠都偷走啦
我饿死啦 波克给我弄点吃的来
没有吃的啦他们都拿走啦
所有东西?
他们拿走了所有的东西
把吃不了的东西放在马鞍上带走啦
别再跟我说他们都干什么啦
爸爸 这是什么?
威士忌?
是的 女儿
凯丽・斯卡莉 够啦
你不会喝酒你要喝醉的
我希望喝醉
醉了倒好
爸爸
这些是什么?
是 债券
是我们的全部财产
就留下这些啦
债券
什么样的债券? 爸爸
当然是邦联的啦 女儿
邦联的债券
那还有什么用呢?
我不爱听你这样说话斯卡莉
爸爸 我们没有钱没有吃的 怎么办?
应该去问你妈妈
对啦
应该去问欧郝纳太太
问妈妈对
欧郝纳太太知道该怎么办
现在别打扰我
出去骑会儿马
我很忙
爸爸
什么事也不用您操心
斯卡莉回来啦
你放心吧
斯卡莉小姐
咱们给病人跟孩子吃什么呢
我不知道 妈眯
我不知道
菜园子里除了罗卜什么都没有
斯卡莉小姐休伦小姐和凯琳小姐
她们要擦擦身子
别的用人都上哪儿去啦?
哦 小姐 就我和波克啦
别的人有的去打仗有的逃跑啦
我不能又照顾病人又管孩子
我只有两只手啊
谁去挤牛奶啊? 斯卡莉小姐我们都是干屋里活的
上帝是我的见证
上帝是我的见证他们别想打垮我
我要渡过这一时刻等一切都过去我永远不再挨饿
也不让家里人挨饿
那怕是说谎 去偷 去骗 或杀人
上帝是我的见证我绝不再挨饿啦
狂飙袭卷佐治亚洲
雪尔曼将军
为了催垮南方邦联
使之一败涂地 永远臣服
这位伟大的入侵者 挥师前进
在他身后
留下了一条宽六十英里的北极
从亚特南大直达海地
泰拉庄园幸存下来了
面对饥饿和苦难
哦  我的腰都要折了
哦  看我的手
妈妈说过 看她的手就知道她是不是位小姐
我看什么手啊小姐以后都无所谓啦
你歇会吧 休伦你还没有完全好我可以干二个人的活
斯卡莉德 她真可恶让我干这个 我不想
这可没办法
继续干活 我不能把泰拉庄园所有的活都干完
我才不管泰拉庄园呢我恨泰拉庄园
看你还敢再说恨泰拉庄园
那就是恨爸爸和妈妈
凯蒂・斯卡莉有件事我必须跟你说
爸爸 什么事?
我以经跟普里西和妈眯说了我不喜欢你这样对待她们
对下人是要严格 但态度要温和
特别是对黑人
是的 爸爸 我知道可我没让她们做我自己不做的事
不管怎么说 我不喜欢 我要跟欧郝纳太太说
你下来干什么? 梅妮
斯卡莉 我要跟你说
你们都太辛苦了我不能躺在那儿什么也不干
快回到楼上去 你身体很虚弱
请让我干吧 斯卡莉
别逞强了 我的事已经够多了
你要再病那就永远好不了
我 我没想到这一点
谁在那儿? 别动动就开枪了
你一个人 小媳妇?
你不太友好 是不是?
除了这耳环还有别的吗?
你们北方佬来过这儿了
你是小泼妇是吧
手里还藏着什么?
你把他打死了
我真高兴
斯卡莉德 斯卡莉德 出什么事了 斯卡莉德?
别害怕 孩子们你们的姐姐擦枪走火了
差点没把她吓死
哦 谢天谢地还嫌我们吓得不够吗?
告诉凯蒂・斯卡莉要小心点儿
你可真会撒谎
我们得赶快把他弄出去埋掉 斯卡莉德
如果让北方佬发现了他们就会
我没看见别的人他大概是逃兵
那也得把他藏起来
他们听到风声就 会抓你的
我可以把他埋在藤箩架小林的角落里
可是 可我们怎么把弄搬出去呢?
我们一人拉一条腿
你连只猫都拉不动
斯卡莉 我们搜一搜他的背包 没什么不好吧?
我都没想到
你搜背包 我搜他的口袋
你看
我有点不舒服
我看里面都是钱
梅妮 你看
你看啦
二十 三十 四十
别数了 现在没功夫
这就意味着我们有吃的了
翻翻别的口袋
快  快
我们得赶快把他拖出去
院子里留下血迹我们就瞒不住了
把你的睡衣给我我要把他的头包上
别在乎 我不会看你的
我要是穿着睡裙或长裤就会用我的那
幸亏我没那么
快上床去吧不然你快死了
等我埋了他 再把血擦干净
不用 我会擦的
我想我是杀人了
现在先不想它了
我明天再想吧
凯迪・斯卡莉
凯迪・斯卡莉结束了
全结束了
战争结束了
李将军投降了
这不可能  那我们为什么要打呢?
艾希礼要回来了
对 艾希礼要回来了
我们要种更多棉花
明年价钱会升得很高
衣衫滥缕的骑士们
从失败的冒险中
重返家园
他们步履盘栅的回到曾是富足的沃土
如今已是满目疮痍
随之而来的是另一个入侵者  投机商
当我们进军乔治亚州时
万岁万岁
使你获自由的旗帜
从亚特兰大欢呼到海边
当我们踏上乔治亚洲时
滚开 别挡道  反派
能让个快死的人搭一下车吗?
我这儿没有南方贱民的地方
o我滚开
我看他宁愿走也不愿意搭这车
驾  滚开  你们这些乞丐
都是他们打胜了
快把裤子仍给我肯尼迪先生
快点
用肥皂把自己好好搓搓别等我动手给你搓
我要把这些裤子给煮煮
整个南方军队都让
虱子和地气折磨苦啦
你这样对他 让他太难为情啦
他身上的虱子跑到你身上你就更难为情啦
过来 波尔
别缠着这位先生 你看他又累又饿
没关系 太太又能看见孩子太好啦
多好的小家伙
再打两年仗我们就能把他带到科布军团啦
你是科布军团的?
是的 太太
那你一定认识我丈夫卫尔克斯上校啦
喔  是的 太太
他好象是 被俘了
谢天谢地 他还没
可怜的艾希礼他被送到了监狱里
梅兰妮
哦 斯卡莉德 我来了
我来看着他吧 太太 我们是好朋友啦
谢谢你
我从早到晚象奴隶似的干我们才能免强吃饱肚子
可你却把吃的都给那些饿死鬼
他们很块都会来的
请别责怪我了 求求你
我刚听说艾希礼当了俘虏
当了俘虏? 是的
也许 他要是还活着现在正在北方的路上
如果有那个北方妇人把她的晚饭分给他一口
帮助我心爱的人回到我身边
但愿如此 梅妮
斯卡莉小姐
斯卡莉小姐我有件事要跟你父亲谈
可他好象是 也许我能帮你
我现在是一家之主
那好
我 我是来向休伦小姐提亲的
你是要告诉我 这么多年你还没有提这件事
她一直在等你
我实际上 我比她大得多
而且我现在一文不铭
如今谁有钱啦?
斯卡莉小姐 请你放心 我是真诚的爱你妹妹
我会使她非常幸福的
如果我们订了婚我可以外出去经商
等我们有了经济基础我们就
好的 弗兰克可以跟爸爸答说
你去问休伦吧
谢谢 谢谢您斯卡莉德小姐
对不起 对不起
斯卡莉 肯尼迪先生好象有什么麻烦事了?
比他想象的麻烦点
他终于向休伦求婚了
真让人高兴可惜他不能马上娶她
不然我们可以少一张嘴吃饭
又来一个
但愿这个不是很饿
他一定很饿
让普里西再预备一盘
艾希礼
亲爱的
斯卡莉德小姐
别打扰他们放开我 傻瓜 那是艾希礼
是她的丈夫
斯卡莉德小姐 我 回来得正好
马掌钉上了吗? 是的 钉好了
斯卡莉德小姐 您 马有鞋 人确没有真是新鲜事
来 搅肥皂是的 小姐斯卡莉小姐
我想知道你现在还有多少钱 是金币
十元 怎么?
那是不够的
天知道你在说什么呢?
斯卡莉小姐 我看见了杰纳尔德先生以前雇的监工
就是那个白人垃圾威克尔森啦
他现在已经成了真正的北方佬了
他吹牛说他的北方朋友要把泰拉庄园的税提得比天都高
我们得交多少?
我听税务官说要三百元呢
三百元
就象是三百万
我们也得想办法交啊
是啊
怎么交?
我去问问希礼先生
他可拿不出三百元来
我可以去问问他
问他也没什么啊
艾希礼
啊听说林肯当初也是劈木桩的
一但我有了这个才能我也会飞黄腾达
艾希礼 北方佬还要我们交三百元的税
我们怎么办?
我们该怎么办呢?
文明遭到破坏以后人会变成什么样子呢?
有头脑和勇气的人可以生存下去
没有的就会被淘汰
看在上帝的份上别站在这儿跟我胡说啦
我们就是要被淘汰的人啦
你是对的 斯卡莉
在泰拉庄园面临危机的时候
我还在这里跟你说这些蠢话
你找我是需要我帮忙 可我帮不了你
斯卡莉
我是个懦夫
你? 艾希礼? 懦夫?
你害怕什么呢?
生活对我变得太现实啦
我想我倒是不在乎劈木头
而是在乎失去了我所爱的生活中那种美好的东西
如果没有战争我可以在十二颗橡树愉快地度过我的一生
可是战争爆发了
我看到儿时的朋友被炸死
看到被我打中的人痛苦地倒下
现在我发现这个世界对我来说 比死还糟糕
这个世界里没有我的立足之地
我无法让你理解其实你不知道什么是害怕
你从来不害怕面对现实
你从不像我这样逃避现实
逃避?
艾希礼 你错了
我也是想逃避的
我对这里太厌倦了我要为吃 为钱而奋斗
为除草 锄地 摘棉花只到干不动了为止
南方是完了
北方佬 投机政客拙萘怂我们什么都没有啦
艾希礼
我们走吧
去墨西哥
墨西哥军队需要军官我们会幸福的
我为你干活 为你做任何事你知道你不爱梅兰妮
那天你在十二颗橡树你说过你爱我
而且梅兰妮
米格大夫告诉我她不能再生育了
可我能给你 我们不能忘掉
在十二颗橡树那天吗? 你以为我能忘吗? 你能忘吗?
说真的 你不爱我吗?
不 我 我不爱你 撒谎就算是撒谎
你认为我能撇下梅兰妮和孩子伤梅兰妮的心吗?
你也不能离开你的父亲和妹妹
我能离开我都烦死啦 厌倦透啦
是的 你是又烦 又厌倦所以你才这么说
你为我们负担得太重了
从现在起我要尽力的帮助你
只有一个办法你能帮我
带我走
这没什么可留恋的
没有?
没有 除了尊严
别这样
别这样斯卡莉别哭了
别哭了
别哭了 我勇敢的斯卡莉
你是爱我的 你是爱我的
你说呀   不
你爱我不 我们不能这样
我们不能 这事不会再发生了你爱我
我要带着梅兰妮和孩子走
好 我说我爱你的勇敢和顽强我太爱了
因此我刚才 我几乎忘记了我最贤淑的妻子
斯卡莉 我不会忘记她们
那 我就什么都没有了
没为他奋斗
为他生存了
有一样东西
有一样东西你爱他胜过于我
虽然你还没有意识到
泰拉庄园
对 我
我还有这个
你们不用走
我不会让你们去挨饿
这事不会再发生了只是为了你 卫克斯
啊是斯卡莉
不要过来
没忘你们的老监工吧?
她现在是爱丽・威克尔森太太了
别走上台阶  不要脸的  从这儿滚出去
你不能这样对我太太说话
太太? 她早该是的
你害死我母亲之后你再生孩子 谁给他做洗礼?
我们是来拜访的友好的拜访 还要跟老朋友谈点事
朋友? 什么时候跟你做过朋友?
还那么高傲? 是吗? 你们的事 我全知道
我知道你父亲已经痴呆了
你交不起税
我来这儿是想买下这地方
我能出个好价钱
爱丽很想住在这儿
滚开 你这个卑鄙的北方佬
等你这爱尔兰人为了交税去卖他
就知道谁是这里的主人啦
我要买这块地方全部买下 住在这儿
我等着拍卖呢
你从泰拉庄园只会得到这个
你会后悔的
我们会回来的
我要你看看谁是泰拉庄园的主人
爸爸 回来
爸爸
胆小的北方佬
啊
斯卡莉小姐这是杰纳尔德先生的表啊
你拿着吧 给你了 爸爸愿意给你
你现在可得留着这块表
你需要卖掉所有值钱的东西 去交税
你会卖爸爸表吗?
别哭啦
我不能看你流泪
妈眯 妈眯
你一直很勇敢 斯卡莉小姐你还要鼓起勇气来
想想你爸爸以前的样子
我不能想爸爸我什么也不能想
只能想那三百块钱
想这些有什么用
谁也没有这么多的钱
除了北方佬和暴发户谁也没有这么多的钱
瑞德
谁? 北方佬吗?
妈眯 你看我又瘦又苍白
我还没有衣服
妈眯 快到搁楼上把妈妈装衣服样子的盒子拿下来
你要这窗帘干什么?
给我做件新衣服
不能用爱伦小姐的窗帘只要就不
别唆 现在是我的窗帘
我要到亚特南大弄三百元去我要看起来象个女王
谁跟你去亚特南大? 我自己去
那是你这么想的 我跟你去
我一定跟着你
哦 好妈眯
你别这么哄我 小姐
我给你垫第一块尿布的时候就了解你
我说跟着你 就一定去
三个老K 嗯 我可糟了 上校
可惜我们不能用扑克来决定战争的胜负
立葛南特将军出的力少 可赢得多
什么事 下士?
长官 有一位女士要见巴特勒船长说是他妹妹?
又一个妹妹
这是监狱 不是后宫巴特勒船长
少校 她不象那些人
她有个保姆跟着
是吗?
我倒想见见她 少校可别带保姆
嗯 我看看这一下午输了多少?
三百四十块
我可要债台高筑了是不是 少校
好吧 下士
把巴特勒船长的妹妹带到他的牢房
谢谢你 少校对不起 先生们
对输了钱还高兴的人不好太严历啦
瑞德
斯卡莉 我的小妹妹
好了 下士我的妹妹没有带挫或锯进来
现在我可以吻你了吗?
像大哥哥那样吻一下前额吧
不 谢谢 我要等将来好好的吻你
喔 瑞德 听说你被关进监狱我真的难过死了
我睡不着 一直在想
他们会绞死你吗?
你会难过?
瑞德哦 别担心 斯卡莉
北方佬给我捏造了一些罪名
其实是为了我的钱
好象我把联邦的金库拐走了似的
喔 你是这样吗?
别见面就谈这个了
我们别谈肮脏的钱的事了
你来看我真是太好了呵 你真是太漂亮了
瑞德 别拿我这样的乡下姑娘取笑了
感谢上帝 你没有穿得破破乱乱我真是看够了
来 转过身去
真是太漂亮了你吃得不错 生活的很好
谢谢 我一直很好
泰拉庄园的每个人都很好只是我太闷了
想到城里来看看
你是一个没有心肝的人这也是你的魅力
他已经超过法律的允许了
我到这儿来不是谈论我的
因为我听说你遇到麻烦了非常的难过
那天晚上你把我仍在路上我气坏啦
我还没原谅你呢
喔 别那件事啦
可要是没有你我可能已经死啦当我想到自己
我想到自己有了我所希望的一切过着无忧无虑的生活
而你却在这可怕的牢房里
简直不是人呆的地方是关马的
我想说点笑话
可我真要哭了
我现在就要哭了
斯卡莉德 这可能吗?
你说可能什么? 瑞德
你以经有了一颗女人的心啦真正女人的心
我有 瑞德我知道我有
你知道 听说你这话坐牢也值得
真是太值得了
你简直能把月亮给说下来
泰拉庄园那个地方一切都好 是吗?
哦 是的你用这双手干什么了?
不过是上次骑马的时候没戴手套
这不是小姐的手象是庄稼人干活的手
你为什么要撒谎? 你为什么要来
哦 瑞德 我差点相信你真的关心我了
可我是关心
还是说实话吧
你急于找我要什么东西
所以穿上天鹅绒的衣服来表演
是什么? 钱?
我需要三百块钱交泰拉庄园的税
喔 瑞德 我对说一切都好那是说谎
情况是糟得不能再糟了而你有的是钱
你拿什么作抵压?
我的耳环不感兴趣
用泰拉庄园我要农场做什么?
你不会损失的我明年用棉花还给你
不够好还有更好的吗?
你说过你爱我
如果你还爱我
你是不是忘了我是个不结婚的人
没有 我没有忘记
听我说 斯卡莉 你不值三百块钱
你对男人来说只意味着倒霉
说啊侮辱我吧
我不在乎 只要给我钱
我不能失去泰拉庄园只要还有一口气 就不能失去它
瑞德
请你把钱借该我吧
我想借你 也没办法给你
我的钱在利物浦不在亚特南大
如果我签一张支票北方佬会象鸭子见到小虫似的
所以 亲爱的你白低声下气了
好啦 好啦 别这样啦
你想让北方佬见你这个样子吗?
把手拿开 你这个流氓
我还没说你就知道我要说什么
你明知道不会借钱给我可还让我说下去
我就是想要听听你说什么
别灰心来看着我上绞架
我的遗嘱里会有你一份我会来看的
唯一担心的就是泰拉庄园要交税的时候还没绞死你
告诉他是贝尔・沃特琳
最近你去那儿了? 是不是把船长给忘了?
我很忙 扶我下来
她是谁? 我从来没有见过这种颜色的头发
你认识这个人吗?
我倒希望认识她她能借给我钱
不管他们在监狱里对你怎么样
你到监狱里去看那个臭白人
真是活该
又新鲜有绿
今天晚上你干什么朱蒂?
一个左治亚的美人儿
在俄亥俄可没有这样的
你们知道我们要干什么吗? 什么?
我们要给你们每个人四十一亩地和一头驴子
还有一头驴子? 四十一亩地和一头驴子
对
因为我们是
你们的朋友
你们都要选举权了
你忙什么呢 妹妹?
这个城市变样了
北方佬琢炝怂他们拙萘宋颐堑囊磺
别挡着道 别挡着道
讨厌 让开 让开
别挡着道 别挡着
这不是斯卡莉小姐吗?
弗南克・肯尼迪还有妈眯
在这儿见到家乡人真是太好啦
我不知道你们在亚特南大
我也不知道你在这儿?
休伦跟你说过我的店吗?
她说过吗? 我不记得了 你有个店?
这个?
请进来 随便看看
这不象太太们去的那种店
可我为它感到骄傲
你没赚什么钱?
啊 还算可以我是很有信心的
人们都说我是个天生的商人
用不了多久 就可以和休伦小姐结婚啦
你干得那么好?
是的 干得不错
我还不是百万富翁
但我已经赚了一千多元了
你经营木材?
是啊
这只是附带经营的
附带经营?
亚特南大周围有很多的松木很多房屋正在修建
这都需要钱斯卡莉小姐
我该准备买房子啦
你买房子干什么?
和休伦小姐建立一个家庭
在亚特南大? 你要把她接到亚特南大 是吗?
这样对泰拉庄园没什么好处
嗯 我不明白你的意思? 斯卡莉小姐
我没什么意思
弗南克 你愿意送我去碧蒂姑妈家吗?
我非常愿意 斯卡莉小姐
你最好留下来吃晚饭
碧蒂姑妈肯定会同意的我愿意跟你多呆一会
这太让我兴奋了斯卡莉小姐
你能告诉我所有的消息吗?
关于休伦小姐的一切
怎么了 斯卡莉小姐?
休伦小姐没生病吧?
喔 不 不
我想她一定给你写信了
她大概没脸给你写信
她该感到羞愧
哦 我怎么会这么一个妹妹
快告诉我 斯卡莉小姐别让我心神不安啦 快点
喔 下个月她要和一个农村小伙子结婚了
她等得不耐烦了她怕成为老处女
我很难过 这事由我来告诉你
真冷啊  我把手笼忘在家啦
你不介意我把手放在你的口袋里吧?
斯卡莉・肯尼迪
三百元 亚特南大国家银行
喔 梅兰妮 你不知道她干了什么事
她跟我的肯尼迪先生结婚啦
她是为了保住泰拉庄园 你应该理解她 休伦
我要宰了她
我恨泰拉庄园 我恨斯卡莉比对泰拉庄园还恨
都是我的错
为跟你弄钱交税我应该去拦路抢劫
我不能让你干这种事
反正木以成舟了
是啊是这样
你不让我干不体面的事情
可你出卖了自己 嫁给你不爱的人
你不用再为我这无能的人操心了
你什么意思?
我要去纽约
我已经在银行里找到了一个职位
可你不能去
我 我还指望你帮我做木材生意呢 艾希礼
我 我就指望你了
我恐怕帮不上你
斯卡莉 我木材生意是一窍不通的
这跟你在银行也是一样的
而且我要把生意都给你一半
这是你的慷慨 斯卡莉
可是不能这样
如果我到亚特南大还要靠你的帮助
我就永远没有独立生活的希望啦
好啊就为这个
你可以逐步买下这个店然后它就是你的了
不 斯卡莉德
欧 艾希礼
艾希礼
斯卡莉
斯卡莉 怎么了?
艾希礼这么冷酷 这么可恨
你干什么啦?
她要 我们去亚特南大
我的木材生意要开业了他连一根手指头都不肯帮我
你太没有骑士风度了
想想吧 艾希礼
如果不是斯卡莉我就死在亚特南大了
而且 而且可能连小波尔都没有啦
每当我想到她耕地 摘棉花
都为了养活我们 而我只能
喔 亲爱的
好啦 梅兰妮
我去亚特南大
我斗不过你们俩个
快点走
啊这都是新来的工人肯尼迪太太
是从左治亚洲监狱里挑来的最好的
他们看起来又瘦又弱的样子
立定
这是能雇来的最好的犯人啦
如让你放手让我管
你要什么 就能干什么
好吧 你是工头
要保证木材厂运转即时供应木材
亚利格听您吩咐 太太
要记住
不要过问和干予我的事
就这么定了 明天一早开工
好了你们走吧 走啊到那边去
斯卡莉 这不对 你是知道的
女人做生意已经很不象样了
而你 你抱怨什么?
如果我不管你永远不会有木材厂的
可我并不想要这个木材厂啊
如果你不是逼我的朋友还欠我的债我是不会买它的
你说对吗 艾希礼?
你在经营慈善机构吗?
回店里去吧 弗南克然回家吃药
你的气色不大好
可是宝贝 你和我一起回家好
别唆了 别再打扰我也别叫我宝贝
好吧   好吧
晚安 艾希礼
哦 天啦 我从没见过脾气这么大的女人
斯卡莉 我不想干予
不过我希望能让我雇用自由黑人来代替那些犯人
这样将会更好
黑人的工钱会让我们破产犯人便宜
我们尽管放手让嘎厉特去做
放手? 这是什么意识你知道吗?
他会饿着他们 鞭打他们
你没看见吗? 有的人病了 吃不饱饭 艾希礼
你会怎么管理 如果让你管 你会一天三顿给他们吃鸡
让他们w羽绒被
我不愿意从那些强迫劳动的可怜的人身上赚钱
你不是也有过奴隶吗?
那不一样不是这样对待他们
即使没有战争
我也会在父亲去世后让他们自由的
很遗憾 艾希礼
你忘了没有钱是什么样了?
我发现钱是世界上最重要的东西
我再也不愿意受穷了
我要赚多多的钱 这样北佬就不能从我手里把泰拉庄园夺走啦
这是唯一的途径
并不是我们几个南方人在受苦
看看我们的朋友他们还保持着尊严和善良
对 可他们在挨饿 连自己都养活不了有什么用
我知道他们在说我可我不在乎
我就是要跟北方人打交道
按他们的方式战胜他们
好了 再往那边挪一点
下午好 肯尼迪太太
下午好
生意很幸隆是不是
挺不错的
斯卡莉 你跟把些抢劫和折磨过我们
而且还让我们饥饿的北方佬做生意
这都过去了
我要赚钱 那怕跟北方佬共事
梅姿格灵之太太 你知道吗?
米格大夫看见她亲自把木材卖给了北方佬
还不只这些呢
她对我哥哥艾希礼所干的事真让人吃惊
她甚至还自己找马车呢
亲爱的肯尼迪太太
最亲爱的肯尼迪太太
你具然还有脸来见我
我想你只要再多等一下
就能得到我的钱了
女人真是善变
你要干什么? 我还有要紧事呢
你能不能满足一下我的好奇心我一直感到非常困惑
是什么? 说
告诉我 你难道不在乎和一个你不爱的人结婚?
你怎么从监狱里出来的? 为什么没绞死你?
没有用钱买不到的东西
我看连那位高贵的
卫尔克斯先生也让你买下来了
这么说 你还恨艾希礼?
我想你是嫉妒他吧
你还以为你是这里的美人是吗?
还以为是一位娇滴滴的小姐
每个男人见到你都会爱得要死
让我过去
别生气 斯卡莉你要去哪儿?
我去木材厂与你有什么关系
一个人经过棚户区
你不知道一个人赶车遇上那些流氓会有多危险
别为我操心
需要开枪的时候我会开枪的
这种女人
给我二十五分
放开我的马
拉住这马  拉住它
注意 她有枪
救命
救命啊
斯卡莉德小姐
斯卡莉德小姐 斯卡莉德小姐等等我
我是大山姆
大山姆
等等我
山姆 山姆
你受伤了 斯卡莉小姐?
别哭了 斯卡莉德小姐马上送你离开这儿
驾  快跑
你到泰拉庄园去 越快越好就待在那儿
喔 太好了我看够了那些投机政客了
谢谢你 弗南克先生再见 斯卡莉德小姐
再见 山姆 谢谢你
斯卡莉 换件衣服晚上到美利德家去
我去参加一个政治集会
政治集会
我今天下午出了事
你还要参加政治集会?
哦 宝贝你受了惊吓了
没有人关心我你们就像没事一样
男人们总是说要保护我们妇女
可今天我出了这么大事弗南克倒去参加政集会了
如果你不难过 英蒂雅
请告诉我你为什么总是这么看着我?
难道 我的脸是绿色的吗?
我并不难过
今天下午发生的事是你自找的
如果还有公理的话你应该更倒霉
英蒂雅 别说了
喔 让她说 梅兰妮
自从我把你弟弟查尔斯从她那儿夺走后
她就一直恨我
如果有人追她
她会脱光衣服在街上走的
我就是恨你
你的所作所为败坏了我们正经人的名誉
现在又让男人们去冒生命危险 因为他们的
英蒂雅
我想最好都别说了谁也别再多说了
出什么事啦我怎么什么都不知道?
嘘 有人走过来了
不知道是谁
请把手枪给我 米格太太
不论是谁
问你们说什么都不知道
他们到哪儿去了?
快告诉我 是生死悠关的事
什么都不要告诉他他是北方的奸细
快一点 或许还来得及
你怎么知道?
我跟两个北方商人玩牌
他们知道了晚上要闹事
已经做好了准备
你丈夫和他们的朋友要落入圈套了
别告诉他 他在套你的话
在得卡德罗夫街老苏利文种植园
在被烧的房子的地窖里聚会
我尽力而为
怎么回事? 你们都不告诉我 我要疯啦
斯卡莉 我们本来不想告诉你
艾希礼 弗南克 还有一些别人
去清除你出事的树林去了
这就是我们南方男人
保护我们所做的事
如果他们被捕 都要被绞死斯卡莉
这都是你惹的祸
英蒂雅 你再说一句就请你出去
郝斯卡莉做的是她应该做的
男人们也是在尽他们的职责
弗南克
艾希礼
这不可能
马队 梅妮小姐
你们做活 别停下来
妈眯 开门吧
晚上好 肯尼迪太太
哪位是卫尔克斯太太?
我是卫尔克斯太太
我要跟卫尔克斯先生谈谈可以吗?
他不在
真的吗?
梅妮小姐不会撒谎
我不是不尊重您卫尔克斯太太
如果你能保证我就不搜查了
要搜就搜吧 他有一个政治集会在肯尼迪先生的店里
他没在那儿今天晚上没有集会
没有政治集会
我到外面去等他们回来
中士包围这所房子堵住所有的们和窗户
是 队长
继续做活吧
我来 我来朗读
大卫・科伯非尔的生平和经历
第一章
我出生了
我从出生的那天起即是我生命的开始
第九章我有一个可纪念的生日
我的生日在三月间来到
这以前 学校中所发生的一切我都不提了
除了司帖夫子比以前更让人羡慕以外
我什么都不记得了
他就要在年底离开假如不是更早的话
在我的眼里 他比以前更活泼更能独立
因而比以前更让人喜欢了
可是除此之外
我什么都不记得了
梅妮 他们喝醉了
让我来应付
请你 什么也别说
你这蠢货
安静
你们不要再唱了安静
你好 梅妮
你又把我丈夫灌醉了巴特勒船长
好 扶他进来吧
对不起 卫尔克斯太太你丈夫被捕了
你们如果要逮捕亚特南大的
那你们的监狱里就住满北方人了喔 对不起 我
扶他进来吧 巴特勒船长如果你自己还能走的话
喔 这
我要给你讲个故事
大夫 我
让他坐在椅子上
巴特勒船长 请你离开我家好吗?
记住以后再也别来了
可是我把他从大街上弄回来没让他在那儿丢人
你就 这样谢我?
我们进来大家一起唱吧
米格大夫
你太我吃惊了
艾希礼 你怎么能做这种事?
我 我还没太醉
扶他进卧室去 妈眯把他扶到床上去
别动他 他被捕了中士
汤姆
你为什么要逮捕他?
我看见他喝醉了
也见你喝醉过你也见过我
他醉倒在沟里我也管不着我不是警察
可他今天晚山领着人袭击了棚户区
就是肯尼迪太太出事的地方
很多屋子被烧了 还打死了人
应该让你们这些反叛明白不能为所欲为了
你在笑什么?
你不用来教训我 汤姆
今晚他一直跟我在一起是的 先生
瑞德 跟你?
在哪儿?
在太太们面前不好说
你最好说出来
到外面门厅 我告诉你
说吧 巴特勒船长
我想有权知道我丈夫去哪儿
好吧 太太 我们 在我们的一个朋友家里
也是队长的朋友
贝尔・沃特琳太太那儿
我们打牌 喝香宾 还有
好那
干的好事在我太太面前把我结发了
现在你可以满意了 汤姆?
明天这俩位太太不会理他们的丈夫
哦 瑞德 我 我没想到 我
你说 你能发誓说他们今晚上
都在贝尔家
你要不相信去问贝尔她会告诉你的
你能像位绅士那样想我保证吗?
象位绅士?
当然了
好 如果
如果我弄错了对不起
请你原谅我 卫尔克斯太太
请你走吧 让我们安静一会
我 我说对不起了
真 真的对不起
走吧  中士
锁上门 拉上窗帘
艾希礼
不要紧 只是肩膀受伤了
扶他上床我给他包扎伤口
我想 我能走
何必呢?
哪边? 这边
喔 妈眯 给我点热水好
需要点软布做绷带我去找
我用什么探伤口? 要是有药箱就好了
你真上那儿去了吗? 那儿什么样子
有刻花的玻璃吊灯 丝绒窗帘好多镜子吗?
天啦 我的太太 你在说什么呢?
巴特勒船长 请告诉我倒底怎么回事
我晚了一步
我赶到那儿他们已经跟北方佬交上了火
卫尔克斯先生受了伤米格大夫和他在一起
我必须证明他们不在现场而在别处
所以把他们 带到贝尔那儿去了
她让他们进去了?
贝尔是我的老朋友了
喔 对不起
很抱歉 我当时想不出更体面的地方
这已经不是你第一次救我了巴特勒船长
我问你 并不是怀疑你的做法
我 我去看看米格大夫还需要什么
艾希礼
你对你自己丈夫的情况一点儿也不感兴趣吗?
哼  弗南克一跟你去贝尔那儿了吗?
没有
那么他在哪儿?
正躺在得卡斯大路上
头部中了弹
他死了
是哪一位?
是我 沃特琳太太
沃特琳太太请到屋里坐会儿吧
我不能进去 卫尔克斯太太
你上车来跟我呆一会
你这么帮助我该怎么谢你呢?
我怎么谢你才好呢?
我收到你的便条说你要来拜访我
向我道谢 卫尔克斯太太
您大概是糊涂了 所以天刚黑 我就赶过来
告诉您 您 不应该这样想
那是很不合适的
我向一位救了我丈夫命的人去道谢 有什么不合适?
卫尔克斯太太 全城没有一位太太像您对我这么好
我是说为医院捐款的事
我不会忘记的
我想卫尔克斯先生要是被绞死
你又成了寡妇 还有一个孩子
他真是个天真可爱孩子
我也有个男孩 所以我
哦 您也有 ? 他住在 ?
喔 不 他不在亚特南大
我从来也没有见过他
他在别处上学
从小我就没见过他了
不管怎么说 要是肯尼迪太太的丈夫出了事
我是连一个手指头也不会帮她的
就是巴特勒船长说也不行
她是个冷酷的女人在亚特南大目中无人
她丈夫等于就是让她杀死的
请你不要这样说我的弟妹
哦 请别介意卫尔克斯太太
我忘了你喜欢她了
不过您跟她可不是一路人我就是这么看的
现在我该走了
我怕在这儿呆久了有人会认出我的马车
这样对您不好
还有 卫尔克斯太太
如果 你在街上遇到了我而不和我说话
我能理解
跟您说话 向您道谢我都感到荣辛
希望能再见面
啊不 这不太合适
晚安 卫尔克斯太太晚安 沃特琳太太
你误解了肯尼迪太太
她为她丈夫的死很痛心
是瑞德 真讨厌
小姐 巴特勒船长来看你
我告诉他 你现在很伤心
告诉他 我就下来 妈眯
她说她就下来
我不知道她为什么要下来可她马就下来
你不喜欢我 妈眯
你不用和我说了 我知道你真不喜欢我
这样不好 斯卡莉
什么?
花露水
我 不明白你的意思
我是说你喝酒了 白兰地喝了不少
喝了怎么样 与你什么相干?
别一个人喝酒
人们会知道 斯卡莉这有损你的名誉
好象
不仅仅是为了老弗南克?
瑞德
我很害怕
我不信 你从来不会害怕
我现在很害怕
害怕死怕下地狱
你看起来很健康也许就没有地狱
有的 我知道有从小就知道
哦 我不会过问你小时候受的教育?
告诉我 你都干了些什么事情而要下地狱?
一开始我不该嫁给弗南克
他是休伦的未婚夫他爱她而不是我
我让他痛苦 我害死了他
是的 我害死了他
瑞德
这是我第一次为自己做过的事感到难过
给你 擦擦眼泪
如果你再做一次你还会是那样
你就象是一个贼 偷了东西以后一点也不后悔
而是害怕去蹲监狱
幸亏妈妈她死了
幸亏她死了 没看到我这样
我一直想像她那样安祥 善良
我一天天令她失望
斯卡莉 我看你现在快要放声大哭了
让我们换个话题说说我为什么来这儿
说吧  说完快走
要说什么?
今生今世我再也不能没有你啦
喔 你真是个最没教养的人这个时候来说这种话斯卡莉
当我第一次见到你 我就觉得
你是我所要的唯一的女人
你现在有木材厂和弗南克的钱
不会象进监狱那样来求我
看来现在我该娶你了
我从来没听过这么粗俗的话
如果我现在跟你下跪你该相信了吧?
你这个无赖 你给我出去
对不起 请你愿谅我我的情感这么激动
吓着你了 亲爱的 应该说亲爱的肯尼迪太太
你应该注意到了 这些天
我对你的友情 已经发展到了 已经发展到了更加深刻的感情
而且是更加美好 更加纯洁和更加神圣
这应承说是 爱情了吧?
你给我起来 我不喜欢这庸俗的玩笑
这是一种高尚的求婚方式
这是我认为最适当的时候
我不能一生总在 你的丈夫中间等着
你有粗鲁 又自负
这种话我不想听下去了
再说 我不会再结婚了
哦 你会的你会嫁给我的
你 你 ?
我不爱你
而且 而且我喜欢结婚
你想过为乐趣而结婚吗?
结婚的乐趣? 别胡说了 那是男人的乐趣
你要外面都听到吗?
你先嫁个孩子后又嫁个老头
为什么不嫁个年纪相当又懂得女人的丈夫呢?
你是个傻瓜 你知道吗? 我会永远爱着另一个人的
别说 你现在听见了没有别再说这事
别 我要晕了
我就是要你晕 想一想吧
你的那些傻瓜有过这样的吻? 有吗?
你的恰尔斯 弗南克还有那个笨艾希礼
说你要嫁给我说愿意 说愿意
我愿意
是真心话吗? 不会说了不算?
不会
看着我 跟我说心里话
说你愿意 是不是为了我的钱?
哦
是 也不全是
不全是?
你知道 瑞德 钱是有用的当然 我也喜欢你
喜欢我?
如果说我疯狂地爱着你那是说谎
你常说我们有共同之处
说得对 亲爱的
你爱我多少 我就爱你多少
愿上天保佑真正爱你的人
想要什么样的戒指? 亲爱的
钻石戒指要买一只特大的 瑞德
我要给你买亚特南大最大最阔气的戒指
我还要用我的钱带你到新奥尔良
度一次最豪华的蜜月
哦 那真是太好啦
我还要跟你买很多很多的嫁妆
哦 瑞德 太好了
可别告诉任何人
还是个小伪君子
瑞德 不和我吻别吗?
怎么 亲爱的 这一下午还没有亲够吗?
哦 你真讨厌
走吧我不在乎 你别再回来
可是我要回来的
你想什么呢 斯卡莉德?
我想我们多阔啊
哦 瑞德我还能继续经营木材厂吗?
当然了 如果你愿意
现在你阔了 象你常说的那样
可以让任何人见鬼去了
那你就是第一个去见鬼的了
不要刮盘子 斯卡莉橱房里还多的是呢
哦 瑞德 我能再要一块巧克力菜吗?
你要是再这样贪吃的话会胖得象妈眯
那我可要离婚了
该给妈眯买点礼物吧?
为什么给她买礼物? 她说我们是一对骡子
骡子? 为什么?
喔 她说我们摆阔气把自己打扮得象赛马那么漂亮
其实是戴着马具的骡子
这骗不了人的
我从来没有听过这样的大实话
妈眯是个聪明的老人
我愿意受到象她这样的人尊敬
我什么也不给她 不给她
我要送给她一条衬裙
我记得我奶奶说过 当她升天堂的时候
她要穿一条很挺的红绸子衬裙
走路时习习沙沙地响上帝会以为是天使翅膀做的呢
她不会要你的她死都不会穿的
也许吧 可我还是要表示一下
醒醒 醒醒 斯卡莉 醒醒
啊 你又在作恶梦了
哦 瑞德
我当时又冷 又饿
又累
我找不到 我找不到我在屋里跑 可我找不到
找什么呢? 亲爱的哦 我不知道
我总作同样的梦可我不知道
好象是藏在雾里
喔 亲爱的
你认为我会在梦里找到它吗? 找到了我就安全了
梦不会这样的 不过 当你有了温暖和安全的感觉
你就不会作这样的恶梦了
斯卡莉 我会让你感到安全的
瑞德 我求你一件事你能答应吗?
你知道我能
你愿意带我离开这儿吗?
你不喜欢新奥尔良?
我喜欢新奥尔良 可我想回家去看看泰拉庄园
你愿意带我回泰拉庄园吗?
好吧 斯卡莉 我当然愿意我们明天就走
你的力量是从这儿来的 泰拉庄园的红土
你是它的一部分它也是你的一部分
我要尽一切可能把泰拉庄园恢复成战前的样子
是吗? 那你就去做吧
花多少钱都没行能成为和过去一样好的种植园
喔 瑞德
瑞德 你对我正好
我们在亚特南大还能有新的大房子吗?
可以 你要多么华丽的房子都行
大理石阳台 彩色玻璃等等
人人都会嫉妒我们吗?
我要让那些看不起我们的人羡慕得脸色发青
我不管  斯卡莉真可恨  w这栋大房子就是为了摆阔
她我们的仆人都叫了去
亲爱的 不要把她想得那么坏
她是为了我们 能保住泰拉庄园
泰拉庄园有什么好
她结过三次婚可我成了老处女啦
啊伟大的主啊
伟大的主啊
天那  我们现在阔了
哼 他比不上
太可可笑了 我为何不能进去?
至少我有资格看看我的孩子长得什么样
你忍耐一会吧 瑞德先生你有时间看
哦 可惜不是个男孩 瑞德先生
哦 别说了妈眯 谁要男孩了?
男孩一点用也没有我就是个证明
喝点雪尔酒
妈眯 她长得很漂亮是吗?
那还用说吗
你见过比这漂亮的吗?
当然 斯卡莉小姐生下来的时候就这么漂亮
再来一杯
妈眯我听习习沙沙的声音?
哦 没什么 瑞德先生就是你送给我的红衬裙
你的衬裙? 我不相信  让我看看
把裙子撩起来
哦 天那 你真调皮
你看吧
怎么 这天裙子你放了这么久才穿?
是的 放得太久了
不再是戴马具的骡子了吧?
先生 斯卡莉小姐不该告诉你这个
你不会记恨我吧?
不 怎么能记恨你呢?
只是随便说说 再来一杯妈眯把这一瓶都拿去吧
米格大夫说 现在你可以进去了
今天我真是太快活了
我给这个家带了三代女孩
真是快活的一天
哦 是的 妈眯 最高兴的日子就是婴儿诞生
我盼望 妈眯 她真漂亮
他们会给她取什么名字?
斯卡莉小姐对我说
要是生个女孩就叫玉季尼亚维克多利亚
是啊
她是个漂亮的娃娃
最漂亮的娃娃
嗯
你知道你的生日吗?
你已经一个星期大了
对 我要给她买一匹小马驹全城最好的
啊我要送她上查尔斯敦最好的学校
对 她会受大南方最好的家庭的欢迎
当她结婚的时候
她会象一个小公主
我看你是在自说自话了
为什么不呢?
她是第一个完全属于我的人
你别得意了
孩子是我生的不是吗?
我是梅兰妮 能进来吗?
请进来 梅妮
是啊进来看看我女儿漂亮的蓝眼睛
可是大多数孩子生下来眼睛都是蓝的
别告诉他 梅妮他对孩子的事什么都不懂
不管怎么说 她的眼睛都是蓝的而且永远是蓝的
像我们漂亮的蓝旗
太对了 漂亮的蓝旗 我们就叫她
邦蒂卜露巴特
好了 再试试 妈眯
二十英寸
二十英寸胖得像碧蒂姑妈了
你一定帮我勒到十八寸半妈眯
你生过孩子了 小姐
你永远也不能到十八寸半了
永远  我没办法
我会有办法的
我不能现在就发胖 变老
我不能再生孩子了
瑞德先生说他明年还想要个儿子呢
告诉巴特勒船长我决定不出去了
晚餐我在屋里吃
我听说了我让他们把我的晚餐也送到这儿来
你不会反对吧?
哦 不
是的 我
我是说你在哪儿吃晚餐都可以
瑞德
什么?
你知道
我  我决定
我希望以后不再生孩子了
亲爱的 邦妮出生之前我就说过
你生一个还是二十个对我没什么
可你知道
你明白我的意思吗?
喔 明白但我为这事可以提出离婚
你就是这么低级总想那种事
如果你还有点骑士风度看看人家艾希礼
梅兰妮不能再生孩子可是他 他
今天下午你去木材厂了? 是吗?
这又有什么关系?
卫希礼可真是个正人君子 请说下去 巴特勒太太
说也没用 你不能理解
斯卡莉 你知道我为你难过
为我难过?
对 为你难过 因为你用双手把辛福仍掉了
而你所追求的却不会使你幸福
我不懂你说的是什么
即使你是单身而梅妮小姐又死了
你得到了你的卫希礼 你会辛福吗?
你不会了解的也不知道他在想什么
你什么也不会知道的除了金钱
别跟我说这些了  我要知道的是
你可以守你的贞节 这样做对我没什么
你是说你不在乎?
世界上有很多东西有那么多人我不会寂寞的
我可以在别处找到安慰
太好了
不过我提醒你 要是你又变卦了我可把门锁上
锁上? 我要走进来什么锁也挡不住
我一直认为大多数女人都狡诈 虚伪 无情
可这个女人
哦 瑞德 这有什么用什么意思? 我是说你被她迷住了
不管她怎么对你可你仍然爱她
不要以为你不说出来我就高兴 也许是
不过我跟她算完了我告诉你 完了
你要为孩子想孩子胜过十个母亲
你是个聪明的人 贝尔是个非常好的人
是吗 瑞德?
我在想你们俩有什么不同
你们都是精明的女人你们俩都取得了成功
可是你有一颗善良的心
你很诚实
再见 瑞德
再见
她一定会是一名出色的女骑手
瞧她的手 她的屁股喔 别胡说了
哦
为什么要自己推着贝比出来家里有很多的佣人
早上好 威尔韦格尔太太
早上好 巴特勒船长
早上好 斯卡莉
跟在这些老太太装什么样?
如果你想想你过去的地位你就会这么做了
不过我要赢得这个城市里每一位孤寡老太婆们的好感
早上好 怀亭太太
早上好 巴特勒船长早上好 斯卡莉
这一下大投机商就变得受人尊敬了?
多少钱也买不来我对邦妮的期望
我承认我有缺点
可邦妮需要到正派人的圈子里
那怕我们要对每个老北毛低声下气
早上好 梅格太太
早上好 巴特勒船长早上好 斯卡莉
梅利威格尔太太我一直佩服您丰富的知识
我想向您请教一点事可以吗?
当然可以
邦妮爱吃大拇指我没法至止她
不能让她这样嘴会变型的
我知道 我知道
她的小嘴长得多好看那我往她的手指上涂过肥皂
肥皂?
往手指上涂点奎宁 她很快就不吃了
奎宁? 我怎么就没有想到呢
真是太感谢您了威利威德尔太太
这样一来 我就不用担心了早上好
早上好 朵丽
那不是巴特勒船长吗?
早上好 卡洛琳我正在想
一个这么爱孩子的男人他身上一定有很多优点
当然是的
喔 我没有告诉过你吗? 范倪告诉米格大夫说
巴特勒船长承认他参加了弗兰克林战役
还受到了联邦议会的嘉奖
没有? 我没告诉过你吧
巴特勒船长还为美化阵亡将士的公墓
捐了一大笔钱呢
没有?
我的小孙子下星期要为邦妮・巴特勒开个派提
哦 你明知道是我先想的
我要为邦妮・巴特勒开派提
卡洛琳米达 你怎么能这么做呢?
我的小孙子 是我提议的
应该我先请 应该我先请
看  爸爸教你的小马跳栏邦妮 注意看 欧
哦 好棒 让我来 让我来吗
好吧 宝贝波克 把她抱上来
上来吧
对 就这样
我的老天那 又来了
两腿夹紧 骑稳了 向前探身一定要顺着它的步子
抓紧缰绳 提起来
太好了 我知道你能跳过去
等你长大一点我带你去肯塔几和弗吉尼亚
你会成为南方最好的女骑手让爸爸亲一下
瑞德先生  瑞德先生
瑞德先生
看见了吗 妈眯? 她多了不起啊?
瑞德先生 我告诉过你一个女孩子跨着骑马
裙子都吹起来 是很不合适的
那好吧 把我就教她侧骑吧
我要给她买一身蓝天鹅绒的马服 她会喜欢的
小姑娘穿黑呢子的就行了
好了 好了 妈眯 别再说了
反正 我觉得不合适
不合适 就是不合适
不合适
哦 斯卡莉
你这时候进城干什么来啦?
啊艾希礼 我刚
你怎么没帮梅妮准备我的生日宴会去呢?
喔 艾希礼我还以为你不知道呢
你要不作出惊喜的样子她会失望的
我知道 到时候我一定象亚特南大最惊喜人
好了 你来了让我把帐本给你看看
你就能看到我是多么无能的生意人了
今天我们不谈这没意思的事
在我戴上这顶新帽子的时候
帐目在我脑子里就不存在了
戴上这么漂亮的帽子当然什么也不想了
斯卡莉 你越来越漂亮了
一点也没变记得在十二颗橡树最后一次夜餐会上
你坐在一颗树下一群男孩子围着你
那时的我已经不存在了
没有一件事象我期望的那样
没有
是的 从那以后我们都走过了一段漫长地路
哎 那优闲的日子
那乡间温暖的黄昏
黑人们的欢笑从他们的住处传来
那温馨宁静的美好时光
不要回忆过去了
不要回忆了
他只能揪住你的心什么事也干不成
我不该惹你伤心亲爱的
我唯一希望就是你能过得幸福
艾希礼
谁呀?
你丈夫
哦 进来
我真的被邀请进入圣殿了?
你不去参加梅兰妮的宴会吗?
我有点头痛 瑞德
你自己去吧替我向梅兰妮道歉
你真是一个怯懦的胆小鬼
起来 你必须参加宴会得快点
英蒂雅她真的 是的 英蒂雅是说了
城里的男人女人都已经知道了
应该杀了他们 散岩パ晕矣懈龉制⑵
从不杀说实话的人
现在没时间争论 起来
我不去 我不能去是她把误会澄清了
你难道是怕梅妮小姐
当着众人的面对你下逐客令吗?
我没做错什么错事英蒂雅恨我
我不能去 我应付不了
你今天晚上不露面你这一辈子也别想在这个城市露面了
这对我倒无所谓你不能毁了邦妮的前途
今天为了她 你也应该参加这个宴会 快穿衣服
穿这件 这种场合用不了穿得太朴素
多擦一点烟脂象个赴宴的样子
他是一个快乐的好人
每个人都不能否认
再见 斯卡莉-瑞德 你不能
你一个人进去吧饥饿的狮子正在等着你呢
瑞德 别离开我 别
不用
每个人都不能否认
他是一个快乐的好人
斯卡莉 亲爱的这件衣服可真漂亮
今天晚上英蒂雅不能来
你帮帮我吧
我真需要你帮我招待客人
米格太太
我们的斯卡莉来了
晚上好
晚上好斯卡莉
晚上好巴特勒太太
艾希礼 给我们的斯卡莉倒杯酒来 好吗?
你在梅妮小姐的宴会上玩得高兴吗? 孩子
高兴
哦 妈眯 千万记住
巴特勒船长回来就说我睡了
好吧
请进来 巴特勒太太
到这儿来
坐下
你要喝睡前酒我在这儿也不妨碍你
我并不想喝酒我听到要声音才
你什么也没听见
你要是知道我在这儿你就不会下来了
你现在很想喝酒我不想喝
拿着 别装腔作势了
我知道你偷偷喝酒 我也知道你的酒量
你以为我在乎你喝白兰地吗?
你喝醉了 我要去睡了
我是醉了
可是我今天夜里还要喝得更醉
你别去睡觉还早呢
坐下
她帮了你你有什么感想?
你对她做了亏心事而她为你遮掩
你在想她是不是知道你和艾希礼的事
你以为她这么做是为了保全自己的面子?
你认为她为你遮掩这样做 是个十足的傻瓜
我不想听你要听
梅妮小姐可不是你想象的那样
因为她心的太高尚了
她不往坏处想她所爱的任何人
她是那样的爱你
我真弄不明白她为什么要爱你
你要不是喝醉了还侮辱我我会解释的
虽然 如果你再从这椅子上站起来
当然这其中最可笑的人物
卫尔克斯先生在精神上不能忠于他妻子
而表面上又不愿意不忠于她
他怎么就拿不定主意呢?
瑞德 你
看我的手 亲爱的
我可以把你撕裂成碎片
要是能把卫艾希礼从你头脑里永远除去就好了
可他不行
所以要这样把他从你脑子里除去
我要用两只手
夹着你的头
把你的头像夹核桃一样夹碎
把他挤出去
快把手拿开 你这醉鬼
我一直佩服你这种精神亲爱的
特别是你在陷入绝境的时候
我没有陷入绝境
永远不会 别想吓唬我
你长期过着下流的生活你什么也不懂
就知道嫉妒晚安
我嫉妒? 是吗
对 也许是
我知道你还没有做出对不起我的事
因为我了解
艾希礼・卫尔克斯和他那高尚的借口
他是正人君子
而这一点比你我都强
我们不是 而且你名声不好对吗?
没那么容易的 斯卡莉
你把我赶出处去见艾希礼・卫尔克斯
你梦想着他
今天晚上你敢不跟我
今天早上觉得好点吗 妈眯?
我的后背还有点痛
你今天早上显得挺高兴小姐
是的 妈眯是的
当他对她微笑她喜极而泣
看到他皱眉就害怕得发抖
你好 我
我要为我昨天晚上的行为向你歉
哦 可是瑞德
我当时喝醉了
而你又是那么的迷人 所以我有点儿情不自禁 难以控制
你不必向我道歉你做什么事我都不会觉得吃惊的
斯卡莉 我一直在考虑如果我们都承认
我们错了
还是离婚吧 我相信这对我们俩个人都好
离婚? 对
没有必要把俩个人栓在一起
我保证你过富裕的生活你可以提出要求
只要邦妮归我你要什么我都同意
谢谢你了
离婚这种败坏门风的事 我可不干
如果艾希礼是自由的
你真是巴不得越早离婚越好呢
离不离 斯卡莉?
快回答我
离不离?
请你走吧 让我清静一会儿
我是要走我就是来告诉你的
我要作一段长时间的旅行 去伦敦 今天就走
我要带邦妮去
请她马上把她的衣服收拾好
你别想把我的孩子带走
她也是我的孩子
你以为我会把她留在一个
毫不顾惜自己名誉的母亲身边 那样的话你就错了
你多会说呀
你以为我会让你把孩子带到
像贝儿那种人那儿去吗? 绝不可能
你要是个男人我会扭断你的颈子
谢谢你别再说那种话了
你倒摆出一副做母亲的神气来了
一只猫做母亲都会比你强
一小时之内给她准备好行装 我警告你
我常常想用马鞭子抽你一顿
对不起 瑞德先生
您好 瑞德叔叔
啊你好  爸爸
爸爸
你到哪儿去了? 我等你一早晨我打兔子去了
用它的皮把小邦妮裹起来
来 亲我一下
邦妮 我要带你去漫游仙境 去旅行
去哪儿? 去哪儿?
我带你看伦敦塔小王子们呆的地方
还有伦敦桥
伦敦桥?
它不会塌下来吗?
你想要它塌 它就塌
爸爸 黑
黑
爸爸 好黑
邦妮  邦妮  邦妮别怕 邦妮谁把灯熄灭了? 保姆  保姆
啊 啊 我的小邦妮怎么了?
嗯 怎么啦  根爸爸说
一只熊
哦 一只熊? 是只大熊吗?
大极了 坐在我的胸口上哦 好了 好了
我在这儿 它再来 我就打死它
晚上好 巴特勒先生
我告诉过你 不要把她一个人呆在黑屋子里
对不起 先生 孩子们常常怕黑 不过会习惯的
让她夜里喊一 两次
让她喊? 你如果不是傻瓜就是个没有人性的人
如果你想让她长大了成为一个胆小鬼
胆小鬼
她身上没有一根胆小的骨头  你被解雇了
随你便吧 先生
妈妈在哪儿呢?
跟我在伦敦不快乐吗?
我要回家
邦妮小姐
是巴特勒船长
斯卡莉小姐你好  妈眯
乖宝贝
妈妈 斯卡莉小姐他们回来了
邦妮
邦妮 邦妮宝贝
乖宝贝
回家高兴吗?
爸爸给了我只小猫
小猫迷 好可爱的-伦敦挺可怕的
乖宝贝-我的小马呢?
小马在呢-我的小马呢? 我要去看我的小马
我的小马呢?
我要去看我的小马
跟妈眯去吧
来吧 乖宝贝跟妈眯去
妈眯可想你啦 宝贝
巴特勒太太
妈眯说你回来了
我来送邦妮
对孩子来说一个坏妈妈也比没有妈妈好
这么说你还要走?
你猜得真准 巴特勒太太
这就走
我的行李都放在车站了
你的脸色很苍白是不是没有胭脂擦了?
还是因为心里我想的才会这样?
这都怨你
不是因为想你而是因为
接着说下去
是因为我怀孕了
真的?
谁是那辛运的父亲?
你知那是你的
我跟本不想要孩子
没有那个女人愿意跟你这样的无赖生孩子
我倒希望不要是你的
高兴点 说不定会小产
她好点儿了吗?
哈太太 她问起我了吗?
难道你不明白她在说胡话
瑞德
我要瑞德
怎么啦 宝贝? 你叫谁呢 孩子?
没有用
没用
米格大夫走了
斯卡莉死了?
喔 不 她好多了
真的好多了
好了 巴特勒船长你已经急昏了头啦
她很快就会好起来我保证
不 不 你不知道她并不想要这孩子
不想要孩子? 女人都想要孩子
是 你想要孩子 可她不要不想要我的孩子
她说她不再要孩子了
我是要伤害她 因为她伤害我
而且我这样做了
别说了你不该跟我说这些事这不合适
直到那天她摔下来我才知道她怀孕了
如果我知道我会立刻回来不管她要不要我回来
你当然会回来
可是那一天 她在楼梯上告诉我
我说了什么? 我大叫着对她说
可是我知道你不是有意的
我是有意的我嫉妒得发狂
她从没爱过我 我本以为她能 可是不行
你想错了
斯卡莉非常爱你只是她自己没意识到
如果是这样 我可以等
如果她能原谅我忘掉这一切
她会的
你要有耐心
不 这是不可能的
你不明白 假如你知道她真正爱的是
你不会相信的
你千万不要听信那些流言飞语
我反正不相信
好了 好了 斯卡莉会好起来的孩子还会再有的
不 她不会的 即使她想要经过这一次她也不会
她当然会要的
我也要有了
不 不 梅妮小姐你可别冒这个险太危险了
孩子使生活焕然一新巴特勒船长
如果能有这样的生活那危险就不重要了
我以前从未见过一位真正勇敢的人
我祈求上帝保佑你梅妮小姐
我要感谢你为我和斯卡莉所做的一切
我从心里感激你
斯卡莉小姐觉得今天好多了瑞德先生
谢谢
斯卡莉 我来求你原谅的
希望能再给我们的共同生活一次机会
共同生活?
我们什么时候有过?
说得对
如果我们能再试一次的话 我们会辛福的
还有什么能让我们辛福的呢?
还有 还有邦妮
而且我爱你 斯卡莉
你什么时候发现的?
我一直爱你可你从没给我机会来证明
那好 你想让我干什么?
首先 别管那个木材厂了
我们离开这儿
我们带着邦妮再渡一次蜜月
放弃它? 可它比任何时候都赚钱啦
我知道 可我们不需要它
卖掉吧  或者干脆送给艾希礼
梅兰妮一直对我们这么好
梅兰妮 总是梅兰妮如果你能多我为想
我是想着你
我想
或许是那个木材厂
使你跟我和邦妮疏远了
我知道你想的是什么 别把邦妮扯进来
是你使邦妮跟我疏远了
可她是爱你的
你想方设法让她爱你而不爱我
看你把她给惯的
妈妈 爸爸
看着我
我们看着呢  宝贝
你真漂亮 宝贝
你也漂亮
我要跳了看着我呀 爸爸
听着 亲爱的邦妮你不要总是跳栏
别忘了你刚刚学会的侧骑
我要这么跳
我能跳得比以前更好因为我长大了
我要把栏杆升高一点
别让她跳 瑞德
不 邦妮 别跳你要是摔下来可别哭找我
瑞德 别让她跳
邦妮
就像爸爸
爸爸
邦妮
梅妮小姐 你来了太好了
喔 妈眯 没有了邦妮家里可真不一样了
斯卡莉怎么受得了啊?
梅妮小姐她伤心极了
可我请你来不是为了她
主给了她力量使她挺住了
我担心的是瑞德先生
这两天 他都快疯了
不 妈眯 不会的
我从没要见过一个男人会这么爱孩子
米格大夫说她脖子断了
瑞德先生抓起手枪就去把小马打死了
当时 我真怕他把自己打死
可怜的巴特勒船长
是啊斯卡莉小姐说他是凶手教孩子跳栏
她说 你还我孩子是你杀了她
他说斯卡莉小姐从来没这么关心过邦妮
他们就这样吵来吵去我的血都凉了
喔 妈眯 别再说了
那天晚上
瑞德先生把自己锁在保育室里配着邦妮
斯卡莉小姐来敲门
他理也不理
就这样已经整整两天了
妈眯
今天晚上 斯卡莉小姐隔着门对他说
明天早上就要下葬了
可是他说  你要是敢来我就把你杀了
你想我能把我的孩子
放进坟墓吗? 她最怕黑了
妈眯 妈眯 他真是疯了
是啊真是这样他不让孩子下葬
劝劝他吧
可我不好管
你不能管 谁能管呢?
瑞德先生最尊重你的意见
求求你了 梅妮小姐
我尽力去做吧
走开 让我们安静地待着
我是卫尔克斯太太巴特勒船长
请让我进来
我看邦妮来了
哦 主啊
瑞德先生这么伤心 请帮助他吧
妈眯 你去烧点儿浓咖啡来
给巴特勒船长送去 我去看斯卡莉小姐
哦 可是
巴特勒船长同意举行葬礼了
明天早晨
阿利路亚 我知道天使会帮助你的 阿利路亚
梅妮小姐梅妮小姐
梅妮小姐
梅妮小姐 梅妮小姐
去请米格大夫
来
送我回家
梅妮小姐 梅妮小姐
好啦我妈妈要到哪儿去呀?
为什么我不能跟着去呀?
有很多事情 不是想干就干的
我们去睡觉了 孩子
瑞德 她不能死她不能死
她和你不一样
她没有那种力量只有一颗善良的心
你也了解她?
我为什么要去睡觉? 现在是早晨
好那 还不到早晨呢
你可以进去了 斯卡莉小姐
米格大夫 请让我去看看她吧
我等了整整两天了 我想告诉她
有件事是我错了 她知道你知错了
她要见斯卡莉
要让梅妮小姐平静地死去
希望你别跟她说些不相干的话
来减轻你良心的负担明白了吗?
是我 梅妮
答应我吗?
什么事?
照看我的小儿子
我曾把他托付给过你
记得吗?
他出生的那天
梅妮 别这么说 我知道你会好起来的
答应我
上大学
是的 到欧洲去还给他一匹小马
喔 梅妮
艾希礼
艾希礼和你
关于 艾希礼 ?
替我照顾艾希礼
就像你
替他照顾我 一样
我会的
照顾他
可 别让他知道
晚安
答应啦
还有什么 梅妮?
巴特勒船长
要对他好一点
瑞德?
他是那么爱你
是的 梅妮
再见
再见了
女士们 可以进去了
艾希礼
我不知道那一只在哪儿?
她一定把它放在哪儿了
别这样
搂住我
我害怕
我害怕极了
斯卡莉 我怎么办呢? 没有她我怎么活呢?
我所有的一切
都跟着她去了
艾希礼
你真的很爱她 是不是?
她是我在现实面前唯一没有破灭的梦
梦 你总是在梦想从没清醒过
哦 斯卡莉 你不知道我经受的痛苦
你早就该告诉我 你爱的是她 而不是我
你不该用那些借口使我存在幻想
现在梅妮要死了
才让我明白 我对你没有一点意义
就像贝尔对瑞德一样
我所爱的实际是
是不存在的
不过
我不在乎
这没关紧
一点儿没关系
哦 艾希礼 艾希礼原谅我
别哭了 不能让她看出你哭过
艾希礼
梅妮
瑞德
瑞德 你在哪儿?
瑞德 等等我
瑞德
进来
梅兰妮 她
上帝让她安息了
她是我所见过的唯一完美的人
伟大的女性
非常伟大的女性
可她死了 对你是件好事不是吗?
你怎么能这么说呢? 你知道我是多么的爱她
不 这我可不知道
至少对你来说 你最后还应该感激她
我当然感激她 她心里只想着别人
最后还提到你
她说什么了?
她说
要对巴特勒船长好一点他这么爱你
她还说什么?
她说
她还要我照顾好艾希礼
得到前妻的允准这样就方便多了
你这是什么意思?
你要干什么吗?
我要走了 亲爱的
你现在需要的就是离婚你对艾希礼的梦想就要变成现实了
哦 不
不 你错了 大错特错了
不 我不要离婚瑞德 今天夜里
我明白了我是爱你的我就跑回家来告诉你
亲爱的
别来这套了 好吗?
给我们的结合留下最后一点可以回忆的尊严吧
最后 ?
瑞德听我说
我肯定多年来我一直爱着你只是 我是这么愚蠢自己并没有意识到
请相信我 你也爱我
梅妮说过的
我相信你可艾希礼怎么办?
我 我从没真正爱过他
你装得可真像一只到今天早晨
不 我尽了 一切努力
当我从伦敦回来的时候那怕你对我有半点表示
我当时见了你多高兴啊真的可你那么气人
我让你病了 那是我的错
我盼那 盼着你要见我可你没有
我是要你的 非常想要你可我以为你不要我了
看来我们彼此误解了现在没用了
如果邦妮还活着也许会使我们幸福
我总爱把邦妮当作你
没有经历战争和贫困之前的那个小姑娘
她是那么像你所以我宠她 娇惯她就像娇惯你一样
可她走了 带走了一切
瑞德
瑞德别说这些了
我很抱歉抱歉我所做的一切
你真是个孩子 亲爱的
你以为说一声抱歉就能把过去都改过来吗?
给你 我的手绢
在你一身中任何危难时刻我从未见你带过手绢
瑞德 瑞德 你要去哪儿?
我要回查尔斯 我的家乡
瑞德 请带我一起去吧
不 这里的一切对我已经结束了
我需要清静
我要去寻找有什么地方
明白我的意思吗? 不 我只知道我爱你
那就是你的不辛
哦 瑞德
瑞德
哦 瑞德 你走了我到哪儿去 我该怎么办呢?
坦率的说 亲爱的我管不着了
我不能让他走 不能
我要想方法让他回来
我现在不能再想了再想我就要疯了
我明天再想
可我一定要想
一定要想
我该怎么做呢?
什么是最重要的?
你是说 凯蒂・斯卡莉・沃郝纳
土地对你毫无意义可是只有土地才是最重要的
只是土地才是永恒的
有一样东西你爱它胜过于我虽然你没有意识到那就是泰拉庄园
你的力量是从这儿来的泰拉庄园的红土
只有土地才是最重要的只有土地才是永恒的
有一样东西你爱它胜过于我那就是泰拉庄园
你力量是从这儿来的泰拉庄园的红土
只有土地才是最重要的
有一样东西你爱它胜过于我
泰拉庄园的红土
泰拉庄园 泰拉庄园
泰拉庄园
家
我要回家
我会想办法让他回来
明天毕竟 又是 新的一天